in this video we're going to be taking a
look at 200 Ultra hard PMP practice
questions and from the length of this
video you can see this video is going to
be a long one so in this video I'm going
to be answering some of the hardest PMP
practice questions out there if you can
get at least a 70% on this exam I think
you're going to pass your your PMP exam
pretty easily I'm Andrew ramal I am the
author of the world's bestselling PMP
study guide PMP exam prep simplified and
I'm also the creator of Udi's
bestselling PMP course with over 370,000
enrollments combined with my books my
videos and my live courses I've helped
over 500,000 students pass the current
PMP exam so with that in mind let's go
ahead and get started on this but before
I get there I want to just point out a
couple things number one this took an
enormous amount of time and this is a
compilation video of all the videos that
came before if you notice I released
them in series of 10 so what I did is I
just combine all of them now into this
giant compilation video another thing is
that it took a lot of time a lot of time
a lot of effort to write these questions
and to make this video so if you guys
don't mind clicking on the like button
subscribing to the channel would help us
out a lot if you appreciate the work and
effort that goes into this if you want
more questions like you're about to see
and more explanations to these questions
check out the link below to the Tia exam
simulator which now has about 1,000
practice questions that you can try
including multiple full length uh Mach
exam micro exams uh mini exams and so on
you can check that out with video
explanations all done by me and with
that in mind guys let's just dra dive
right into it and start off with
question one keep in mind this is a
compilation video so let's keep going
let's get to question one all the way to
200 all right here we go question number
one now again these questions are meant
to be difficult all right a project
manager is planning the construction of
a new Public Library the community and
project stakeholders are having
difficulty agreeing on the key features
to be included in the final design what
should the project manager do facilitate
a workshop Workshop to gather input from
all stakeholders Define the difference
between essential and non-essential
features involve design consultant to
mediate stakeholder
discussions identify the root cause of
the stakeholder inability to agree on
the project scope now you really have to
not a mindset on this question because
you you can see in the question that we
have it says the community and
stakeholders there's some kind of
difficulty going on here uh to help
identify the features now if there is a
problem on a project one of your most
important thing to do is to ensure you
understand the problem the first thing
we're going to do before we solve a
problem is to identify how did this
problem come about what's going on here
can can there be potential or multiple
Sol Solutions how did we get to this
problem these are questions you should
be asking yourself now there's something
very unique about D if you learn the
mindset you understand that D
understands the problem because look
he's looking for the root cause of the
problem the problem is their inability
to agree on the scope something about a
b and c is telling you something you see
it's they all have something in common
this is an action you're actually going
to hold a workshop you're going to
Define the differences first of all you
should never be the one choosing what's
right for the project and what's wrong
for the project in this one you're
choosing between what's the essential
and non-essential that's generally your
product owner your project sponsor your
customers does that not
you involveed Design Consultants now
you're bringing in other people without
even understanding the actual root cause
the main cause of the problem so
remember now when it comes to this exam
the mindset says don't take an action
unless you saw
the problem unless you understand the
problem all right no actions without
understanding the problem assess the
situation okay very good s a number one
done all right we got 199 more to
go question two a project manager
convenes an emergency session with the
software development team to address
significant bugs that are delaying the
Project's delivery the product owner
suggest conducting a root cause analysis
to identify the underlying issues what
what should the project manager do
collaborate with the team to discuss the
RCA suggestions and decide collectively
on the next step okay getting the team
involved encourage a a lead developer to
take charge of the RCA fostering Team
anony all right letting the team work by
themselves coordinate with the quality
assurance lead to refine testing
processes and B based on the RCA outcome
all right bringing more people in
organize the session to ensure all team
members contribute their insights
potential Solutions okay okay not not a
bad answer you're letting everybody
contribute okay so let's take a look at
this question now this is the an agile
project how do I know this because I can
see it says product owner this
immediately tells me that this is an
agile uh project and the product owner
suggesting something that the team
should be
following in a situation like this if
there's some kind of solution or
somebody wants the team to do something
you have to let the team decide if they
want to do it or not remember something
on an agile project the team is
self-leading they're
self-directing you don't you're not a a
dictator to the team as you would on a
traditional project so the best answer
here is let the team
decide work with the team to discuss the
RCA suggestion and let them decide if
they want to implement it or not the
rest of them is pretty much
implementation notice first of all be
never do be this is giving away your
work if it ever comes like to a point on
this exam where it says well let
somebody else deal with it while you
just watch it's never the answer never
give away your work coordinate with a
quality now you're bringing in more
people and it seems like you're
basically going to implement this RCA
outcome don't do that organize is the
ultimate contributed insights and
potential solutions to what this one is
very a little vague we're not sure what
it's talking about
but it seems like they're coming up with
their own Solutions here the best thing
the question is addressed in this
RCA so the best thing here is bring the
RCA to them as a suggestion and say hey
do you want to implement this or not let
the team decide is the model of the
story here remember on an agile project
the team decides how how they want to do
the work the team decides what methods
they're going to do the work because
they're a self-leading self-directing
team question
three a project manager over seeing the
launch of a new e-commerce platform
discovers that the finance department
has concerns about not being involved in
the cost estimations and their potential
impact on the project Returns what
should the project manager do first
amend the stakeholder engagement plan to
better integrate Finance in future plans
all
right document the exclusion of the
finance team as a risk to project
success all right maintain the project
timeline the plan and financial review
before the Final Phase okay organize a
meeting with the finance team to
understand the concerns all right
similar to somewhat similar to that
first question because if you
notice uh the finance department they
have some kind of concern all right they
weren't involved and whoever came up
with the budgets and they think it's
going to affect what what we're going to
get back from the project notice this
one particularly says what should you do
first again this one has a very similar
theme all right and the a lot of these
choices have a very similar team but one
is very uniquely different the answer
here is of course D you see if you
notice a is this before you before you
understand their concern before you
understand what really happened here
you're already amending the engagement
plan don't do that never take an action
first document the exclusion of the
finance team is a risk to the project
success it might
be all right it might be an exclusion
but before we even document that risk we
need to understand that
risk maintain never do nothing if you
get a choice where it says maintain it
um keep doing what you're
doing uh then that's not the answer so
the moment I say like maintain the
timeline well the timeline could be
affected by this the best thing we
should do first is let's go and meet
with the team understand their concerns
that will we have a better way of
determine what action we should take
next question number four as part of a
project to integrate a new security
feature into an online shopping platform
stakeholders have shown concerns over
understanding the integration process
during the planning phase what should
the project manager do to in hands
stakeholders understanding of the
integration all right so we are
integrating we're putting something into
operations we're getting something out
there what should we do well schedule
regular demonstration session during
each Sprint to show progress integration
steps sure arrange for the technical
team to provide a detailed explanation
before each Sprint
begins organize a training session to
educate stakeholder technical aspects of
the
integration provide detailed
documentation on the integration process
prior to the start of each Sprint phase
well if you understand the world of
agile this one is pretty simple because
what we should be doing in every single
Sprint is we should be doing the Sprint
review meetings and that's what this is
really asking asking you all right
notice stakeholders have concerned
because they don't understand this
integration process during the planning
stage so what should you do well do
regular demonstrations with them explain
to them what the project is doing this
way you can show the progress of what we
have done and how it's working they
don't need a detail stakeholders
especially like customers don't want
detailed documentation they might not be
able to understand especially if it's
very
technical they don't need to be educated
on the technical aspects it's more for
like your team members arrange with the
technical team they don't need a
detailed explanation before each Sprint
they just need to understand what's
going on you remember something
customers really don't care about the
technical aspects of things they care
about the functionality of things if
you're building a website for me I
really am not interested in how the back
end works I don't need to know what
codeing language you use I don't need to
know what forms you were using or
functions all I need to know is does it
work so keep that in
mind all right best answer there was
a question five a project manager is
preparing for the Sprint planning
sessions for a new feature in a Health
Care system this meeting aims to
determine the amount of work for the
upcoming Sprint while two pieces of
information are essential for the
project manager ensure the meeting is
productive and efficient so now you're
doing a meeting we know we're working on
an ad job project because we got this
upcoming Sprint this word alone tells me
um Sprint Sprint plan is going to be an
agile project so what are two essential
things that we should have for our
meetings remember this is the Sprint
planning session remember what the
Sprint planning session is what's the
input to that Sprint planning session
what's going to be the output of it best
answer here is going to be if you
understand it it's going to be first of
all team performance metrics and a
detail
product backlog how do we get here well
first of all understand what a Sprint
planning session is the Sprint planning
session is where the team decides how
much or what work they're going to do
how much and what work they're going to
do in the next Sprint the output is the
Sprint backlog so for them to
determine what work they're going to do
they're going to need a product backlog
generally should have the user stories
in it by now the next thing they're
going to need is how fast they work
they're going to need that performance
metrics or what's known as the team
velocity why do they need that because
for them to determine how much work they
can do from the product backlog they're
going to have to know how fast they do
work previously how fast they generally
work how many points they do per
iteration or per Sprint they don't
necessarily updated risk assessment
product Marketplace goal that's more of
like your sales and markeet in current
project phase timeline the thing with
agile projects you're not going to
really have like pH and timelines laid
out like that they're building it based
on prioritization of the work in the
product
backlog all right this one here was
choose
to question number six a project manager
is leading an interet by biotechnology
research project characterized by
significant am
ambiguity big word there
unpredictability a suggestion has been
made to introduce a system to engage the
quality of the project outputs
effectively what hybrid technique should
the project manager employ to ensure
quality assurance so key word here is we
got to basically it's what are we going
to do to ensure we have good quality
assurance combine weekly Sprints with
quarterly external audits to validate
project standards H quarterly external
audits
huh merge traditional Milestone reviews
with agile Sprint
demonstrations okay adapt paer
programming and customer feedback
sessions okay integrate continuous
integration tools with formal quality
control checkpoints now we have to
understand that when it comes to Quality
quality is meeting customers
satisfaction High customer satisfaction
good quality product the ultimate test
of quality is a satisfied
customer so how can we do this how can
we ensure that we introduce a system
that has high quality what which one
here leads to high quality would it be
quarterly external audits would it be
Milestone reviews and Sprint
demonstrations would it be peer
programming customer feedback or
integrate continuous integration tools
with formal quality checkpoints best
answer here guys is going to be peer
programming and customer feedback if
you're wondering how do you get that
well understand what peer programming is
so this is used in extreme programming
we do cover this in the agile section of
the course when one guy writes the code
the other guy checking the code if the
code is consistently checked as it's
being written the code is less likely to
have bugs and the question is is the
customer feedback getting accepted into
the project that's customer feedback the
best way to make a customer happy with a
product is to get the customer involved
in the development of the product get
feedback as you're developing the
product making this the best answer we
don't like this one here first of all
it's it's quarterly and this one doesn't
involve your customer the best way to
make something really good for our
customers to get them
involved although I like this one here
with agile Sprint demonstrations the
problem here is Milestone reviews and
we're not sure how long those Milestone
reviews are continuous integration this
one here is not this is integration
tools and it's not bringing customers in
customers will give us the best way that
will tell us what we're doing right what
we're doing wrong and this is the best
way in order to produce quality
products question seven uh project
managers are overseeing a software
development project where the team has
prioritized creating a new user
authentication system in the current
Sprint Midway through the Sprint two
developers Express a desire to divert
their efforts to optimize in database
queries anticipating future performance
Botts what should you do next I want to
point out this is a tough question by
the way allocate time for developers to
present their optimization proposal at
the next Sprint planning
meeting reinforcing importance of
adherent to the Sprint's primary goal of
completing the authentication
system request a special session to
assess the potential impact of the
database optimization on future Sprints
support the developers initiative by
allocating a small portion of their time
to start preliminary work on the
database this one is a tough question
this one tests your ability to
understand agile principles and the
agile principles tells us that once a
Sprint starts
what should you do you should do the
work in the Sprint don't change the team
don't change the work when somebody when
they're coming to you in a Sprint and oh
we want to do this we want to go here I
want to go here the best thing you can
do is to keep them on track and keep
them to finish the Sprint goal that's
what B is and that's what we
need everything else is not completing
the goal everything else is allowing
them to go and do this database thing
allocate time for developers to present
their optimization of the now you're
allocating time that's taken away from
the Sprint goal request special session
once again same thing supported now if
you support it and you allocate a small
time once again you're making them work
something that is not on the Sprint goal
on they once they finish the Sprint if
the team feels like this is something
that needs to get done maybe it's added
to the product backlog and maybe they
they can do it in the next
spread question number eight a project
manager is overseeing the development of
an enterprise resource planning system
system and is decided that a combination
of scrum and can band methodologies
would be most effective however the
product owner is unsure about how to
begin optimizing and prioritizing work
what should the project manager what
should the project manager
do uh guide the product owner on
developing and optimizing a
comprehensive product backlog okay have
team members explained the integration
of scrum and kban principles to the
product owner to enhance understanding
all right
recommend the product the the project
team use visual management tools to
improve workflow teach the product to Le
how to map out process flows to better
understand task sequences okay what are
we going to do here so this one here
test of durability in the PMP exam
objectives you have to know about
training people on somebody doesn't know
how to do something don't do it for them
the mindset tells you if somebody knows
how to do something do not make them do
somebody else role don't make somebody
else come in and do their role teach
them how to do their role and the best
thing here we can do is teach the
product owner hey if you're prioritizing
work you're going to be using that
product
backlog how to begin organizing and
prioritizing work it's all organizing
and prioritizing work is all about in
that product backlog so work with the
product owner on that now have the team
member explain don't give away this is
part of your job notice how you're
giving away to work recommend the team
the team it shouldn't be here when it
comes to prioritizing work that's the
product owner's job the team should
never prioritize a product backlog teach
the product own I like this to map out
process flows but this doesn't teach him
about prioritizing
work make an a the best
answer okay how are you guys doing so
far you guys uh doing okay these
questions are a little difficult
hopefully you know actually they're lot
difficult hopefully you guys are doing
well by the way don't forget to click on
that subscribe button
question number nine a project manager
is leading a team on a critical
marketing campaign for a major Pro uh
product launch after unexpected last
minute changes the team worked over time
to meet tight deadlines the sponsors
allocated a monetary award to recognize
the team efforts based on the project
management practice what is the most
appropriate action for the project
manager distribute the entire War to the
team of who work the longest hours
organize a team build and Retreat to
enhance moral future projects use the
award to fund professional development
opportunity to benefit the team in
future projects decide how to distribute
the award based on informal feedback
from the team now this is a tough
question there's two choices here that I
want you guys to eliminate right away
distribute the word now you're giving
away the entire word to one person not
because you work the longest hours
doesn't mean you did the most
work when you're doing a question like
this and I'm sure you're going to get
one or two like this on the test anytime
you have to create an award system
there's a couple things to number one
there's a couple things to keep in mind
number one it has to be fair all right
and number two it has to be be public
you can't come up with a system and hide
it from people and it has to be fairly
allocated so let's see what we got so
we're going to eliminate this one here
right off the bat this is the throwout
answer decide how to distribute based on
informal feedback from the team this is
probably something you want more of a
feedback so we got two we're going to go
away it now comes the tough
one do we organize a team build and
Retreat to enhance more for future
projects or do we use the award to fund
professional that to benefit them so
which one do you think is going to
benefit them more in the future the best
answer here is C this one here is going
to make them learn more and it's going
to benefit them more in the in the
future and future projects versus team
building to retreat to enhance for the
moral of future projects although it's
not a bad answer C helps future
projects next question number 10 a
project manager is overseeing the
construction of a new
community uh Recreation Center which
needs to be developed quickly to meet
the community's expectation the team is
skilled stakeholders are engaged and the
community is excited about the new
facility what should the project manager
to to prioritize timely completion
assign more resources to critical tasks
without consulting the team develop a
milestone based plan ensuring regular
stakeholder involvement and
communication okay monitor Daily
Progress in a way that integrates input
from team members to ensure alignment
with project goals all right request an
extension of the on the project deadline
from sponsor okay there's a couple of
answers here so we're building a uh a
center we know that we have a lot of
Engagement stakeholders skilled
everybody seems to be doing great you
got your team is uh skilled here you got
your stakeholders are engaged
everybody's exced it sounds great but we
want to finish this thing quickly what
can we do it's a trick question the
answer here is actually B now assign
more resources never do something
without consulting the team especially
the team is doing the work so that was a
throwout answer there's no need to
request a deadline unless you're going
to go over to the
schedule those two answers are
automatically
eliminated now monitor Daily Progress in
Array that integrates input from the
team this is the something daily is
probably going to take up a lot of time
and integrates input from the team to
ensure alignment with goals okay but the
best the best person to get involvement
to ensure this the project is correct is
stakeholder engagement stakeholder
involvement a milestone base helps to
keep the project on schedule and of
course good
communication so the key point of this
question that I want you guys to
understand is that in this
question and a lot of these questions
we're going to be doing and we have done
not to take older engagement stakeholder
involvement is the key to success on
projects it's the key to a lot of the
answers as we can see here on this
question question number 11 by the way
I'm just going to be reading the
question and the answers the moment you
see the question on the screen please
pause the video answer it and then see
me answer it uh with explanations all
right question number 11 a project
manager has begin has begun a complex
airport Expansion Project although the
project is in the initiating phase the
sponsor keeps asking asking for concrete
dates for the most important project
Milestones when will the project manager
be able to provide the requested
information now keep in mind this
question is a little confusing because
it does specify that you're in that
initiating section of the project but
this person wants concrete dates a after
the initial risk assessments are
completed to estimate timelines okay at
the end of the plan in Phase once detail
schedule and risk assessments are
completed okay Journey EX ution phase
when the project is on the way and
progress can be measured all right once
the project Charter signed as is
outlined initial Milestone answer here
is going to be B now here's
why first of all notice it wants the the
sponsa wants concrete dates even though
they're in the initiating phase of the
project you cannot get concrete
information in the initiating section
keep in mind for your exam the
initiating is all high level high level
scope high level schedule high level
budget high level risk all of that
belongs in the project Charter itself so
you have to wait till the end of Planet
that's the whole objective of Planet the
whole objective of planet is to spend a
lot of time and determine what's the
best schedule do those expert judgment
do those bottomup estimations break down
to work in the WBS and so on uh after
initial an initial risk assessment is
not going to give you concrete
information to a is wrong you don't need
to wait till the execution that's the
point of planning now once the charter
is signed it doesn't mean that any of
the real planning work has got the tror
signed the project is authorized but you
really haven't done all the work yet
it's not till the planning when you
really do the work making B the best
best
answer question 12 a project manager is
overseeing a large infrastructure
project in a hierarchal organization the
team members are used to receiving
direct instructions and their
performance reviews are based on task
completion percentage after discussing
with the sponsor the project manager
realizes that some task needs to be
reassigned to meet the next Milestone
this change could be perceived as
negative reflection on the current uh
assignes
performance what should the project
manager do a assign the task to the most
skilled member without farther
discussion okay behold the meeting to
explain the changes and collaborate on
reassigning tasks all right
see privately ask a senior member to
take over the task and inform the others
of the reassignment all right send an
email to the team outlining the task
changes and reasoning behind them okay
follow the mindset on this particular
question because if you notice in the
question we have team members they're
receiving direct instructions and
performance reviews are based on task
completion now something changed they
realized that some tasks uh need to be
reassigned in the next Milestone this of
course can affect them so when something
is affecting the team what does the
mindset tell you well let's go over this
here best answer is hold a meeting and
explain the changes to them part of the
mindset is to confront your problems
right don't step away from your problems
don't hide problems never hide anything
from
anyone notice this one is assign the
task to the most skilled Team part of
the mindset tells you shouldn't just go
and assign task work with the team try
not to do work by yourself but be
collaborative and bring people into the
decision-making process a you're
basically doing that by yourself B now
you're meeting with the team you're
working with them never give away your
work I keep saying this over and over in
all my mindset videos never give away
your work never actually tell somebody
else to do it never ask a sponsor never
ask the the pmo Never Give It Away to a
senior team member send an email to the
outline and the changes and the reason
although I like like this
notice B and D is basically the same
thing in this one you're sending an
email and you're letting them know the
reason in this when you're holding a
meeting and you're working in a
collaboration so which way is better
sending out an email or working with the
team in a collaborative manner B is
definitely better than
C question 13 a project manager is
leading a City Park renovation project
during a status meeting with City
officials the project manager provides
an update about a significant
deliverable some of the officials
claimed they were not informed about
this deliverable what should the project
manager do next confirm if the scope
statement have been updated to include
the deliverable okay meet with these
officials to review the communication
plan and cify deliverables all right
check the attendance records of these
officials at prior project meetings Okay
d review the project documents to ensure
the deliverable was communicated follow
the mindset once again on this one here
let's see what it says here best answer
here guys is going to be once again is
to confront your problems if you have
something on your project that's going
on that you feel is negative meet with
people talk to people is going to be the
best answer now there's one thing I want
to point out here is if something seems
like you're doing it out of malicious
reasons or something seems like it's
it's going to negatively impact the
project it's probably not going to be
the answer that's what C is notice check
the attendance records of these people
attended meetings it seems like you're
checking to see if they show up so you
can like crucify them or prosecute them
or something like that probably not the
best answer confirm if the project scope
has been updated to include the
deliverable well the best thing here to
do is before you do that meet with them
and make sure that they even know what
they're talking about or what if they
understand what this deliverable is
about review the project documentation
to ensure the deliverable was
communicated before you do this this all
right before notice it says what you do
next before you do this meet with them
first make sure you review the
communication plans with them all right
question number 14 a project manager is
overseeing the construction of a new
office buildin a key stakeholder
complains that they never received the
structural Integrity test status report
the project manager provides the report
and the stakeholder notices that an
important aspect of the structure was
not tested what tool should the project
manager have used to prevent this
situation the communication log
requirements traceability Matrix
stakeholder register or the quality
management
plan okay so let's take a look at the
answer here notice you're looking for
prevent something like this from
happening so you got to go back in time
watch the keyword is prevent here so we
got to go back in time and the best
answer here is going to be stolder
register this was a tough one I agree if
you got this one wrong don't feel bad
notice a key stakeholder the main
complaint is what they never received
the test report they never received the
report
now what document outlines the
communication needs of a particular
stakeholder it's the stakeholder
register not the communication
management plan the communication
management plan tells what communication
will take place at what time
when it's going to take place how it's
going to take place who's going to set
it who's going to give it to them the
stakeholder register is a different
document this one says who the
stakeholders are and their communication
requirements so this makes it the best
answer now a communication log is all
Communications on the project this is
telling us what happened this is not
going to prevent this from happening The
traceability Matrix tell us who gave us
what requirement that's not going to
help you in this particular one it's not
asking for that the whole problem is
somebody didn't get a communication
the quality management plan says how you
plan to meet your quality requirements
this is not a quality requirement thing
here this is more of a somebody didn't
get a particular
report question 15 a project manager is
overseeing the development of a new
Health Care Facility the project team is
struggling to understand some critical
aspects of the project scope a senior
subject matter expert from the
organization headquarter is available
for one week what should the project
manager do to benefit from theem
presence all right a conduct a workshop
with the to address the team challenges
all right discuss with the the specific
scope issues the team is facing okay
arrange for the to provide training
sessions to the team all
right have the to review the project
documentation for alignment okay so this
one here follow the mindset on this one
to get this one correct and the best
answer
is if you got C you are doing it correct
okay here's why I tell I keep telling
you guys you need to be collaborative
you need not don't do things by yourself
if you're not included the team and
you're just doing the work by yourself
and you're making your own decision it's
probably not the best answer that's not
good servant leadership that's more of
like a being like a dictator and you're
making all the decisions for the team so
let's go through this notice this one is
conduct a workshop with the to address
the team challenges this is you're doing
a workshop with the it doesn't say you
include the team here this is just you
and the working
together if you're going to be
addressing the team challenges it's best
to have the team involved in your
Workshop but that's not what that is
discuss with the SM the specific scope
once again you're not involved in the
team have the before you have them
review the doc meet with the team if
you're going to only have the for a week
there's nothing here that says uh review
that is there is that there's an
alignment problem all right that they're
just having some critical aspects of the
scope but we're not sure what the
alignment is so the best thing is bring
the if you have an bring them in to help
train the team so that way they can have
a better understanding of the project
scope question number 16 a project
manager is leading an agile project
developing a new customer relation
management
system Midway through the project the
team receives feedback from the legal
team regarding new data protection laws
that the project might adhes
to which two action should the project
manager take next all right I want to
point out that this is a multi- uh
selection question and you're going to
be doing what's next all right direct
the product owner to prioritize the data
protection features and future Sprints
okay request detailed information with
new laws from the legal department all
right have the legal team implement the
compliance measures all right plan the
immediate integration compliance
requirements to mitigate any legal
issues all right conduct an impact
analysis for the team to understand how
this law affects your project basically
okay what did you get best answer here
remember to choose two the first one I
got is B and the second one I got is C
here's why now before we take action
before this law is implemented the first
thing you guys got to do is you guys got
to say what is this law about so let's
go and learn about the law
the next thing you got to do is before
something is implemented you got to
understand how it's going to impact the
project that's e those are the two
answers
now once you do B and
E maybe then you want to speak to the
product
owner uh maybe then you want to plan how
to integrate this all into the project
all right that's what you got to
remember don't take an action just like
that assess the situation see what's
going on understand what's happening
around you before taking an action this
is a type of an action notice your
talent to prioritize the work you just
can't implement the compliance measures
without understanding that C and D
without understanding how it's going to
affect your project making B and E the
best
answer question number 17 a project
manager is initia a new software
development project for a client known
for their vague requirements and
challenging communication all sit sound
align this so this client always gives
you vague requirements and it's hard to
communicate the previous interactions
with this clients have led to
misunderstanding about the scope okay
what strategy should the project manager
Implement to prevent this so you're
looking to what can we do to stop this
from even
happening apply a phase development
approach to validate the scope at each
at each Milestone okay collaborate with
a product owner to establish a clear
minimum viable product all right enhance
team client communication ation protocol
to ensure better Clarity and feedback
okay sounds good Implement a strict
deliverable schedule schedules to force
Clarity and client interaction all right
follow the mindset on this but you have
to know your agile practices in order to
get this one correct because the best
answer here is going to be be the
minimum viable product and your exam
likes this concept of minimum viable
product before I I get before I give you
the answer why there's one answer you
should have
eliminated if you ever get a question
and some of the choices sounds negative
like forcing people telling people they
have to do
something it's probably never going to
be the right answer if you're firing
somebody it's never going to be the
right answer never be negative if
something sounds negative or sounds bad
or sounds like you're pushing people to
do something probably not the right
answer let's see notice this Choice here
says Implement strict deliverables to
force CL never do anything to force
anyone throw that right off the bat a
phase development approach to validate
the scope well this notice at the end of
each Milestone Milestones can take a
long
time you want something much more
quicker now this is where this question
got tricky a good percentage of you
probably went with C notice this one
here is team client communication so I
like this answer better Clarity and
feedback I like this good but you know
what's better you know what is better
than just speaking with the client is
giving them a product and have them give
you back feedback notice vague
requirements vague requirements the way
to beat vague requirements is with a
minimum viable product keep in mind what
a minimum viable product is it's a
product that you release to your
customers that has very it has basic
usable functionality but it doesn't have
all the functionality when you give this
to the clients they're more likely to
use it and they'll tell you what they
like and what they don't like so this is
really good because what this does is
that it really pushes the client to tell
you things to change things to update
things to remove the best way to get
somebody involved is is to give them the
thing to use versus communicating just
communicating with them so the best
answer here is going to be your minimum
viable
product 18 in the middle of software
development project following a
predictive uh life cycle a significant
portion of the software is set for
incremental delivery to the client the
experienced team responsible for this
portion has expressed the desire to take
on more decision-making responsibilities
traditionally handled by the project
manager after each delivery what should
you do a schedule a meeting with Senior
Management to seek their guidance or
adjust in the decision-making process B
support the team initiatives to take on
decision-making responsibilities while
retaining final approval authority C
maintain the traditional decision-making
structure with the project man receives
all decisions regardless of team's uh
Readiness D consult with sponsor explore
the option of delegating key postd
delivery decisions with the team choose
the best answer don't forget this is a
predictive or a traditional life cycle
best answer here the mindset should have
eliminated a couple choices right off
the bat for you such as go on a senior
management never go to Senior Management
for guidance they hired you to do the
project not for you to go and ask them
how to do it so is your sponsorer that's
a type of Senior
Management the sponsor wants the output
they don't need they don't need to come
and help you do your project never give
away your work now you got two answers B
support the team initiatives on
decision- making sounds good maintain
the
traditional if you get a question on
your exam and the choice one of the
choices says leave it alone don't do
anything um like maintain the TR
maintain a plan maintain the current
structure if you read the choice and it
seems like okay this choice is not doing
anything to the question it's leaving
whatever they were doing before it's not
the answer so you notice maintain this
traditional decision-making structure so
then you're not this answer really
doesn't do anything to the question
making this the best answer bring the
team support the team right support the
team team Initiative for making but
remember it is a predictive project and
in the predictive project you probably
have that final critical decision making
in an agile project is generally the
team using it remember agile project
really utilize that servant leader
mentality versus traditional project
probably
not 19 a project manager is overseeing
the development of a new software tool
although the tool isn't fully finished
the product owner has decided to release
an early version the minimum viable
product a key stakeholder the vice
president of marketing is unhappy with
the limited feature in in the launch
what should the produ project manager do
to ensure a better satisfaction for your
future release so they're asking what
can we do now to fix problems later work
with the team and stakeholders to adjust
future
release uh future release timelines
based on expectations okay set up a
process where stakeholders can provide
feedback before future releases are
finalized all right take control of the
communication with the stakeholders to
ensure everyone understands ask the
sponsor to resolve the disagreement
between the product owner and the vice
president of marketing okay best answer
here you could use the mindset and
eliminate a couple of these choices
right off the bat let's see what the
best answer here is now work with the
team notice that you know if you're if
you're going through these questions and
you're up to number 20 you've done the
first 10 you you you're getting the
theme here right you're always working
with people you're always collaborating
with someone you're meeting with the
team you're meeting with the sponsor
right uh to get the project approve all
right don't go to the sponsor to to help
you with your work so always collaborate
notice D act a sponsor to resolve never
give away your work don't go to the
sponsor and says go do this never do
that take control notice this take
control where take now you
are it's an agile project how do you
know well they're using a minimum viable
product all right it doesn't necessarily
have to say it's an agile project but by
reading this you can tell it's an agile
project when it's an agile project you
should be working with the team be a
servant leader on that agile project if
you start taking control of stuff you're
not really a servant leader at that
point so let's eliminate that set up a
process St can provide although I like
this the team should be involved in
it uh so this is a good answer but it
let the team bring people in notice
you're setting up the process by
yourself here probably not a good idea
let's bring the team in let's bring the
stakeholders in because in this one
you're working with the team and the
stakeholders to adjust future timelines
all right all right last question in
this
video question 20 a project manager is
overseeing an adile project for
developing a new mobile application
within a large tech company initially
the project manager planned to use email
for all project communication
however the product owner suggest using
a specialized project management tool
that better integrates with agile
workflow what should the project manager
do okay so in this question the product
owner wants you to use a particular tool
on your project what do we
do a evaluate how the new communication
tool could impact the current timelines
and workflow before making a decision
okay update the communication management
plan to fully adapt the products owner's
preferred tool and inform the team of
the change all right have the team test
the proposed tool on a small part of the
project before deciding whether to
implement it across the
team D continue using email for major
announcement but use the new tool for
daily agile interactions with the team
now the mindset should have eliminated
almost every choice and given you the
full answer hopefully you guys got this
one correct let's go see why some of
these choices was pretty easily
eliminated making the end
C here's why Number One D get rid of
this because in this one nothing is
really happening you're still using this
and the product owner wants you to use
their specialized tool by you doing D
you're not giving a product owner
anything you're not really assessing
much and you're making the decisions all
by yourself you're making a decision to
use the email you're making a decision
to only use the tool part of it a
notice uh before making a decision once
again you're making a decision you're
not getting anyone involved you're
evaluating it you're doing this by
yourself you're not being that servant
leader you're not
collaborating update the communication
manag now you're just implementing the
tool you're just bypassing a whole team
here you're like hey you know what I'm
just going to implement this you guys
you guys can pound salt or Rock what's
that say you guys can pound salt you
guys can pound sand there you go you
guys can pound sand we're going to be
doing this versus C says have the team
tested bring them and let them decide
whether it's good to implement all right
here we go guys question number 21 by
the way I do want to point out that uh
if you haven't take a look at the other
videos see how you're doing on these
Ultra hard questions these questions are
purposely made to be difficult these are
probably going to be more difficult than
you would see on the actual test let's
keep going all right question number 21
during the development of a new
cloud-based analytical platform the team
has risen concerns about certain product
backlog items that are challenging to
implement due to Technical and resource
limitations what should the project
manager recommend for the product owner
to do now this is a good question
because if you notice on this particular
question you have a problem and then
it's asking what the product owner
should do with a particular problem it's
a very unique question a prioritize and
address the impediment based on the
impacts on the most valuable features on
the platform okay conduct a risk
assessment to evaluate how the
impediment might affect the project
timeline all right Implement a phase
based approach to solving the issue
starting with those imp that those that
impact the current Sprint remove the
items and add new items okay so what
should we be doing here now first of all
I want you guys to realize that it says
it's asking what the project manager
should recommend the product owner do
and this alone tells you the answer to
this if you read carefully you should
have gotten a here's why because first
of all you should eliminate some some
choices number one you should never just
remove items because of problems if
those items are high value items you
shouldn't just go about removing them
maybe you should solve those problems
first maybe if you can never solve them
maybe then you can remove them but let's
get get rid of this Implement a
phase-based approach
uh to solve the to solving the issues
starting with the impact on the current
Sprint there's not much here about that
current Sprint conduct the risk
assessment you're not going to ask the
product owner to conduct the risk
assessment that's something you and the
team should be doing don't recommend the
product owner to do it the product owner
is really responsible to prioritize the
work and the product backlog right now
what they should be doing the product
owner should be taught that you know
what maybe you want to change the
priority based on some of those impact
on there so work with the product owner
on this making that the best
answer all right question
22 a project manager new to Agile
methodologies is overseeing the
development of a software tool observing
that other projects stumble without a
well- defined scope and completion
criteria leading to continuous scope
expansion the project manager wants to
prevent similar issues what proactive
steps should the project manager take to
establish Clarity and prevent scope
creep okay good question they're really
asking here uh about preventing scope
creep okay create a detailed timeline
with Milestones to monitor project
progress and control
changes okay introduce a rigorous change
management process to evaluate and
approve additional features okay promote
regular synchronization meetings between
the project team to discuss project
schedule and what work to do first all
right organize workshops with all
stakeholders to collaboratively create
the project Charter and clearly define
the definition of done okay guys this I
thought was a pretty easy question
here's why and but it's still difficult
but I thought it was pretty easy and the
reason why is because if you notice it's
an agile
project if you're following agile
methodology IES you're not going to have
a rigorous change management approach
you're not going to be just controlling
changes like
that c is not a bad answer but C is
talking about the
schedule right discuss project schedule
not the work right this is about scope
creep so let's get rid of that now what
addresses scope creep what
addresses uh Clarity on the scope
there's nothing that in my opinion that
does a better job of addressing the
clarity of the work than a minimum
viable product and a definition of done
so in this one here we have the
definition of done because if you notice
the definition of done is really when
they Define what is it that they
actually want how does the team know
when they're finished how does how how
does the team know what our product has
hit a certain criteria or a certain
performance or look a certain way for
them to be done best answer is d
23 throughout a project it becomes
apparent that team members from
different departments have different
different perspectives on what the final
outcome of the project should be what
should the project manager do first
facilitate a session to revise and
clarify the project goal with the entire
team okay meet with the sponsor to
ensure alignment to the project
objectives all right make sure the
project outcome is aligned with the
project Charter and scope statement all
right assign the department heads the
responsibility of resolving the issue
okay so in this particular one keep in
mind what are you going to do first all
right you have team members from
different departments they have
different perspectives what should we do
first best answer here is to bring them
together
yes part of the mindset when it comes to
this exam is bring people together and
solve problems don't go away from them
don't run from a problem never kick the
can down the road in other words don't
give away the problem or push the
problem off and never do nothing all
right if one of the choices says leave
the problem fix it later it's never the
answer so you notice in this one
here we have facilitate session to
clarify the goals let's bring everybody
together and let's have everybody
understand what the problem is never go
to the sponsor meet to a sponsor to
ensure a line the sponsor already knows
the objectives this has nothing to do
with the sponsor this is team members
this doesn't address the problem make
sure the outcome is aligned with the
charter and scope statement this is a
problem with team members assign the
department there's nothing here with
department heads it's with the team
members best answer here was
a 24 a project manager is overseeing the
construction of a new manufacturing
facility when an econom economic
downturn May suddenly threaten the
projects
viability what should the project
manager do adjust the Project's
Financial forecast to account for the
economic downturn suggest to the
sponsorer that the project should be
postponed redirect some project
resources to support other essential
projects identify and document a new
risk and create a re and create
mitigation strategies all right let's
see what the answer is now this one not
that difficult you have to read
carefully when you look at questions
look at this you have to look and
understand that with you see something
that says may when you look at something
that says might that's a risk if you see
something that will
happen or or has happened and it's
affecting a project that's an issue so
in this particular one since we know
this is a risk we're going to have to
identify which we're doing here we want
to document this new risk probably in
the risk register and then we want to
create a mitigation strategy to how to
address it now I want you guys to
understand that
you shouldn't take an action just like
that the project manager mindsets says
don't take an action right away right
you notice for first of all this is a
construction project so it's more likely
a traditional project and because it's a
traditional project you never take
actions right away because if you go and
you change a plan you change a schedule
you change a scope you're going to need
what a change request and none of the
other choices even begins to address
that so the best answer here is this
notice this is an action notice never go
to the sponsor or never postpone a
project just like that you have to
assess it do can't just redirect
resources you're basically shutting the
project
down 25 a project manager is starting a
highway Expansion Project the State
Transportation Department requested an
initial environmental impact assessment
after after which they'll
decide whether to continue a team member
suggests planning for the full Project
based on past Trends what should the
project manager do first notice
first advise the team member to focus on
the current deliverable okay review the
charter to confirm the high level scope
all right develop a detail plan for the
entire project for the entire Project
based on history all right confirm with
the stakeholders and plan the full
project scope this was a very tough
question there was one choice you could
have eliminated and I'm just going to
eliminate it right off the bat never do
nothing thing this one here shuts down
the team say just do the current work
the problem with this thing here is that
you're starting a project right it's
still in that initiating phase now what
you should be doing first is assess
review look at things don't take an
action right away notice that this is an
action confirm with the stakeholders and
plan the full scope you have you can't
do that you have to wait for this
assessment to be
done the best thing here you can do is
just review the scope and confirm the
high level scope for now and wait until
the assessment is done if not you
wouldn't be able to proceed on the
project this was a very tricky
question uh it was trying to push you to
do something that you shouldn't be doing
but keep in mind it says what to do
first and you know one of the things you
never do first is just take an
action right off the bat
26 a project manager is overseeing the
upgrade of an old manufacturing system
to a new automated solution aligning
with the organizational operational
process changes the project Charter is
approved and the pmo has provided
templates for all new projects what
should the project manager
prioritize well what are we going to be
prioritizing here all right so we just
started this new thing we got the
charters approved pmos approved the
template choices a align the project
plan with the organization strategic
goals working closely with Senior
Management
okay develop a training and
communication management plan in turn
collaboration with the team all right
collaborate a detailed budget and
schedule regular reviews with the
finance team okay collaborate with the
operation departments to minimize
disruption during the upgrade this was a
tricky question you notice the charter
is
approved you have all the templates what
should you prioritize well the next
thing you do is make the plan right so
which one here is going to help you make
a plan and who should you make the plan
with that's the that's how you're going
to get the answer the answer here is B
here's
why align the plan with the Strategic
goals cool but you're never going to
work with Senior Management on a plan
Senior Management doesn't sit there and
help you come up with detailed plans
remember a project plan is a very
detailed
document now create a detailed budget
with the finance department you do this
with your team not the finance
department or the operation Department
what you should do is collaborate with
the team and the way to collaborate is
to have good communication so maybe one
of the first things you develop is that
communication management plan kind of a
tricky question but that is the best of
these four choices now I do want to
point out that sometimes you're doing
practice questions minds or anybody's
and you're like well that choice kind of
suck Andrew
the question is is it the best of the
four the choice doesn't have to be
amazing or the choice doesn't have to be
the only one that's correct the choice
has to be better than the other three
choices that are there if it's four
remember the game is to choose the best
choice not the correct choice and I I
keep telling students this all the time
they'll tell me Well Andrew that choice
is not going to really do anything is it
better than the other three and they'll
be like yeah it is okay then that's the
answer remember it's the best of the
four choices keep that in
mind
27 a project manager has just completed
the development of a new city park and
is preparing to transition transition
the project to the city maintenance uh
Department before closing the project
what should the project manager do
verify all project deliver has met
according to the project plan okay
conduct the final inspection with the
sponsor to Ure all tasks is the WBS are
complete
okay ensure all project documentation is
completed and archive conduct a final
performance review with the stakeholders
so really good question very difficult
answer best answer here is going to be B
now hold your horses don't go crazy I
know a lot of people got this one wrong
here it's not in closing it says before
closing on a traditional project
what do you do before closing what is
the process that comes before closing
verify scope right you should do um
control quality then do verify scope
verify scope is when you generally bring
the customer and or sponsorer to verify
the work has been done then you can
close the project Which choice best
gives you that b gives you that ensure
all document is complete and archived
that's in the Clos in final performance
review that's the performance of the
project performance not the deliverable
performance that's en
closing there were two good answers is
either a or b verify the objectives has
been met according to the plan but
before you do that that's also a part in
closing before you do that you need to
verify the inspection of the work in the
process of verify scope one of the tools
is inspection and the output is a
verified deliverable if you have no clue
what I'm talking about check out the
course check out my course link below to
learn all about those
processes before I get to uh 28 if
you're enjoying this video and you're
learning a lot how to Ace your exam can
you do me a quick favor can you click on
the like button can you um subscribe to
the channel it really helps us out like
if I'm begging you here if you can do
that for us would be amazing doesn't
cost you much it's and by the way it's
free to do that it's absolutely free
like it doesn't cost you anything to do
that um
28 a project manager needs to prioritize
multiple projects within a portfolio and
requires accurate budget estimates the
process must align with adob principles
one insuring reliable financial plan how
should the how should the budget for
each project be
estimated okay calculate the cost by
estimating individual Tas estimate for
the team considering the current
workload all right leverage the combined
expertise of the projects of the sponsor
product owner and agile coach to deive
budget estimates okay use analytical
software to model potential costs based
on predictive analysis and historical
all right have the productor conduct a
thorough requirements analysis with the
team to forecast project budget this one
not too difficult read the section in my
study guide or in the course that talks
about how do you do Agile estimated an
agile estimated is really comes down to
since it's heavily people built it comes
down to how much you're paying everybody
and how long they're going to be on the
project and how many Sprints they are
there's a couple there's a couple
answers here to to throw out have the
product owner conducted never give away
your work this is based on predictive
analysis no good leverage the expertise
of the sponsor product owner and agile
coach the best expertise the the actual
cost of the agile project lies in how
much money you're paying your workers
that's why you're going to use a it's
how much agile is heavily people it's
not so much so in a product project
where a lot of the cost may be
associated with materials like if you're
building a building sheetrock is going
to be a big cost or steal Adar projects
are mostly done by people so you're
leveraging the cost of the team make an
a the best
answer 29 a project manager is
overseeing a large scale agile project
to develop a new e-commerce platform at
the Project's retrospective the team
discusses that the product owner's
expectation for the Sprint deliverables
were not fully met what proactive
measure should the project manager have
taken initiate a kickoff project
Workshop to ensure all team members are
trained on agile tools and techniques
used for the project okay establish a
risk management framework that
specifically addresses potential
misalignments between team outputs and
stakeholders okay develop an integration
plan to systematically align development
work with ongoing marketing and sales
strategy D ensure the project vision and
objectives to each Sprint were
communicated to all team
members
okay now you have to read this one very
carefully all right notice join a
retrospective they discuss the productor
expectations we're not met it's it's a
question that's making you look
backwards it's what measur should have
been taken right it's what you got to
read the question do they want the
solutions to go forward or do they want
the solutions that could have fix this
problem in this particular one it's what
should have been
done notice if the team is working and
not sure of what the work should have
been done that should have been
clarified from the start they should
have known what the project Vision was
what the main objectives was that should
have been clearly communicated to ensure
all members know what you know what is
it that they should have been
accomplishing
this one says a uh a project kickoff
Workshop kickoff workshops are generally
done once at the beginning of the
project not just throughout this is not
a it's nothing here about
risk it already happened right to
potential
misalignment develop an integration plan
to systematically
align uh development work and ongoing
they already noce they are first of all
they do the standup meeting but this is
with marketing and sales it's the
product owner that's not expectation so
that was a throw off making D the best
answer all right last question in this
video we're doing number 30 a project
manager is leading the development of a
new customer support software support
Software System dur to Sprint a
developers encounters ambiguity
regarding the acceptance criteria of a
feature what should the project manager
do come be a meeting with the stering
committee to discuss the feature
initiate a discussion the discussion in
the next team meeting to gather
Collective input refer the question to
the technical architect to provide an
expert interpretation collaborate with a
product owner to resolve the ambiguity
and the acceptance criteria this one
here you have to understand agile
principles making D the best answer you
see you got to understand where this
acceptance criteria come from who
defines the work basically and that's
the product owner if the team is not too
sure of what the work should be the team
doesn't know what it should look like or
or how it should perform how it should
what report it should output that is
part of the product owner to help to
find that Mak can this the best answer
this is a the stering committee the
accepting criteria doesn't come from
there it comes from the from the product
owner and the next to gather input it's
not that the team is having a problem
it's the team to the product owner not
the team within themselves you don't
want to go to a technical architect you
need to go to the product owner they're
the one that's going to create that
acceptance criteria guys question 31
during the execution phase of a project
develop of a development project the
team encounters te a technical challenge
that jeopardizes the schedule the
scheduled delivery of key
functionalities the technical team has
indicated a delay what should the
project manager do next schedule an
emergency meeting with all stakeholders
to brainstorm
Solutions initiate a quick training
session for the technical team to
enhance their problem solving
capabilities record the problem its
impact and urgency in the project issue
log for struct structure tracking
organize a team building event to boost
moral and encourage Innovative thinking
for problem this question here is pretty
easy because if you notice this is not a
risk this is an issue now this question
does take a lot of the mindset though
because if you notice I just mentioned
it's an issue and if there is an issue
you have to make sure that you put it
into the issue log now I want to point
out a couple things here that's really
important to know first of all you can't
do training sessions on Tech to the
technical team the project manager
doesn't or generally doesn't have the
technical skills to train a technical
team this exam makes that assumption
that you don't have that technical skill
so B is definitely
wrong schedule an emergency meeting with
all I want you guys to be careful of
this word all all stakeholders that
includes Senior Management regulatory
bod you're going to schedule a meeting
with all anytime you see that word all
in a choice think to yourself
H I really have to think about this
because all literally means all you're
going to invite everybody everybody
every single stakeholder you probably
want to do this with your technical team
or the team themselves not with all
stakeholders now organize a team
building event there's nothing here that
talks about moral and encouragement the
team doesn't doesn't say that the team
is is feeling demoralized or something
like that so this doesn't even answer
the question but this is an issue and
this is the best way to solve
issues during a pivotal project phase it
is revealed that critical stakeholders
did not attend a meeting focus on
confirming the project strategic
alignment and expected business
benefits resulting in their feedbacks
being overlooked this over site had led
to conflicts within the decision-making
process what should the project manager
do
first so couple things you notice it
says what are you doing first initiate a
discussion to directly address and
understand the concern all right
distribute a detail meeting summary and
request written feedback from the absent
shareholders okay conduct a formal risk
assessment to evaluate the impact of
Missin cers input develop a contingency
plan to navigate potential project
delays or changes all right what do you
guys have now notice it says what should
you do first now anytime there's a
conflict on a project part of the
mindset it tells us is to bring people
together address the conflict and solve
the conflict this one here does exactly
that I mean it literally says directly
address and understand the root cause
part of the mindset is never take action
against a
problem even in the pmo guide it gives
you the list of things you have to do it
literally says understand the problem
before solving the problem get to the
root cause of the problem why are we
having this problem who started this
problem where did this problem come from
these are things you're thinking about
before solving the
problem now the problem here is that
they didn't attend the meeting never do
something that is that sounds negative
not this in B you did you're
Distributing a detail meeting summary
and request written feed Fe back from
the so this is kind of negative in my
opinion it's like well then give me
feedback on this you weren't
here this is notice a form of risk
analysis uh to evaluate the impact of
missing shareholders input this is not a
risk they've already missed it all right
this is an issue they missed it develop
a contingency plan to navigate potential
delays we're not sure what delays it yet
all right this is let the conflicts
within but it doesn't say there's only
any delays here this answer is a
33 during a critical phase of the
project the pivotal team member informs
the project manager of their impended
resignation intended to sub submit their
notice to their line manager soon this
Revelation comes at a time when their
contribution is critical to meeting the
Project's upcoming deadline what should
the project manager
do have a senior team member do a
meeting to reassess task allocation and
address any concern update the project
risk register to reflect the potential
impact on the project timeline brief the
stakeholders on the situation to set
realistic expectations about potential
delays proactively collaborate with all
members to formulate a plan for
transition and mitigate project
disruption okay so it's asking here what
are we going to do notice that is the
the main thing
here so notice that this person is
leaving all right they're intending to
submit uh and it comes at a time when
it's going to when their distribution is
critical so what are we going to do the
best thing here you can do guys is to
meet with the team be proactive work
with the team come up with a plan of how
we can transition and mitigate any kind
of disruptions now they had another good
choice here but it wasn't a have a
senior never give away your work if a
choice seems like you're giving away
that work to someone it's probably never
good never right answer update the r to
reflect the potential impact on the
project
timeline this kind of affect more than
the project timeline although I like
this answer this is just a project
timeline and you shouldn't just do the
impact assessment yourself you probably
want to work with your team members on
that not just you because somebody
leaving not just can it impact the
timeline it can also Impact
scope brief the stakeholders uh
stakeholding situation said realistic
about potential delays how do you know
about the delays how do you know there
will be a delay in B and C you're
thinking there's going to be a delay but
you haven't even worked with the team
maybe the team can handle the work and
there wouldn't be a delay
correct making D the best
answer 34 in a software development
project as the team moves into into the
development phase they decide to utilize
time tracking to estimate efforts with
one hour of effort equaling one point
some tasks are estimated at Five Points
While
others extend up to 200 points to
enhance the project accurate accy in
scheduling what should the project
manager encourage the team to do a
recommend divide dividing task into
subtasks to improve man manageability
and estimation
accuracy B have the team use new
estimate and technique that better
reflects the complexity C encourage the
adaptation of a fixed point system for
all
tasks have the team D have the team
recolor point system to better different
simple and complex
now you really have to use the mindset
on this if you put the mindset on this
it wasn't that difficult so let me show
you guys what the mindset here is the
best way to do this is to have them
recommend first of all recommend you
really shouldn't just tell the team what
to do this is D you're telling them what
to do this is a you're telling them what
to
do work with the team all right
recommend
in order for estimation to be accurate
the work has to be broken down to
smaller chunks subdividing the work
decompose the work we do decomposition
in both agile and traditional projects
so we would recommend to do more
decomposition encourage it a fixed point
for all tasks
again there's no way you can have a fix
point system for all tests this one
doesn't even make
sense uh and again be care careful with
that word all make an a the best answer
there 35 a tech startup is gearing up to
launch a groundbreaking app by the
upcoming summer however during the
initial planning they encounter
uncertainty in Project
specifications they're not sure how
stakeholders will use the product what
should the project manager take to
ensure the project stays on track
incorporate insights from technology
Consultants establish a comprehensive
Rich management framework to anticipate
and mitigate potential delays assess the
team and proposing a minimum viable
product organize Workshops the project
team to list to solidify the Project's
technical requirement okay so you notice
uncertainty dur specification what can
help on certainty that's the key word
the best way to do that is an MVP a
minimum viable product so what an MVP is
is a thing that you release it's not the
full product it doesn't have all the
features but it has a bunch of usable
features it it's something you build you
give to your customers they use it they
utilize it they tell you if you're going
right if you're going wrong what to
change what to update this is one of the
best way to address any uncertainty on a
project this is the only choice that
actually deals with that we can this the
best answer in corporate insights we
don't want technology Consultants
uncertainty should come from your
customers not
Consultants yes a framework is good but
it says mitigate delays there's much
more than delays here it's scope not
schedule workshops with the development
team you know what the development team
needs to work with the customers not
just with themselves best answer is
C anyway we are now up to question 35 if
you're enjoying this video and you're
learning a lot I would really appreciate
if you can click on that like button
doesn't cost anything it's absolutely
free but we put a lot of time and effort
into making these questions in this
video so if you appreciate the time and
effort we put in all we ask for is at
least clicking on the like button and
subscribe to the channel click the
notification Bell that way when the next
video comes out questions 41 to 50
you'll be you'll be the first to know
36 during a large scale event planning
project the project manager notices a
growing list of logistical challenges
reported by various team members
although these challenges have been
acknowledged in team meetings few have
been effectively resolved leading to
potential risk for the event success
what should the project manager
doing schedule additional planning
sessions specifically focus on
logistical challenges
assign a dedicated team to focus solely
on identifying and res resolving
logistical issues
prioritizing the logistical challenges
based on their their potential impact on
the event increase the frequency of Team
meetings to ensure more regular updates
on challenges all right let's see what
we're going to do here guys the best
answer here is going to be c not sure if
you got that but let's see why so let's
look back look back at the question
there's a growing list of logistical
challenges they've been acknowledged in
meetings but they haven't really been
resolve this is leading to potential
risks so schedule additional session
specifically focus on this logistical
challenge this was a good answer I'm
going to show you why that one is wrong
in a second though assign a dedicated
team to solely identify and resolve
these that just never just give away to
work for the team you have to work with
the
team increase the frequ the meeting is
not going to just do this it you need to
challenge the the logistics notice
schedule additional planning
sessions this is the problem we don't
need plan maybe we can do maybe
additional meeting this is planning
sessions eliminating that the best
answer here is you have to start
prioritizing this when you have notice
potential risk when there's a risk the
risk has to be
prioritized prioritize it based on their
impact on the event that would be the
best thing here that you should be doing
now if you're wondering well shouldn't
you be working with the team on that
that is true and I would like that
choice but C is the best of these four
here you don't need additional planning
sessions that's wrong a dedicated team
never give away to work and increase the
frequency is not going to help it so the
best thing here to do with risk is to
prioritize
them 36 37 I mean during the execution
phase of an urban development project
the project manager uses email updates
to keep all stakeholders
in the city and form feedback indicates
that some stakeholders find the
information either too technical or to
General what should you do first
initiate a one-on-one briefing for
stakeholders needing detailed
explanations organize a workshop to keep
them
inform email the specific evaluate the
specific needs of the stakeholders
launch or Project Blog that provides
updates in varying level of details best
answer here is before
you sent it out you know the first thing
you should really be doing is to
understand what are the needs of the
stakeholders and you should tailor the
communication to each individual
stakeholder a one-on-one briefing will
take forever because we know it's an
urban project and it could be a lot of
stakeholders a workshop a workshop some
of them may want some of them may not
want launch a Project
Blog although I like this maybe you want
to do c I would do c maybe then do B so
they have varying level of details but
evaluate their needs
first 38 during the deployment phase of
a new telecommunication Network the
project encounters significant delays to
identify mitigate these delays what
action should the project manager
take increase the frequency of project
status meetting to enhance
communication reallocate resources to
the most delayed aspect of the project
adust the timeline to accommodate
unexpected delay facilitate a
collaborative session with the team to
pinpoint and tackle the delays all right
this here I think is a pretty easy
question if you've been following me so
far through all throughout these uh 38
questions so
far this one here is pretty simple
because if there's a problem on the
project ask the team to help you that's
the best answer you're not going to just
increase status meetings without working
with the team never just reallocate
resource without the team and you just
can't adjust timelines as needed uh
especially you're going to on a on a
traditional project you're going to need
to change request work with the team to
solve the
problem
39 a key stakeholder request that
project manager delivers a critical
infrastructure component two weeks ahead
of schedule the project manager assesses
the situation and determine that
accessing the schedule is possible by
overlapping Pro certain
processes what is the most effective
course of
action a re-evaluate the project scope
to identify non-essential elements that
can be postponed adjust the timeline by
sequencing work to allow for parallel
activity increase the budget to allow
for overtime and additional resources
use advanced technology to automate
automate certain construction process
this one here is tricky one very tricky
here's why
this is when you're running when you're
doing overlapping
activities okay this is called Fast
Tracking not Crush fast tracking will
decrease time it increases the risk but
it generally doesn't increase cost and
because it's incre it doesn't really
increase the cost you don't need c not
to mention C would require a change
request now noce reevaluate to identify
that can be if you're going to postpone
parts of the scope that also needs to
change your
request automated technology for certain
construction this goes beyond the scope
of the
question first of all you can if you
could you can just go into a timeline
and run things in parallel you don't
need to change request to readjust
activities you can readjust activities
as long as the schedule is not changing
that's fine if it gets a little shorter
that's fine too but remember if you're
going to be extending that schedule you
might need a change request 39 best B
best
answer last question guys is 40 at the
onset of a software development project
the project manager is tasked with divis
dividing devising a strategy for for
assessing the contribution of each
developer these assessments are to be
compiled and presented to the
organization leadership at the project
conclusion watch of the project manager
what should be the project manager Next
Step arrange for regular one one
meetings with each developer to discuss
and document in their
progress okay develop clear Quantum
fiable uh criteria for evaluating
developers performance and communicate
these standards all right utilize
software development metrics like lines
of code to directly measure developers
productivity okay conduct Anonymous
surveys among team members to gather
insights on individual contributions
all right this one here this is more of
an Ethics
question when it comes to ethics be fair
be upfront let people know what's being
assessed and it has to be fair and this
question in particular is saying what do
you do
next the next thing you should be doing
is coming up with a clear criterias
quantifiable criterias that's easily
measured measured with numbers is great
and then communicate them to the team so
everybody knows about
them people say a meeting with each
developer you probably want to do B
number one maybe then do a once you've
done a maybe then you can sit down with
the developers but you need to be clear
first you need to come up with your
criteria before sitting down with them
you need to know what to look for before
sitting down with them making this a
better answer than
this you don't need to utilize software
development metrics like line of codes
what if some people don't some people
are very productive and they don't have
as much line of codes as others you
don't need Anonymous survey amounts them
then they start to evaluate each other
you need to have clear and even before
you do a survey you need to do B first
making this the best answer all right
question 41 at the beginning of a new
Environmental Conservation project a key
stakeholder expressed concerns over a
Project's approach fearing it wouldn't
meet the intended environmental goals
and will exceed the initial forecast
what should the project man manager do
first all right we got this key word
there first organize a meeting with the
stakeholder to understand the concerns
and identify potential involvements all
right launch a pilot phase to
demonstrate the project Effectiveness
and adjust based on early
results C enhance communication with the
stakeholder by providing regular updates
and involving them more closely in
Project planning process outline the
long-term benefits and sustainability
impacts of the project emphasizing its
alignment with broader environmental
objectives all right the best answer
here is going to be a now let me you
know we went over this a lot in the
previous question but you notice there's
some kind of concern there's some kind
of a problem on this notice somebody's
expressing
concern and anytime you as a project
manager is faced with some stakeholder
having some kind of issue or they're
having some kind of concern or they
don't like something if the question
says what to do first first don't take
an action against it is to review meet
with that stakeholder see what's going
on assess the situation just don't go
out and Tak an action until you really
understand you know what this concern is
about so that's this one organize a
meeting with the stakeholder because you
want to understand what that concern is
now why is the others wrong well launch
a pilot program without even
understanding what the concern is you're
taking an action don't take an action
without understanding the concern you're
enhancing communication it doesn't
really say there's a communication
problem the guy doesn't have a problem
with communication he has a problem with
the Project's approach so that's not it
outline the long-term benefit I'm not
sure what this is going to do it doesn't
really state that it doesn't do the
long-term benefit the problem here is
the the approach not really the
objectives which is what D is so D
doesn't even address this all right
pretty easy one I think that one it was
kind of easy if you have the mindset
down you're starting to get it I think
this is getting a little easy for
you 42
in the midst of implementing a new
healthcare it system a project manager
faces a challenge the initial phase
involved in the upgrade of the existing
software is behind schedule impacting
the sub subsequent software
implementation phase due to Shared
technical uh teams what course of action
should the project manager take so in
this one you're facing a
challenge um you're behind schedule so
you got you got some problems here
negotiate with other project managers
for temporary resource Shar and to
expedite the hardware upgrade all right
initiate an assessment to evaluate the
impact of the delay of the overall
project timeline all right implement the
reward system for the technical team to
incentivize faster completion engage a
consultant to provide expert advice on
streamlining the hardware now in this
one here this is also one where you have
to be careful with your actions so you
notice the answer here is going to be B
you see before you go out and you
negotiate for other resources you
implement some reward system or you do
some kind of Consulting you really got
to understand well exactly how does this
really affect the project you just can't
say well okay it seems like we're behind
schedule right we're behind schedule and
it's impacting some things but how is it
affecting the budget how is this
whatever is happen how is it affecting
the budget in this one we're just
talking about time so do your assessment
before taking an
action
43 at the midpoint of renew renewable
energy project the project manager is
faced with conflict between the design
team and the environmental Consultants
regarding the feasibility of the
proposed turbine
placement the design team believes the
placement will optimize energy
Productions while the environmental
Consultants warned could lead to
significant eological
disruptions a lot of big words on this
one what should the project manager take
to resolve this
conflict okay so you got some issues
here between two teams right between the
design team and the environmental
consultant so you got issues between
them what do you do well proceed with
the Design's recommendation okay to
maximize energy output organize a
collaborative session discuss the impact
find a compromise okay consult uh
commission independent review of the
turbine's placement poon decision on a
turbine until farther data okay the best
thing here is when you have a problem
between people is to try to help them
resolve it because you don't want to
choose a side choosing a side would be
considered forcing that means the answer
here is bringing them together and have
them come up with a good solution now
compromising is not the best solution
here but I don't want you to go out and
take an action without them being
involved you
notice here you did something without
them being involved here you did
something without them you you just made
your own decision the best thing to do
is to work with the teams and work with
the teams to come up with
Solutions 44 after a new project is
executed uh executed an executive
suggest incorporating new add-on to
provide more function to the product
what should the project manager do
update the product immediately to
include the suggested scenario without
formal approval note the suggestion for
inclusion in a separate risk assessment
document integrate this executive
feedback into an appendix of the current
report encourage the executive to
formalize the suggestions to a change
request process now in this one here you
notice it says that the the new project
is executed the best assumption here is
to go with that this is a traditional
project and if anybody wants to put on a
new add-on which is going to be a scope
change the best thing here is to have
them go through the Change Control
process you just can't add in add
something to the product which is
basically a scope change without going
through that you should never just
include a scope change or an add-on to a
product without a formula approval
that's not your job to approve things
your job is to manage the team building
the deliverable not approving or
disapproving just don't do nothing you
notice note the suggestion in the risk
analysis this these one here you just it
seems like you're putting things in a
report but you're not actually dealing
with the add-on itself
45 at the onset of an urban regeneration
project the project matter observes that
although t- moral is high meetings often
diverge into unrelated conversations
causing them to over causing them to
overrun and decision to be postponed
what is the most effective initial
action for the PM to take schedule
shorter meeting to encourage more
focused discussions okay designated time
keeper to ensure meeting ADH to schedule
times adhere to schedule times C
emphasize the meeting objectives and
agenda at the beginning of each
session introduce a digital platform for
a team member to share non project
related discussions
now I wrote this question very
particularly I wrote it in a way for you
to understand that it says initial
action it's like what is the the initial
thing you try should never be the
hardest shouldn't take the most energy
you should try to solve problems the
easiest way
possible and that's C how about if you
get in front of the meeting and you
emphasize what the objectives are at the
beginning of each session this is what
we got to get done guys if this fails
maybe then you may want to go to B maybe
you may want to go to A and D then but
remember
the keyword here is initial you got to
watch the wording of the question the
initial action is never to take a
drastic action a would literally cut the
meetings down D would make you get some
kind of whole new software B designate
the initial action is just to say hey
folks we need to stop this let's see how
this this is what we got to get done
let's stick to
it 46
Journal routine progress update sessions
for multinational project a project
manager notes that one of the key
technical analysts although
exceptionally knowledgeable really
contributes to group discussions and
despite engaging despite engaging
actively in private conversations okay
so we have somebody that is very smart
technical analyst and they seem to be
good in private but they're not very
good in group discussions what should
you do schedule a dedicated dedicated
session where only the technical analyst
presents their finding to the
team I'm not sure if this is going to
work actively solicit the analyst input
during meetings emphasizing the
importance of the expertise to the
Project's success create an anonymous
feedback mechanism where the analyst can
can submit their insights without
speaking up in mediums wait for the
analyst to naturally become more
comfortable and decide to contribute to
discussions at their own pace okay let's
see how we can can answer this this I
believe was a tough question and believe
me me and the gentleman that wrote this
one I wrote this one he got this one
wrong uh I I thought this was a really
good question because you really got to
address what the question is
asking okay we want what is it we want
out of this question we want the
analysts to contribute in the group
discussion that's the
problem all right what do we do about
this well the best thing here is to talk
to this person you notice it seems like
when people are talking to this person
they talk but it seems like no one is
talking to this person so they're not
actively engaging in in these meetings
so actively solicit the analy input
during the Mee and emphasize hey these
are great things to know now why isn't
the other right
well this here takes no action if the
choice is to do nothing in other words
leave it until the analyst feels like
speaking uh or gets more comfortable
speaking this is not you might be
waiting forever if the if the option is
to do nothing it's probably not the
answer crate Anonymous feedback well is
that for everyone or just for the
analyst if it's just one person it's not
really I I had fun writing this one if
the analyst is the only one speaking
it's not really Anonymous anymore now is
it schedule a dedicated session where
they only presents their finding to the
team it's the same scenario and this one
here just they just take you out
completely but he's presenting to the
find and to the team it's better the two
choices were either A or B but notice
this one is presents their fin night to
the team if you were saying this don't
do B because he doesn't want the analyst
doesn't want to talk in front of people
well a he's talking in front of people
except you're not there that's how you
had to read that so tricky one there b
is the best
answer by the way if you're enjoying
this video so far you're getting these
questions right you're learning
something can you do me a quick favor
you know what I'm going to ask you right
click on the like button subscribe to
the channel it would be an enormous help
for us you guys don't understand how
much this helps us out YouTube does not
just a quick thing YouTube uh doesn't
recommend our videos YouTube will push
our videos to the bottom if nobody likes
it or nobody inter or engages with the
channel so we could be making content
and no one's going to watch because no
one will see it and if people stop
watching our content we'll have to stop
making them so sorry to be hard on you
guys but we got a lot of views and not a
lot of likes and or subscribe sorry for
that guys let's go back to the
questions
47 just before the final review of new
software development project the project
manager is informed by the quality
assurance team that several key features
do not meet the predefined
specifications agreed upon the client
agreed agreed upon agreed upon with the
client correcting these issues will
delay the project deliver by several
weeks what should you do next remember
the key word prioritize the work to meet
the agreed specifications accepting the
project timeline may need to be extended
all right suggest a partial delivery of
the project to the client with
non-client comp uh with non-compliant
features to be updated in future release
propose a compromise on a specification
to the client reducing the scope to
match your current state consult with
the development team to find a faster
solution that could delay that could
reduce the delay while attempting to
meet the specification
now you got to be careful with this word
next it's like okay you realize we're
probably going to be late we're not
going to have everything what should you
do next like what are you going to do
right away and the best answer here is
going to be D meet with the team and ask
them hey is there can we find a faster
way can we get this
done right uh notice is informed by the
quality of Insurance team even if the
quality insurance team tells you this
you got to go to them and you got to say
to them hey can you do this any
quicker um and can we reduce is there a
way to reduce this delay and maybe then
you can go back and tell the client but
the first thing you should do not the
quality insurance team calls you up and
says this and your only thing is okay
let me go tell the client and move on no
so consult with the team let's find a
faster way you cannot prioritize work
like that that's something the team team
or the sponsor should be doing suggest a
partial delivery you never want to just
deliver especially with non-compliant
features this is something the T the the
um first of all you would need your
sponsor or your customers to approve
that uh propose a compromise you should
never like this see was the throwout you
know I add this in here to kill this
every time we write questions there
always going to be a few choices called
throwaways or I call them garbage
choices in other words you shouldn't
select that the moment it says that you
reduce the scope you don't have that
power to just reduce scope agile and
their traditional projects the project
manager doesn't have the power to just
remove a remove scope parts that's
something the sponsor or the product
owner should be
doing tough
question 48 during a critical phase of
an Agile development project a
specialist responsible for designing a
key component is unexpected required to
take extensive medical leave the special
task are now at risk of delay as they
were to so individual equipped with the
necessary expertise H sto individual
what proactive measure could a project
man have taken to mitigate the risk
build a cross functional
team distribute The Specialist task
amount several members from the project
onset okay establish a comprehensive
documentation practice for all project
task okay allocate addition funds to
hire temporary Specialists if needed now
notice it says here what proactive this
is the key word like what could you have
done to stop this or to reduce the blow
of this all of these choices are not too
bad except one of them all right like
allocate extra funds to hire temporary
specialist maybe unless you would have
predicted this in the risk assessment
the best thing here if you know agile
you know you should build a team of
generalizing
specialist across functional team what
this does is that everybody is able to
help each other in this one you built a
specialist team you went against the
rules of agile you want a cross
functional team a team where everybody
is capable of helping everybody else
this
reduces all kind of bottlenecks with the
team I Do cover this in the course so
make sure you check out the agile team
section distribute this here was
something that you would have probably
done afterwards but then it would have
been hard to predict who's going to be
in and out right this one this is the
throwaway Choice here to me because how
could you predicted this you distribute
just this guy's task you would have to
done it to everybody not just this
person notice does specialist tasks you
would have never noticed this because
notice it's
unexpectedly comprehensive practice for
all project tasks that would have been
okay but it's not this is a specialist
task only this person is capable of
doing it although I like the it's best
to make sure that you have a good
generalizing
specialist uh cross functional team okay
two more to goal in the planning phase
of a large software implementation
project the project manager decides to
conduct an extensive analysis of
potential risk associated with the
Project's timeline and budget the goal
is to understand the likelihood of a
project completion within the defined
perimeters and to identify which
variable most significantly impact the
project outcome using many different
perspectives what technique should the
project manager apply to evaluate and
address the risk now so you're doing a
risk assessment basically you're looking
at the likelihood of the risk you're
looking at certain perimeters from
different perspectives
hm what technique are you doing here
well are you developing a RIS breakdown
structure uh conducting a sensitivity
analysis utilize a cause and effect
diagram
or Monte Carlo this is a straightforward
knowledge based question that I wrote in
a very difficult way best answer here is
going to be the this is a Monti cardo
simulation a Monti cardo simulation
looks at many many many many different
scenarios
perspectives uh or different outcomes
that can affect projects for example if
this if you have this weather event how
is it going to affect this project like
what's going to happen if the if you had
a category 4 hurricane category 5
hurricane a blizzard so you're looking
at all different perspectives and how
it's going to affect the project and
that really is what this is describing a
cause and effect diagram will tell you
the reasons for risks or the cause of
failure this is a fishbone diagram
sensitivity analysis starts to rank them
up this looks at particular impacts of
positive and negative risk RIS breakdown
structure just categorize your RIS this
is looking at different
perspectives question 50 on a project to
to develop a new CRM system the project
manager launch that that a stakeholder
meeting laar during the stakeholder
meeting that UPC that upcoming
regulatory changes will affect data
handling processes within the system the
change are expected to be enforced
shortly after the Project's planned
completion date what is the most
appropriate action for the project man
ensure the projects remain compliant
with the new regulation okay incorporate
the regulations into the Project's risk
log for future
analysis plan to address the regulator
in the next CRM system the uh
development integrate discussion of the
regulatory changes into the project
phases request immediate detailed
information during the next product
update Meed
okay best answer here now this one was
tricky because first of all it's not a
risk all right notice incorporate into
the Project's risk R should say risk
register uh but it's not a risk because
this
will affect the data handle it this leg
if it was like it might then you may
want to add it to the risk
register but it's not a might this is a
will this is something that will happen
it's guaranteed to happen so it's not a
risk risk has
probability now you don't want to wait
for the next system to be developed and
that's D also immediate detailing inform
change during the next product update
you got to do it right now because
you're going to you're going to be
pushing this thing out and then that
regulation is going to come in the best
thing here you can do is start
incorporating that regulation into what
you are doing question 51 during a
mobile application development project
the project manager faces significant
uncertainty regarding user preferences
and the effectiveness of proposed
features the initial user feedback has
been
inconclusive leading to questions about
the project current direction what is
the best course of action for the
project manager to ensure the project
aligns with users expectations finish
developing the application and correct
all features not align with users
expectation proceed with the creation of
an MVP and if you're not familiar this
means minimum viable product pause
development efforts until a
comprehensive market analysis provides
clear guidance on user preference
instruct the development team to
incorporate the most popular features of
complete an application to ensure
relevance okay best answer here is going
to be
MVP here's why first of all before we
get into it what's an MVP so minimum
viable product is something that the
team releases to the customers to get
feedback for example let's say they're
making this mobile application do you
have to release the entire mobile
application to the users to get feedback
no you you release something that's
minimal something that's usable it
doesn't have every single feature but it
has some of the core features something
that you can give them that they can use
they can play with they can input data
that way you can get great feedback on
it MVP is a popular topic on your exam
it is in the exam objective so make sure
you understand what it is now why is
this the best answer well you notice the
question specifically States the
effectiveness of these features the only
which TR to understand the effectiveness
of the features is to get the users to
use them they'll tell you whether those
features are effective now and being
that there's a lot of uncertainty the
best way to gain certainty is to have
the users use it give them the features
it wouldn't be a good idea to finish the
entire thing and then correct it all
this is more like Kick the Can down the
road and fix later which is something we
never want to do the mindset tells us
never kick the can down the road never
pause your project is part of the
mindset unless there's something major
going on on like a safety issue and
somebody may die or you're breaking the
law you shouldn't be pausing your
project instruct the development team to
incorporate the most popular features
but how do we know if these features are
even going to be effective it's not just
about being the popular feature best
answer was B 52 in anticipation of new
environmental regulations a
manufacturing project involve in two
distinct operational teams one using
traditional manufacturing methods
and the other employing Green Technology
and they need to evaluate the impact of
these regulations on combined
operation what is the most effective
action for the project manager to ensure
compliance and seamess integration okay
so we got two teams right we have one
using traditional the other one using
green technology and they need to
evaluate the impact of regulations all
right a organize a collaborative
workshop with representative from both
teams to discuss compliance strategies
okay conduct a separate workshop for
each team to allow for focused
discussion on adapting their specific
operation for the of the new regulation
facilitate individual strategy session
with each team to outline their approach
followed by a joint session okay
assemble a panel of regulatory experts
to provide guidance and recommendations
to both teams best answer here follow
the mindset on this one the best answer
here is always to bring people
together let them work together your job
as a project manager is to be a
facilitator and collaborate big
collaboration about everybody on a
project that's what a is all about you
never want to just do individual
workshops right let them just figure it
out on their own they have to work
together so especially something like a
regulation I like C D is definitely the
out of the uh you don't want to do that
because the team has to come up with the
ways to Implement that on there so let's
get rid of the facilitate individual
discussions with each team this might
take longer and then any which you're
going to follow up with a joint session
the best thing here to do is just to
bring them together and let them figure
it out together while you be a
facilitator of that meet in
53 the goal on a project is to foster a
culture of cooporation that drives the
teams towards exceptional
performance following a recommendation
from theany comp's founder the project
manager decides to adapt a servant
leadership approach what should the
project manager do to effectively embody
servant leadership so basically the
question is
asking what's what's servant leadership
principles here a Implement a
competitive reward system to incentivize
individual Excellence Drive project
outcome all right direct the team to
refine their strategies continue ously
until they devise an unbeatable plan for
the project execution all
right evaluate the project scrope
meticulously and set clear prioritized
goal to encourage team alignment and
focus all right establish a clear
project goals and nurture a supportive
environment that enables team members to
Excel and contribute to their fullest
potential now you really have to think
about servant leadership here the thing
about this question is that most of
these choices are technically good
there's one of them that's may not be a
good choice but three of them are
technically good choices now you have to
say well which one of those good ones
are servant leadership that's going to
be D here's why so a was the throwout
answer this you're creating a
competitive system a servant leader as a
servant leader you're not making a
competitive system you're supporting the
team you're not trying to make them be
better than each other you want a
generalizing specialist you don't want
team members feels like they have to
outperform the other to get something at
the end that's what a
is B direct the team to refine their
strategies this is not a bad thing but
notice you're directing the team to
refine their strategies until they find
an unbeatable plan your job is to
support the team not direct the team
evaluate the scope and said clear
priority you shouldn't be setting goals
for the team that's what the team does
all right prioritize goals to encourage
team alignment and then you're going
through the scope remember as a servant
leader what you're doing is you're
supporting the team technically the team
is
self-directing on these types of
projects the team is choosing the work
that they want to do remember seron
leadership is using ad out projects and
it's the team that says okay we're going
to do this work from the backlog that
comes from the top you know this is what
we're going to do in this Sprint and
you're just there to support not Direct
54 during the critical phase of a remote
operated environmental research project
a key analyst departs necessitating the
Swift uh simulation hard word to
pronounce of new members who lacks
familiarity with the Project Specific
challenges and objectives the extensive
project documentation exists yet the
Project's complexity might hinder the
rapid comprehension necessary for the
new Project's members task what
proactive measure should a project
manager Implement to ensure new members
effective integration all right this
this you know I didn't write this
question one of my team members didn't
this has a lot of big words in it so I
like this question because it's one of
these questions where you read it and
you're like what are they asking me that
that was my first thing when I read I
was like all these giant words I can I
barely can pronounce most of them what
are they asking me like I had to read
this one twice you will get questions
like this on your exam
uh and the first thing you do before
even looking at the choice you got to
say what are they looking for right what
what is it that they're asking me so a
couple quick things you notice that
there is a new member somebody is
leaving that's the key thing right uh
there's a new member but this person
doesn't have familiarity with this
particular Project Specific challenges
and objectives there is Project
documentation the question is proactive
measures should the project manager
Implement so we got to
remember what could we have done we're
not trying to fix the current problem
it's what could we have done to ensure
that this new integration this new
members was working well all right a
arrange for the new member to Shadow an
experienced team member for Hands-On
learning okay B encourage the new member
to study the doc thoroughly and followed
by a session to discuss their role all
right schedule a series of training
webinars on a projects methodology and
Technologies okay facilitate a workshop
with with the team focusing on projects
comp Ure all current members and new
member attend the question is which one
follows the the mindset which one brings
the team together which one ensures that
this new person is not just doing it by
themsel which one allows them to have
the team there with them well that's
going to be D if you think about it a is
more like go follow that guy you're like
giving away to work we don't want to do
that this one although I like be it's a
decent answer I encourage a new member
to study the document but this is is
more like hey you study that by yourself
you're not there with the person this
one here is more bringing the team
together series of webinars on the
Project's methodologies this is not
something that you could have done and
notice and Technologies this may delay
time the best thing here to do and
especially it's a
webinar uh this person might not be
participating which one drives that
servant leadership with drives that
mindset 55 in a routine progress check
and AD job project manager notice that a
lead analysis is habitu passing off less
complex analyst work to newer team
members claim it allows them to
concentrate on the
more integrate aspects of the project
what should the project manager do a
develop a rotational task assignment
system to ensure all members gain
experience across a range of tasks
directly assigned tasks based on the
complexity to Ure each team member works
with their capability establish a
mentorship program where senior members
guide Junior members to complex
tasks D organize a team discussion
during the next project update meeting
to evaluate the effectiveness of the
current task allegation method now let's
stop right here this was a tough
question it seems like an easy one but
it's not so the team came up with a way
of doing something that they feel is
effective what do you do again the team
is doing this themselves it's a lead
analyst you know it's passing passing
off his work to newer team members the
question is what do you do well here's
what you do first of all you don't stop
it you you don't know how effective this
is you don't this may be a great thing
for the team if you come in and you say
well let's do a rotational
system if you directly if you come in
and you say Hey you have to do it this
way
A and B puts you in charge puts you as
this direct project manager that says
hey this is where I want it done you
guys can't do that that just shuts the
team off you don't want to shut it off
you want to evaluate it you want to see
is this thing effective work with the
team this may be a great thing or it may
be a bad thing let the team work work
together C is also the same as a and b
now you are telling them what to do
remember the team is the Smart Ones I
always told you guys in the course
project manager we're not the Smart Ones
guys we are the collaborators we're the
facilitators this unless you know how to
code and and build buildings you're not
going to be the smart one on a project
we don't want to be the smart one we
want to be the one that collaborate on
the project we want to bring people
together we want people to get
along uh but we are not going to be the
one coding the applications so in this
one let this maybe maybe this is good we
don't know I think it's I think it's a
good
thing 56
as a critical update to an e-commerce
platform nearest completion the project
manager receives a last minute request
from stakeholders for additional
features that would significantly
enhance customer experience but require
extensive extra work from the team
potentially affected the launch timeline
what should the project manager do okay
so we got a e-commerce platform it's
almost finished in somebody wants to add
something what do you do
uh expedite the process by incorporating
the new features into the plan calculate
the additional cost and request an
immediate increase in budget reject the
the request outright maintain and focus
discuss the implementation of request
for development and presents feasible
solutions to the stakeholders follow the
mindset on this this is a pretty easy
question although we call this one extra
hard Ultra hard questions this one is
technically not customer requests
something what you're going to do well
the first thing is what I'm going to
tell you what you should never do is to
never requ never on on your exam if
there is ever a choice about reject
something don't select it if you get
choices that seem negative fire somebody
reject something say no to this stop
something it's probably never the answer
all right so don't reject something all
right because you notice it's
significantly enhanced customer
experience maybe we should add that
in calculate the extra cost and request
I think B is a good answer it's
analyzing the change but remember it's
best to come up and analyze the change
with the team not by yourself expedite
it just don't incorporate things like
that all right without revisiting the
project you need to you need to analyze
it all right you just can't incorporate
like
that 57 in the development phase of an
international Public Health Project a
project manager faces skep iism from
government Partners about the project
duration achievement due to limited
visibility into the project progress H
what action should the project manager
take to address this okay so notice the
problem here
is skepticism from people from folks
partners because they have limited
visibility so you notice I read the
question and I have a good understanding
of what it's asking initiate a monthly
newsletter focusing on project
Milestones challenges okay arrange for a
series of workshop with the project
beneficiaries to directly showcase the
Project's impact organize a virtual
meeting with government Partners discuss
how they would like project updates to
be done and yield any questions okay
compile an extensive report on Project
outcomes and plan activities to be
distributed quarterly this is a very
easy question if you read it carefully
the the main problem here is that the
skepticism is coming from where limit Li
mited
visibility what is the best action
should take should we just determine the
best way the project status should be
visible or should we ask them first what
do you think we're going to do well if
you said hey Andrew you know what let's
meet with them and ask them how they
would like these updates to take place
right project progress then you're
absolutely correct you notice a you're
determining what's best for them B
you're determining what's best for them
D you're determining what's best for
them you know what's best for someone I
don't know maybe you should ask them
that right what's the best update to
your CEO what's the best update to your
regulatory agency how about if you ask
your CEO how about if you ask that
agency that's what C is so remember be
collaborative 58 during the
implementation phase of an Innovative
Mobile Banking application a significant
update from regulatory bodies adjustment
to several key features of the app
requires adjustment notice requires
adjustment the agile project manager
arranges a meeting with the responsible
regulatory officer who is new to the
project to discuss these required
changes for this adop project what
action should the project manager take
to ensure these updates are efficiently
integrated into the scope okay eight I
want you guys to keep in mind ad job
project right because you got to keep in
mind something before we look at these
choices the way this is going to be some
kind of scope change the way you manage
scope on traditional versus agile is
vastly different make sure to review the
course on that all right hey request
that the compliance officer formalize a
regulatory updates and write and submit
them for approval from the Change
Control Board encourage a compliance to
detail regulatory changes for inclusion
in the product backlog instruct the
compliance office and immediately
communicate the changes to the develop
team in the next daily scrum ask
compliant off to assess the plan and
suggest modification to accommodate the
new regulation best answer here is going
to be correct B I think this one was
very difficult but you have to
understand how changes to Agile project
Scopes are done we know we have to
include this because it's required for
it to be done and in order for work to
get done on an agile project where must
the work be it must be in the product
backlog and you notice that in in a
they're going through a change control
board there's no really change control
board on an aob project a was the Thro
answer notice you don't communicate
scope changes during the daily scrum the
daily scrum is basically just to answer
three question what you did yesterday
what you're going to do today what
impediments you have not to come in and
introduce new task and all that first of
all that's something that should have
the the real good answer here would have
been for the compliance officer to meet
with a product owner to include into the
product backlog and to be prioritized
that would have been the best answer and
that the best thing closest to that is
B the compliance officer shouldn't be
assessing the current plan is this
person a project manager do they have a
lot of experience probably not best
answer B
59 guys are you enjoying this session
did I teach you a lot did you learn a
lot if you did can you please click on
that like button subscribe to the
channel to learn more of pass all your
certification exams let's get back to
this 59 a project manager noticed that
the integration process is more
cumbersome than anticipated
significantly slowing down the project
progress this issue is primarily due to
a newly implement it protocol that was
designed to enhance security what should
you do next all right introduce
additional training session for the team
on the new it protocol okay require the
team to double their efforts to meet the
deadline despite the
protocol okay organize a workshop to
identify workarounds to the it protocol
that does not compromise security all
right initiate discussion with it
leadership and the team to understand
the protocol implementation how best to
facilitate the project okay notice it
says what you're going to do next now
once again I want to mention don't do
anything don't uh do anything that's
negative and one of the ne things you
can do that's negative is overworking
people if they're going to double their
efforts what are you going to do make
them work 16 hours a day so that one
there we can get rid of that was a
throut answer follow the mindset bring
people together is there a way for the
team to implement this protocol
correctly um is there a way that it can
accommodate the we don't know that yet
the best thing here to do the next thing
you should be doing is meet with
everyone talk with everyone be
collaborative in this situation that's
what D is maybe then you may want to do
c so I would do D that's number one
maybe then we could do c some people C
was also a good choice it does say it
does not compromise security but you
shouldn't go and around their protocols
until you really understand what this is
about additional training sessions you
know what I may I'm going to do D then I
may do c then a or I may do D then a
then C but notice the comes first so you
got to keep in mind anytime you see that
word next you're saying what comes first
now I want you guys to keep in mind
anytime you see the word NEX or what do
you do first basically you're going to
put some of these choices in order what
the exam is asking you in this type of
question is hey what do you do next what
do you do first well the the choices are
going to be things you will be doing but
then you have to say to yourself okay
which one do we do first then second
then third that's really what it is like
put them in order and then give me the
first one that's really what this
question
is last question as a project manager
for an app develop development project
you are approached by a stakeholder with
a request to add feature that mirors the
functionality of something develop in a
previous Sprint the stako is looking for
a quick estimation on how this addition
might affect schedule and cost all right
so we want a quick estimate here what
steps should you take to accurately
provide this all right calculate the new
feature impact by comparing it with the
total budget and adjus in based on the
proportion of work already
completed that seem quick but you might
be able meet with the product owner to
help you with the estimate schedule
review the agile user stories and
velocity metrics from previous Sprint
related to similar feature to estimate
the effort required for the new addition
okay initiate a detail risk analys
incorporate a new feature focus on
potential schedule overuns and budget
now this one here I'll tell you guys
something about questions like this when
you get a question like this all four of
the choices are basically wrong you know
the the best answer in this question
if somebody comes to you and says how
long would this take how much would it
cost ask the team the team is but that's
not the choice you see on this exam it's
not just about choosing the correct
answer it's the best of the four this is
a question where well what is the best
of these four yeah they all kind of suck
but you know what I got to choose one
right that's the the least of the
suckiest answer if that makes sense so
that's why I like this question in here
and of course the answer is going to be
C that is correct because you know why
when you are estimating how long some
something should take or how what it may
cost the team does it by utilizing how
fast the velocity metrics how fast they
can do work and what the work is so if
the work is similar to previous stories
then use the metrics they use that is
the best answer this would take too long
a you never use a product or to help you
with estimation that's something you and
your team does d would take too long
because it's a risk analysis so C may
not be the correct answer the best best
answer but it's the best of those four
all right let's go question 61 during a
complex software development project the
project manager notices a
significant significant variances
between the plan and actual performance
metrics the key deliverables are at risk
of being delayed due to these
discrepancies what should the project
manager do first to ensure the Project's
objectives are being met a adjust the
timeline and communicate the changes to
all
stakeholders conduct a detailed analysis
of the performance data to identify root
causes request additional resources to
accelerate Project work and meet
scheduled targets reassess the project
management strategies to better align
with current
challenges okay now I want you guys to
notice in this question that you have
some kind of a problem and if you notice
the problem is what you notice that
there's variances between the plan and
the actual work that's going on so when
you have a problem on a project what
should you do first I mean that's what
the question here is asking and I want
you guys to remember something don't
take actions first assess review
evaluate analyze and that brings the
answer to B yes because when there's a
problem on a project the first thing the
project manager does is not to just
adjust the schedule without
understanding what that problem is it is
not to hire additional resources if they
don't know what that problem is notice
they're looking at the risk management
strategies it's already happened it's
not really at risk yet uh the best thing
here to do is to add do a detail
analysis of the actual data and and
notice this is the risk management
strategies not the risk strategies not
the risk responses if you're thinking
that these are the management Str how
you plan to manage risk it's definitely
not that one B is the best answer follow
the mindset on this one
question 62 in a large infrastructure
project the project manager is faced
with the challenge of sudden regulatory
changes that could potentially impact
the scope and cost the project is
currently on track but these changes
might
require adjustment in project exec ution
what should you do first so once again
you have that first thing update the
budget and timeline okay initiate a
stakeholder meeting to discuss the
impacts and adjustments conduct a
comprehensive review implement the
regulatory changes this question is very
similar to what we had before now you
notice it says here sudden regulatory
changes and it says could potentially
impact so this is it may impact the
project or may not best answer here is
just like in the first question we just
did is going to be to analyze this
review analyze this change how is it
going to affect the project in what
areas of the project how much is it
going to add or even remove from the
scope how much is it going to add or
remove from the budget and if the scope
and budget is being affected maybe so is
the schedule so you just don't want to
just go and update without preliminary
assessment get a good assessment you
should never just go update your project
but just preliminary
assessment you don't want to meet before
you meet with the stakeholders you need
to analyze this regulation
yourself never Implement like this D was
the Trad answer if you're selected D you
got to do some study you got to review
the mindset section in the course
anytime you see a question that says
first what should you do first it's
probably not to fix the problem it's
probably not to implement what
somebody's asking for it's more than
likely to analyze ize what they're
asking
for
63 a project manager is overseeing the
construction of a new office building
the project is running over budget due
to high cost of materials the project
team suggests several options to cut
cost including using less materials that
may slightly reduce
durability simplifying the build-in
design or eliminate some non-essential
features
which approach should the project
manager use to address costs want sure
the building meets its intended purpose
now this is a definition question you're
not really going to get the mindset here
but you got to understand the
definition is it earn value uh is it a
value engineering is it critical path is
it earn value or is it Monte Carlo best
answer here is going to be value
engineering what is value
engineering value engineer is something
we do all the time time value
engineering is if I tell you guys that I
want you guys to go out and buy a new
car and you're like okay I I'll buy that
new car but what you're going to do is
if I tell you what type of car you
should get get a Toyota Camry that's a
white one that's a 2024 you know the
scope your objective is to get that
thing as cheap as possible that's value
engineering value engineering is about
how can we deliver what the customer
wants in the cheapest is or the most
cost effective way which is basically
what this is describing critical path
method this is just formulas that's not
what they're asking this is uh tracking
the statistics of how much money you're
spending versus how much you should have
spent this is earn value I'm sorry
critical path method is actually your
schedule see I miss was I looked at
critical path method and and said earn
value SN value is all the formulas
you're going to be using in order to
track your budget and see how far how
far you're on or off your budget
critical path method allows you to build
an entire schedule that tells you your
critical path on a schedule and the
Monti Carlo is about different
simulations the Monti Carlo simulations
is trying hundreds or thousands of
different simulations to come up with a
budget schedule or even determine
risks all right a is the best answer now
I do have a few more questions on value
engineer I just put that in there
they're going to be used mostly as a
term here we go question
64 during a project Charter review
session a dispute arises between the
sponsor and the product owner witnessed
by the team and other uh stakeholders in
this situation what should the project
manager do to manage a conflict and
continue the project propose a follow-up
session to address unresolved issues
after the meeting okay facilitate the
meeting actively using conflict
resolution strategies to manage the
dispute and maintain team
cohesion adjourn the meeting immediately
suggest a cool and off
period arrange a separate conflict
resolution session with a neutral
facilitator to assist parties now your
exam wants you to take a direct approach
want you to fix that problem right away
so what are you going to do right you
want to take a confronting approach so
the best one here that's a confront and
approach is going to be B that's right
you want to facilitate this meeting
actively you're going to have in every
meeting you're going to have conflict
it's just the nature of the game it's
how humans work so what you got to do is
you got to take an active approach
conflict is not bad conflict is a good
thing always remember that I told you
that a 100 times in the course conflict
is good managed conflict is good
unmanaged conflict that can lead to a
World War where people may physically
hurt each other it's probably not a good
idea never let it get there so B best
answer question 65 a project manager's
task would organize in risk for a new
infrastructure project to ensure
comprehensive risk management the
project manager decides to use a risk
breakdown structure however the team is
consider the RBS may become overly
complex and difficult to manage what
should the project manager to create an
effective and manageable RBS develop a
simple categorization scheme that only
includes high priority risk okay use an
existing RBS from a similar project and
adapt it to the current project needs
all
right create a detailed RBS with
multiple subcategories to capture all
potential risks all right involve key
stakeholders in development of the RBS
to ensure it's comprehensive and
manageable this is a good question and
it's a tough question so first of all
you have to remember what an RBS is an
RBS is done to do what an RBS actually
doesn't have risk in it that's in the
risk register what does the RBS do the
RBS is there to categorize risks
okay now you notice a if you set a
develop a simple categorization scheme
that's fine it only includes High prior
it doesn't really have risk in it it's a
way to categorize the risk you're going
to use those categories in your risk
register uh and only includes high level
risks high high priority risk no it's
not only for that use an existing RBS
template to adapt it to the current I
like this idea but every project is
unique it's best to get people involved
the more people involved in telling you
to risk for your project the more likely
you're going to be successful at it a
detail with multiple subcategories to
capture all potential risk although this
may be a good one the best thing here is
to get more people involved on your
project
remember the more people involved the
more key stakeholders this could be team
members for for example subject matter
experts or whoever they'll tell you
better of how to develop that particular
thing question
66 in a construction project the project
manager decides to implement value value
engineering to enhance the Project's
value the goal is to improve the radio
the ratio of function to cost by
analyzing and proposing cost effective
Solutions what should the project
manager do first have the team conduct a
brain sermon session to remove functions
for cost reduction all right Focus
solely on reducing cost even if it means
compromise and a functionality engage
with stakeholder to understand the
critical
functions Implement all proposed changes
immediately to maximize cost now this
one here it does say value engineering
but it's really a mindset question you
notice once again it's this first like
what are we going to do first value
engineering is about how we make things
cheaper it's how we make things more
cost effective while delivering the same
amount of function
so one of the things we never want to do
is to remove functions just to reduce
cost it's about keeping the functions
the same so I'm going to eliminate this
right off the bat that should have been
one of the throwout answers and
Implement all proposed
changes uh we're going to get rid of
that because you just don't Implement
all the changes uh that's probably not
going to maximize function the best
answer here by the way is going to be C
engage with stakeholders you want to
understand what the functions are notice
before you start to optimize the project
before you start
to maybe reduce some functions maybe
find alternative to those functions
something a little cheaper that gives
them the same function understand what
the functions are never compromise on
functionality best answer to there guys
was
C
67 a project manager is conducting a
value engineering Workshop to identify
ways to improve a Project's value during
the session a team member just replacing
a component with a cheaper alternative
that slightly reduces performance but
saves a significant amount of money what
are the project manager do to determine
if this solutions aligns with value
engineer approv the change as it reduces
overall project
value uh project cost reject the change
as it reduces performance evaluate the
reduction and reduction and performance
impacts the project functionality
implement the change if it does not
require additional stakeholder approval
same thing here use the mindset
somebody's asking you for a change what
are you going to be doing the best thing
here guys is of course to evaluate that
change never approve reject or implement
the change just without evaluating the
change that's part of being a project
manager 68 a project manager is working
on a large infrastructure project that
is facing scheduled delays the project
manager wants to use advanc forecast and
technique to predict the future status
and progress of the
project the project team has been use an
evm to track progress what should the
project manager do to forecast the
project completion data accurately so
this one here is you notice they're
using
evm and they're want they they want to
use Advanced technique now this of
course is going to be with evm so what
are you going to do well apply the SPI
to the remaining work and calculate an
AC okay conduct a Monte Carlo simulation
to account for potential variations in
the schedule all right use CPM to
reevaluate the timeline Implement
rolling wave planning to adjust future
work plans best answer here guys is
going to be now this by the way is
really definition if you really
understood what evm means earn value
management then you know some of the
formulas included the SPI the schedule
performance index you can actually take
and use the schedule performance index
with the EAC to to forecast a schedule
making this the best answer Monte Carlo
simulations looks at things multiple
simulations that can affect the schedule
helps to build the schedule more than
predict the
schedule this is to build the timeline
your critical path method helps you to
develop a schedule not necessarily to
predict it Rolland wave planning is just
planning to replan here this is not
related really to it doesn't really have
much to do with evm because this is
planning and evm isn't
executed 69 a software development
project is Midway through its timeline
and the project manager notices that the
actual progress is lacking behind the
schedule the plan
schedule the sponsor is concerned about
meeting the upcoming Milestone what
technique should the project manager use
to address the sponsor's concern about
uh sponsors concern and predict the
project completion date create a trend
analysis using historical performance
data okay apply evm to calculate the
time variance use a three-point
estimation to forecast future tasks
perform a resource level analysis to
optimize resource allocation this one is
really a definition question also notice
notice is the project is lacking behind
the schedule you're concerned about
meeting it what technique basically
you're going to use and predict the
Project's completion date which one you
have which one is going to help us do
that the best answer is going to be evm
correct it's similar to this question
that we had
here evm the EAC in particular the
estimate at completion is a Formula that
can predict budget and it can also
predict schedule Trend analysis using
historical information while this is
good evm will be more accurate because
it's not just based on historical it's
based on what's happening right now uh
threo estimation it tells you the door
duration of something it doesn't really
predict anything resource leveling I'm
not sure how that predicts anything
resource leveling ensures no one really
works over
time question 70 a construction project
is experienced significant delays due to
many unforeseen weather conditions
causing concerns about meeting the final
deadline the project manager needs to
predict the potential impact on the
project completion dates and communicate
this what approach should you take
update the Gan chart with the new
weather delay information and manually
adjust the timeline all right use a
Monte Carlo anal simulation to predict
the probability of various completion
dates all right apply CPM analysis to
identify which activities can be
fast-tracked okay perform a cost benefit
analysis to decide whether to hire
additional resources to mitigate the
delays now the best answer here is going
to be a Monti card simulation now I want
to point out
something get notice
many unforeseen conditions this means
many simulations if you're looking for
something that goes through many many
different simulations or quote unquote
scenarios that's the definition of a
Monte Carlo again chared is used to make
the actual schedule CPM is used to make
the um the the schedule it's not going
to be used to to predict or to give you
the results of multiple scenarios or
simulations
cost benefit analysis not yet this is
still this here is right now they have
to figure out how they're going to
manage that weather conditions then they
can determine if they want to hire more
resources so if you're doing this the
best answer is the Monty Carlo
simulation let's get started project
manager is preparing for a quality audit
of a new software development project
the audit team needs to ensure the
Project's quality management system
aligns with the organizational standards
and identify areas for improvement what
is the most cost- effective course of
action for the project manager to take
after the quality audit so after the
audit's
done provide the team with all documents
and requests through a review okay
prepare the team to answer any questions
from the audit collaborate with the team
to understand their findings and develop
corrective actions focus on uh
presenting the success of the project to
highlight the team's performance now you
have to read this question carefully to
ensure it's says after the audit best
answer here is going to be C first of
all providing the team with all project
documents is something you probably do
during the audit preparing the team to
answer any question is something you
should do before the
audit collaborate with the team and
understand that their findings yes this
is something you're going to do after
the audit focus on presenting the
success uh of the project to highlight
the teams perform this is something you
can probably do after after the project
is done um not during the audit so read
this one carefully if you didn't get it
correct 72 during the execution phase of
a manufacturing project an internal
audit team reveal several
non-conformances in the production
process the audit team has identified
these issues as potential risk to the
success what should the project manager
do to these
non-confirmed immediately the production
process until all confirmes are resolved
okay develop and Implement corrective
actions to address these confirmes
identified by the
team okay dismiss the non-conformist
minor issues and continue okay informed
the sponsor by these confirmed request
additional resources now this here is
not asking you what to do first this is
telling you to solve the problem if you
get that part of not is not what should
you do next or what should you do first
it's literally asking you how are you
going to fix this there's a couple
things you shouldn't be doing best
answer here is going to be to fix the
problem right develop and come up with
corrective actions to fix these
non-confirmed project like that
especially for something that is going
to
be as potential
risks right you want to evaluate it you
want to come up with responses to it
just don't halt a project like that the
only time you may halt a project is is
when safety issues for example somebody
might die or get injured you're breaking
some kind of law those are reasons to
Halt a project but not here this is not
what this is never dismiss never kick
the can down the road or just never do
nothing that's what this is that means
you're just going to continue doing what
you're doing and ignore them never
ignore anyone never go to your sponsor
for help your sponsor shouldn't be the
one that's helping you solve problems
they hired you to solve the problem not
them 70
three in the middle of a large
infrastructure project the project
manager receives an
external uh quality auditor highlighting
several significant non-confirming these
issues if not addressed could impact the
timeline of budget what should you do to
address these non-confirmed
effectively continue the plan and
monitor these non-confirmed escalate all
right request sponsor to review the
auditor report all right adjust the
scope to account for identified
non-confirmed integrate the recommend
corrective actions from the audit
reports into the plan all right what is
the best answer now this question when
we wrote it we notice it's not all of
these are going to be great choices but
you got to choose the best of the four
what did you guys
get some of these didn't make sense at
all for example don't do nothing
continue with the current plan and
monitor this is literally doing nothing
request is never go to your sponsor
right never go to the sponsor the only
time you go to your sponsor is for an
approval or disapproval you shouldn't go
to your sponsor for guidance on how to
manage a project remember they hired you
for that not them never adjust the scope
like that the scope is probably going to
require some kind of uh change request
if it's a traditional or only the
product owner can add to the product
backlog if you're changing agile scope
definitely not that integrate these yes
you
notice uh you re receive a report that
highlight non-confirmed these are not
address good impact the best answer here
is D of these four now I want I left
this like this because I want you guys
to point out I want to point out
something critical this isn't a test of
choose the correct answer it's choose
the best of the four now I'm going to
tell you I don't like d d kind of suck
yeah but it's the least of the suckiest
answer remember it's a game of four
choices it's a game
of what is the best of the
four none of them have to be correct
it's just that one has to be more
correct than the other three one has to
be the least of the suckiest answer if
you know what I mean the other three a b
and c you would probably never do but
you're probably saying hey Andrew it
doesn't say in the question that it
doesn't include the corrective actions
in a report you're absolutely right but
that's still D is still better than ab
and C if you know what I mean question
74 project manager is preparing to over
oversee the development of a new mobile
application during a stakeholder meeting
a senior executive expresses concern
that the project may not align with the
Strategic goals of the organization the
project manager needs to address this
concern to ensure continued support and
Alignment what should you do next
reassure the executive that the team is
capable of delivering the project on
time and within budget review the
project alignment with the Strategic
goals conduct a schedule a follow-up
meeting with the executive to discuss
project benefits in more detail per
conduct a performance review of the
project team to identify any areas for
improvement now let's take a look at
this you notice this stakeholder is
saying hey this project is not aligned
with our goals so what should you do
next well here's what you do next maybe
you should analyze to see if it is
aligned with the Strategic goal before
taking any
action a is something you don't want to
do this is your saying yes it is it's
already aine don't worry about it this
is doing nothing never do nothing
schedule a follow-up meeting you know
what I would probably do B then I would
do c understand does it really meet it
maybe it's something you should review
and notice your preparing it's like
you're in the beginning of this thing
conduct the performance review of the
team you haven't really basically
started this project yet so I'm not sure
why you're doing that that best answer
is
B 75 a project manager is working on a
government infrastructure project that
requires strict compliance with company
standards during a routine review the
project manager discovers that some
activities may may not meet the required
standards what should you
do halt all activities until a full
compliance review is conducted okay
update the project plan to include
additional quality checks all right
notify regulatory t with non-compliance
activities conduct the root CA to
identify the reasons for non-compliance
and Implement corrective actions if
you've been following along this video
this one should be pretty easy you
notice that first of all it's not that
the project is not meeting the
compliance it's not like it's 100% doing
that it does say me so watch the key
words and that brings the answer to
identif before you if it wasn't needing
the compliance and you're doing
something against the law I would have
probably said maybe is best but you
should never work against the law by the
way if a project is doing something and
it's against the law people may get hurt
or somebody might go to jail you should
probably stop it but if something might
be happening just don't pull the project
like that analyze it to see what's going
on and then if you find it maybe then
you do that update the plan not yet
analyze it to see what the corrective
actions are don't go notify of potential
non-compliance if you go to the
regulator ERS and you said hey there's
some potential things they're going to
say can you make sure before you let us
know 76 during the construction of a new
building the project manager lawence
that unforeseen geological issues will
significantly increase the cost beyond
the budget what should you do next
adjust the timeline to reduce labor cost
okay consult with a geological
technician for remote cost effective
solution implement the phase
Construction analyze the situation
consider all possible follow the mindset
on this one this one does have two good
answers the best answer here is to
analyze the situation hey use the
mindset on this one never adjust a
timeline like that probably requires a
change request Implement a phase
approach I'm not sure how that's going
to save money uh consult with a G Alo I
think D and B were good answers it's
just that this here is a more
incompressible answer it has more it it
it pulls more into it then B
does
77 as a project manager overseeing the
roll out of a new it systems it's
discovered halfway through the fiscal
year that several critical software
enhancement funded by this year budget
will not be completed on
schedule these enhancements were
initiated based on midyear changes and
are critical for the success what you
you do first initiate a review of the
scope to identify areas for schedule
acceleration okay
collaborative team to assess the project
deliverable and focus on critical
enhancements okay Engage The spons with
sponsor to adjust expectations and
secure support for external timelines
communicate the progress and adjust the
timelines for these enhancements to the
finance department now this one has two
good answers also best answer here don't
forget what are you going to do first
best answer here is going to be work
with your team now initiate a review of
the scope to identify areas for schedule
acceleration that's not something you're
going to be able to do by yourself the
team is going to have to help you do
that engage adjust their expectations
although that sounds okay this is the
second best answer that sounds okay and
secure supporting of the extended
deadlines that may not be okay to them
they don't want it to be
extended you don't want to just work
with the finance department you got to
work with your customers on this making
this the best answer who is the best
people to tell you how to implement a
change the team who's the best people to
tell you how to fix something the team
who's the best person to give you
problems to your solution the team they
can be the best
answer 78 in the midst of a major
software development project the project
manager is preparing for an upcoming
executive in-depth review the project
manager must present how the Project's
progress is being tracked and measured
to the executive team who are Keen to
understand how effectively the project
is being
managed so they want to know how it's
being tracked and
measured what should the project manager
focus on in their presentation uh focus
on in their presentation for the
Executive review provide a detailed rep
report on team productivity and
individual
contributions compile Eva metrics
including the SV CV for comprehensive
review Jing discussed the implementation
of the new project manager
tool and its impact on Project
efficiency outline the risk encountered
so far in the mitigation strategies this
one I thought was pretty straightforward
if you know evm if you know what SV and
CV stood for it was a pretty easy
question because if you
notice EV or evm allows you to measure
the performance of your project if you
notice these questions you really don't
need to know the formulas but you need
to understand what they are
productivity and individual contribution
wouldn't tell you how to how the project
is being measured measured generally
means you're measuring time and cost is
generally what you measure the
most uh I'm not sure what this
implementation tool is going to help us
measure and track so is risk the best
thing here what do we measure on a
project guys time and
money 79 leading a new uh new agile
Global Environmental Conservation
project the project manager overseas a
diverse team distributed across several
continents recognizing the dver the
diverse cultural cultural backgrounds
within the team the project manager aims
to Foster unity and effective
collaboration what is the most effective
action for the project manager to
enhance team
integration organized a series of cross
functional training for all teams to
educate them about cultural differences
okay set up a digital collaboration
space for team remember to share
personal and professional updates all
right our in monthly face Toof face
Retreats all right engage uh encourage
open communication and demonstrate
confident team ability and their
contributions two good answers on this
one right I know you're stuck between
two I didn't make this question my team
member did and I was kind of stuck
between two myself what two were you
stuck between was it A and D because
that's what I was all right I'm going to
eliminate the bad ones okay this is a
monthly face to face is probably not um
doable it is not a project where you
just have a few it notice it's a global
conservation project and it's team
distributed across the globe maybe not
feasible a digital collaboration space
is not just for people to share this is
given a way to work to
them I liked a series of crosss for all
teamers educate them about cultural
differences you could do that or you can
encourage open communication and let the
team work together you know if you're
the key the key here if you're
wondering why is it a because there's a
key word in the question agile remember
something on an agile project you're a
servant leader the team is a
self-directing
self-managing team and what you need to
do sometimes as a servant leader you
need to step back and let the
team figure out ways you don't want it
to get out of hands maybe if it gets out
of hand maybe then you would do a but
them have confidence in the team ability
to keep on progressing and encourage
that open line of communication that
would be best versus you coming up with
a solution see the difference in this in
D you're letting the team figure it out
complete solution and a you're giving
them the solution trick question by the
way 80 at the onset of a healthcare
software upgrade project the client
emphasizes that the the the enhancements
are critical to improving patient care
and operational efficiency potentially
affecting the healthcare providers
reputation and financial performance the
client is eager to
see improvements implemented in the
shortest time
frame what should the project manager do
utilize agile methodologies to ensure
rapid delivery of high priority features
all right Implement a waterfall method
to automate testing okay establish a
dedicated time task force focus on
critical system upgrades first all
right conduct a series of stakeholder
Workshop to prioritize software
enhancement based on impact the best
answer here guys uh notice this project
has just
started and it's a software development
project this project is riped ripe for
agile why because you notice um there
are things that they want first they
want to see the Improvement implemented
the good thing about agile especially SC
prom is that you get the most important
features first waterfall is not going to
be something that's going to be done in
the shortest time frame that takes the
longest a dedicated task focus on
critical the the only person that can
tell you the critical is the customers
themselves product owner conduct a
series of state to prioritize software
based this is going to be done by the
product owner making a the best answer
practice question
81 in the middle of an urban Pro
development project the project manager
faces a setback as a key engineer and an
urban planner announced their immin
imminent departure from the team the
project is already on a strict timeline
with critical mindset with critical
Milestones approaching the remaining
team members are concerned about the
increased workload and the potential
impact on the project schedule what
should the project manager
do increase the workload on incre on
team members to cover the task of The
Departed
individuals out Outsource specific
critical tasks to specialize firm to
keep the project on schedule work with
the remaining team members to recruit
new members to complete the workload and
apply for a project timeline extension
due to unforeseen staff and challenges
now in this particular
question which is something that you're
going to see common on your exam is that
somebody
left some team members left what do you
do well there's a couple things you
don't do and there's a couple things you
should be doing for example one of the
things here that we shouldn't be doing
ever on any test question is never work
people over over time never overwork
anyone part of the mindset tells us that
when you are managing a team never
overwork them in any scenario now in
real life it may be acceptable but for
your exam if that choice seems you're
reading it you're like Hey we're going
to be working this guy overtime we're
going to be overworking the employees
never an answer get rid of
that
Outsourcing not something you can do
right away all right although they may
solve the problem it's not something you
can do right away you have to go to a
whole procurement
process apply for this is going to
require some form of a change request
you just can't apply for that the best
thing here you can do is to work with
the mindset and make sure that you
involve your team members to help you
remember let the team help you let the
team figure things out not just you
figuring it out and in this scenario the
best choice here is to work with the
team to help them Recruit new members in
other words you're bringing you're
making them involv you're bringing them
on the project or I should say on the
issue 82
a firm planed to transition from lean a
transition to planed to transition to
lean development techniques the project
manager encounters resistance from
several worldwide uh stakeholders weary
of the new processes the project manager
needs to build confidence in lean
methodologies amongst the stakeholders
what uh what should the project manager
propose schedule meetings with the
stakeholder to address concerns all
right introduce a reward systems for
early adapters of lean techniques okay
adapt the lean development uh accept
that accept that lean development will
not work in all companies organize a
companywide seminar the history and
principles of lean now this one here
although I said this was Ultra hard this
one should be pretty easy couple things
here that you don't want to do is if you
ever read a question and it seems that
one of the choices is to do nothing it's
not the end answer never do nothing all
right always remember that so in that
one I'm going to eliminate C right off
the bat right off the bat and the reason
is
because in this one you're just saying
okay I guess lean development doesn't
work and you just move on if the choice
is to do nothing that's not the answer
introduce your reward systems for early
adap well they already don't want it but
you putting that in place they already
don't want it so you telling people
there going to be some kind of reward
you have to figure out what their
concern is a company wi this is the
history and principles of the it's not
addressing their concern the best thing
here you can do is to meet with them see
what what exactly like they don't like
and then you can explain the benefits to
them making death the best
answer 83 leading a significant
initiative to overhaul a corporation's
it infrastructure the project manager
has already navigated through several
phases success y with the CTO overseeing
the initiatives departs unexpectedly oh
when the CTO departs unexpectedly okay
so a major person is
leaving the incoming CTO then pauses the
initiative pinned in a comprehens review
of the project alignment with the
company's revised technological
Direction what is the most effective
first step for the project manager so
basically what should you do first so in
this question we have a key stakeholder
is leaving new stakeholder or should say
left new stakeholder comes in basically
what you the first arrange a meeting
with the new CTO to outline the project
benefits and strategic alignment prepare
a detailed report comparing the current
project status with industry standards
and
Trends initiate a project audit to
demonstrate compliance with best
practices and regulatory
requirements develop a contingency plan
addressing political uh potential
changes requested by the new
CTO okay let me say this first common
question on the exam you're going to
find somebody left a major stakeholders
left what do you do well there's a
couple things you don't do like just
don't change anything around the best
thing here to do when somebody leaves
and somebody new comes in is to meet
with that person understand what that
person is explain understand what that
person wants explain what this project
is about this is definitely the best
answer prepare a detail report compared
you probably want to do this after you
meet with the
person uh initiate a project audit to
demonstrate compliance not yet meet with
this person let outline what the
Project's benefits are outline remember
this person is saying well is this
project align yes what you want to do is
you want want to go and meet with the
person and show them before doing this
so I would do a maybe then B then C
develop a contingency plan addressing
polit uh potential Changers request not
yet meet with the person first now I
want to point out something about this
question you see those three choices are
not
incorrect but they're asking what to do
first maybe at some point we are going
to develop a contingency plan to address
potential changes maybe at some point
we're going to audit it maybe at some
point we're going to prepare detail uh
report showing how a detailed report
comparing the status of Industry
standards maybe we're going to do those
things but the first thing you want to
do is to meet with them discuss see what
this person is about see what exactly
they're looking for making a the best
answer
84 in the midst of estimated task for a
major upgrade to an ex an application a
project manager finds that the
development team has different views on
the effort required for a particularly
challenging
feature what should the project manager
do to synchronize these variant
estimates okay simple question you have
team members with different views on
what an estimate should be what do you
do suggest implementing a quick
prototype to better gauge the necessary
effort allow the team additional time to
research and independently reassess
their
estimates okay request each team member
to detail their estimation process and
Foster a group
consensus all right assign the task
estimation to the most experienced
developer to set a
standard okay let's see the best answer
here you got two you got team members
can't agree on an estimate what do we do
best answer here is to bring
together so in this one here let them
detail their estimation
process together we want to and Foster
group consensus maybe they don't
understand how they're coming up with
their estimates maybe Bob doesn't
understand how Tom is getting his
estimat maybe Jane doesn't understand
how Bob is doing his estimates either
this would be the best answer
here now suggest a quick
prototype I'm not sure if I think a
prototype is going a little far before
we do that the best thing here is to
bring let the team work
together allow the team additional time
to research and independently the best
thing here be we don't want them to do
it independently we want them to do it
together Foster group consensus let the
team work together C is definitely
better than b assign the task
exclamation to the most experienced
never give away to work just don't say
okay you do it all and let the team in
this way this is kind of like a
forcein conflict solution in this one
you're saying okay you do it all and the
rest of you guys just depend on that
person in other words you're eliminating
the rest of the
team
85 during the roll out of a new
e-commerce platform an agile project
manager observes a trend of customers
gravitating towards a competitor site
which recently introduced a high highly
user friendly checkout process what is
the first action the project manag ERS
should do engag in a detailed discussion
with the product owner about any recent
customer feedback or shifts in Market
Trend intensify the development effort
on uh refining the existing features to
make them more competitive all right
pause the introduction additional
features to prioritize a complete
overhaul add a new userfriendly checkout
process this one here work with the
mindset all right if you are working on
a project especially as the question
points out an agile project and you see
something that should be added to the
application what do you do well go to
the product owner work with the product
owner let them know about customer
feedback you know um saying that hey
there some checkout maybe the product
owner already knows and only the product
owner can put it into the product
backlog you should never add something
to an ad job project unless you're the
product
owner never just pause either never stop
a project just like that unless you're
going to kill someone unless you're
breaking the law unless it's against a
regulation intensify uh the development
efforts and refining the existing
feature to make it more competitive
that's not something you can do that
goes back to the product order once
again 86 in the process of initiating an
Advanced Analytical platform to enhance
datadriven decision- making across its
various functions an organization is
integrating a solution that is new to
its technological
landscape what should the project
manager
emphasize evaluation of the platform's
capability with Legacy Data Systems and
user adaptability
okay precise needs analysis within the
key business sectors to Ure the platform
meet specific objectives okay broad
consultation on future proofing the
platform against evolving data
analytical analysis Technologies all
right streamlining cross functional
workflows to minimize disruption during
the platform now this
question uh my team made it and the
Worden is complex like I read it I had
to read it two times to see what it was
if you read
it carefully it's actually pretty easy
all right I found this question after
reading it three times I'm like ah
obviously that's the answer but the word
in the big word in it just gets you just
got to read it a few times you maybe you
did that too but let me show you the
answer and I'll show you why it's an
easy question so first of all it's in
initiating the project is is getting
started what is something you're going
to emphasize and initiate it's
collecting those requirements it's
making sure that the project meets its
objectiv making sure that the scope is
actually something that should get done
in this industry remember in the process
of initiating you're proving you're
doing the business case that's one of
the inputs to the project Charter so
that's what this is
notice this one here precise needs
analysis this is important what you're
doing with precise needs analysis is you
are making sure that hey this project
will meet the sector that it's been
built for now here's where the other
ones are
wrong streamlining cross functional
workflows I like that but I'm going to
put an x on it for a reason broadcast
future proofing I like that I'm going to
put an x on it evaluation of the
platform I like that but I'm going to
put an x on it all of these are good to
do during initiating but B actually
includes AC C and D when you're
basically doing B you're basically doing
everything else one of the things you
want to do on this exam is if you come
to a question
and it looks like the answers are very
specific very very specific and you you
can't determine that a c and d are
specific to that platform or analytical
thing that they're doing go with a
broader answer remember a broad a broad
question should get a broad answer a
specific question gets a specific
answer 87 during the second Sprint of a
software development project it's
observed that one team member frequently
dictates scrum meetings leading to
diminish input from other team members
and hinder progress on task the Team
memb Dynamics are affected and there's a
growing concern over the Project's
collaborative environment what should
you do Implement Anonymous feedback
system to collect opinions okay reassign
the dominating team member to task that
requires less collaboration all right
shift to written daily updates to reduce
the opportunity for any single person to
dominate
discussions okay arrange a private
conversation with the dominating team
member to discuss their uh conduct's
impact on the Team Dynamics all right
this here it's a complex one if you
don't know the mindset if you do it's
not that difficult expect a question on
the exam
like this where you're going to get
somebody is doing something bad on a
project generally it's an individual
problem and when there's an individual
problem on a project your best thing to
do is to deal with that individual
individually couple things you shouldn't
do don't fire them don't remove them the
reason is because this person may not
know they may feel like they're doing
something great listen I've been in
meetings when I Domin ated it to him and
I thought I was really helping them and
then the boss came to me later and says
Andrew don't ever do that again because
you were making people upset you weren't
giving people the time to talk and I
didn't realize it because I was I was
excited you know you get excited you
really want to put out your opinion
there uh so meet with that person the
person may not be a bad person they just
may not realize that so let's meet with
them one
one we are we don't need the feedback
you can already see it so that's not
going to help shift to written don't
move away don't anytime you have an
issue don't go around the issue in this
one you're just saying okay so what are
you going to do never have meetings
again don't go around the issue go
straight to the issue solve the issue
remember this on your exam does this
Choice hit the issue or is it going
around the issue and see we're going
around that issue
by the way if you're enjoying this video
and you're learning a lot give the video
a like subscribe to the channel for more
content just like this I know it I hate
asking all the time but it just helps us
out a lot YouTube does not prioritize
our video if if you guys don't click
that like button so please click that
like
button during a critical phase of a
technology implementation project
extensive and unforeseen changes to the
scope have led
to significant delays all right these
potential changes alterations were
flagged in the initial risk assessment
okay concerned about the uh impli
implications of the Project's
progress the team proposes request an
extension from stakeholders all right
reasonable to ask what should you do
next key word conduct a toar
reevaluation of the timeline with input
from all stakeholders okay
ensure every scope change has been
properly logged and it's impact assess
okay finish the project schedule as
extend the project schedule as needed to
finish the scope engage directly with
key stakeholders to renegotiate project
deliverables and timeline this is a
tricky question all right I'm giving you
guys that heads up tricky tricky you
have to read it very carefully what
answer did you guys get answer answer is
B not
a so first of all let's eliminate the
bad ones the bad one is you just can't
extend the schedule like that right you
just you would need to go through a
whole change request
process uh engage director is to
renegotiate the deliverables they don't
want to renegotiate the best thing here
is to face the problem not not just get
rid of the problem redo it
all now Comes A and B this was a tricky
question so my team member wrote this
one and I almost got it wrong because I
wasn't reading fast enough the mindset
tells us if somebody wants a change
assess the thing before making a change
which is what B is but it says what to
do first what to do
next before you do that before you
assess the timeline you better make sure
that all those changes were logged that
all the scope changes are there because
imagine you go and you do a and you
forgot to log one of the changes that
was there now if you're wondering where
do we put this it should have been in
some kind of change log or issue log or
something so before you do a do be this
is a common thing on this this
exam when you work on this when you do
this test you got to be careful anytime
you see what to do first what you do
next remember put this in order say this
to yourself before you move
on out of those four choices am I doing
that first or that first should you and
that's what we're doing
here do you review all the all the
changes to the scope are are documented
and then assess the the the the impact
on the timeline or do you just assess
the impact on the
timeline without checking without
checking if all the Scopes changes has
been documented that's how you look at
this
89 as a project manager overseeing a
pivotal update to a client Software
System you notice a significant lack of
Engagement from the client side during
critical Sprint review sessions despite
this your team has successfully
developed a a working prototype that's
ready for
evaluation what is the first thing the
project manager should do send a detail
Pro uh send a detailed progress report
email to the client highlighting the
prototype's completion and next steps
deploy the prototype to the client to
gather their feedback
okay schedule a comprehensive review
session with the Project's technical
lead to refine the Prototype before
client's
presentation organize a Sprint review to
actively review the Prototype
encouraging their inputs and and
adjustments
now this this question not too difficult
so the it seems like there's kind of
like a lack of Engagement maybe what the
client is seeing is not what they want
the best thing here to do is to do a
Sprint review the only time I don't want
to say the only time but the main time
that a client comes in and gives us
feedback on the product is during those
Sprint
reviews you don't want to just send out
an email it's not just about an email
about what we did we need their input
the point of prototypes is to get input
just you just can't deploy the Prototype
and wait for their feedback they might
not know it's exist or they might not
use it the best thing to do is to
demonstrate that now this one here
comprehensive review notice the
Project's technical lead you don't
prototypes are meant to be given to
customers not just to the technical
leads you want to get prototypes into
the hand of the customers demonst ation
product usage making D the best
answer and the last question I know I
hate to ask again but can you click that
like button subscribe to the channel I
know I know it's
annoying in the midst of a Project's
life cycle a project manager identifies
that essential feedback from a vital
operational division has been
consistently omitted in the planet and
execution phases this negligence has led
to widespread dissatisfaction con conc
erning how project outcomes align with
operational workflow of this
division what should the project manager
do first now we just did a question like
this where we talked about what you do
first so let's take a look at this
change the scope to include the
overlooked operational
Insight conduct a comprehensive review
of the projects adhes to the
organizational policies adherence to the
organizational policies review the
communication management plan to
understand the current Communication
channel craft a refect a reactive plan
to integrate unforeseen operational
needs into the Project's trajectory this
is not an easy question it sounds like
an easy question now before I give you
the answer I want to point out something
you notice that essential feedback from
has been consistently
omitted H there's a problem there
there's negligence in the flow of some
kind of communications right there this
has led to problems what should you do
first well the first thing you want to
do is to understand why that problem
exists first of all couple things here
we can
eliminate you can't just change a scope
like that it's not you if it's agile the
scope belongs to the product owner if
it's traditional it needs to go to a
change request so let's get rid of
it a reactive plan don't fix a problem
yet understand the problem before fixing
the
problem get ready d c a comprehensive
review of the product this is the
organizational policies the real problem
here is that the feedback was omitted
get to the root cause of the
problem okay so it's not just the
organizational policy is that there's
something wrong in the way
Communications is getting done the best
thing here we can do is to review that
communication management plan review
that plan see what's going on why was
there a disconnect on the plan itself we
can see the correct all right question
91 in the midst of deploying a major it
infrastructure update a project manager
identifies a significant knowledge Gap
within the
team primary amounts uh amount
recently onboarded staff with the
Project's tight deadline and budget
fully allocated external training
options are not feasible what two action
should the project manager take next now
you notice this is a choose two and I
want to point out to you that on your
exam you're going to have these
multi-choice questions where you have to
select two or three of those choices so
keep that in mind I think this is the
first one I'm giving you in this series
but keep that in mind you will see four
or five of these types of questions on
your full test all right so let's go
through the choices here assess specific
areas uh where the new staff members
lack
expertise consider reallocating critical
task to more experienced team members
until further notice propose a beef a
brief project pause to reallocate budget
funds towards emergency training
establish a mentorship paring between
the new staff and seasoned Professionals
for on the job training suggest that new
staff in dependently seek out online
resources to bridge their knowledge gaps
at their own cost now if you appli in
the mindset this question is not too
difficult notice that you have this take
next right so what are you going to be
doing next well the next thing you
should really be doing is knowing okay
in what specific areas are they lacking
any kind of training like what specific
areas that they lacking knowledge in you
shouldn't just go and start doing
training until you understand understand
that so hopefully you guys got that um
the next good answer here was let's put
a some kind of mentorship and you got
initiate this you have to be proactive
you should not tell the team that they
should just go and figure it out
themselves that's what e does that's why
that's wrong you shouldn't say okay you
guys go and find your own thing and
especially at their own cost on this
exam don't be negative if a choice seems
negative it's probably not the right
answer
uh consider reallocating critical task
what you're doing here is you're
overworking people if you have a choice
that seems like you're overworking
people probably not the right answer
never pause your project the only time
you should ever shut a project down is
if you're doing something that's against
the law or or unethical for example
you're breaking some kind of regulations
then it's a good time to stop the
project maybe there's a safety
regulations that you're not meeting then
it's a good time to stop the project but
when when it comes to things like this
you probably don't stop the project
making a and d the best
answers question
92 while working on an Innovative web
plat web platform a project manager
receives a request from a critical
stakeholder for the inclusion of several
unforeseen functionalities within the
current Agile development cycle what
should the project manager do advise the
stakeholder to present their suggestion
following the review of the
uh present cycle recommend assessing the
viability of these functions these
functionalities add the sub subsequent
team plan and meeting swiftly revise the
Project's development agenda to Inc
compress the requested functionalities
have the product owner to engage with
stakeholders concerning the
incorporation of their request into the
ongoing project now I know I said these
are going to be complex questions but if
you understand agile practices it's
rather really easily if you don't this
is a pretty complex question so what
happens when somebody requests some kind
of function on an agile project what do
you do well the best thing here you do
is to have them meet with the product
owner remember something only the
product owner can add functions to a
project not a project manager you don't
have that capability that's the role of
the product owner not the team the
product
owner never just say uh advise the Stak
present to the next cycle have them meet
with the product owner look at this
recommend assessing the vi function in
the next team plan meeting the team
doesn't determine functionalities the
product owner does you should not
swiftly incorporate it that is not your
job 93 as the deadline for critical
project approaches the project manager
notices a decrease in team enthusiasm
with several members consistently arri
and late to the office the project
manager notes the team is not focused
and D at what should you
do coordinate with human resources to
dismiss potential postp part uh to
discuss potential post project
opportunities for team members okay
maybe that'll motivate them conduct
motivational Workshop to re re-energize
the team and reinforce the importance of
their contributions all right sounds
good too initiate a peer recognition
program to highlight individual
contributions and Foster team Spirits
all right that's that's good good too in
for is strict attendance policy to curb
latencies and improve discipline within
the team I'm going to eliminate this one
right off the
bat the reason is because again on this
the mindset is going to tell us never be
negative if you're coming out so if
you're coming after someone and yelling
at them and disciplining them and
Reporting them and firing them it's
never the answer unless the question
says what not to do well in this one
here what are we going to do so we got
three good answers we we could see we
could try to motivate him by discussing
some kind of uh meeting with the pmo or
the HR to make sure they have more
opportunities afterwards maybe that
motivate them maybe we should try
motivating them or a peer recognition
what did you guys get best answer here
is what you should do as a project
manager is you should be keeping your
team motivated
correct you should keep your team
motivated don't just tell the team you
see what you're doing here in a is that
you're giving away the motivation to the
HR department C you're having them
individually try to motivate each other
by a peer recognition program the best
thing here you should do is try to do B
first I would do see if this works meet
with your team why are they feeling bad
what can I do what's going on guys
remember confront the problem is the key
on this
exam all right I know I said hard
questions this one is actually easy
during the development of a new
Healthcare System the project manager
requests that the product owner
prioritize features that will
significantly enhance patient data
processing efficiently what tool should
a product owner use scope statement
Sprint backlog product backlog WBS best
answer here is the product backlog the
product backlog stores all of the
features for an agile um for an Agile
development project how did I know that
this was an agile project even if it
didn't say it notice it says the product
owner the WBS and the scope statements
are used in traditional projects for a
full project management plan the Sprint
backlog contains things that will get
done in the next Sprint it doesn't have
all the features that that's going to be
on the agile project and the product
owner doesn't add to the Sprint backlog
only the team does now on your exam
expect where you're going to get some
similar questions like this where a few
of them are super easy you read it you
just pass it right away but then of
course you're going to get hard
questions like this one during the final
stages of a significant infrastructure
project it was discovered that
comprehensive reports on critical
structural
assessments performed by a key engineer
who has since Departed the company were
not documented or shared with the team
to mitigate such risk in the future what
should have been implemented by the
project manager during the project
Project Life Cycle all right so now
we're looking back all right and this
question I'm telling you guys is not
easy have the team initiate a cross
trainining program enabling team members
to understand and perform each other's
roles during absence okay organize
monthly knowledge exchange sessions
where engineer could discuss challenges
and solutions ensuring Collective
awareness of project
details okay uh engage external
Consultants to oversee all critical
testing phases ensuring an unbiased
review on documentation of
finding all right establish an
integrated project management
information system to share
information this question is not easy
most people when I did this with my um
with my classes got this one wrong so
let's see what you guys got now this
type of question you have to think
longterm like but longterm from the
beginning not something you could have
fix it they're not asking you to fix the
problem they're saying what should have
what what could you do now to prevent
this in the future all right that's what
they're trying to
do so the best answer here is going to
be D correct I'm not sure if you guys
got that but that's the answer here's
why there's a few of these we're going
to eliminate right off the bat first of
all let's get rid of B monthly knowledge
sessions a month may be too long try
have to put a timeline on something that
means if somebody quit halfway through
the month all the knowledge between day
1 to day 15 is gone what if they quit on
day 29 and you do the knowledge sessions
every 30 days um you kind of lost 29
days wor of knowledge not a good
idea we don't want to engage you don't
need to bring people in to start to put
all kinds of of additional pressure on
the team or additional team members not
a good idea let's get rid of those two
choices now I really liked it A and
D in a you have Team initiate cross
training program that way everybody
seems to be doing everybody's work
enabling team members to understand and
perform each other's role but what if
what if I know cross training is good
but what if it's an engineering job what
if Engineers need certain kind of
licenses there's a reason we put
engineers in
there that's may not work at all but you
know what's going to definitely work d
if you have an information system that
shares information something that's done
throughout the project then this if you
notice if we have a system that was
consistently sharing information this
would have solved the problem of this
guy leaving and anybody can leave at any
point because the information is all
there making D better than
a 96 as a project manager initiates a
project with a fully remote team
ensuring effective communication becomes
a challenge what is the best approach
for the project manager to maintain
consistent information flow within the
team suggest the creation of a monthly
detailed project updates for
comprehensive overview all right
establish structured online
communication platform for frequent and
organized team interactions all
right recommend open form for team
members to post daily updates okay
organize bi-weekly email blast to
summarize project progress and incoming
tasks I like this question this question
has a very important lesson to learn the
best answer here is going to be B now I
want to point out
something when you get a vague question
you can't generally answer it with a
very specific answer for example if I
say what's the best color shirt to wear
and your answer is you should wear blue
well that's my answer too let's all wear
blue I wear blue every day
but not everybody likes blue the best
color shirt to wear is whatever makes
the stakeholder happy and
successful notice it's a vague question
with a vague answer notice this
particular question is like well what
can we do to ensure effective
communication is it an email is it an
open form or is it some monthly detail
reports notice how a c and d are very
particular things versus B it's well
obviously they're online let's get some
kind of platform for they're not we're
not doing a monthly we're not doing a
daily we're not doing a weekly we're
just saying frequent this is more
generic than the
others that's what we want remember a
generic question should get a pretty
generic answer you can't just give a
specific question if you don't have all
the details this question doesn't give
much detailed it's a very open-ended
question should get an open-ended answer
got it hopefully that makes sense so
this question I don't think was
difficult but it taught a very important
lesson that when you go through your
exam keep this taught in mind as you go
through it by the way if you find this
tip help helpful and it's going to help
you on your test give the video a like
subscribe to the
channel 97 as a complex project draws to
a close the project manager realizes
that several risks
initially assess as slow probability and
impact evolved into significant issues
catching the project team off guard all
right this is a common thing by the way
in real life what proactive step notice
proactive should the project manager
have taken Implement a weekly risk
review session with the Project's coure
team to identify any changes in the risk
landscape all right Institute a monthly
risk tracking system to monitors the
project risk stat is continuously okay
mandated is zero policy of tolerance for
all risks ensuring every potential risk
was addressed immediately upon
identification H I don't know what that
one zero uh tolerance that that might be
tough under taken continuous assessment
and prioritization of risk throughout
the Project Life Cycle so we just did
that question generic type of question
where you got this generic uh question
and the best answer was generic answer
what do you think this one is well it's
the same type of question I put here
because if there's one thing we got to
learn is in the course I taught you guys
risk is something that's continuous it's
something you do all the time not
something you do some of the time risk
you consistently assess risk remember
risk changes
365 247
365 all right risk changes all the time
every day is there's a new risk every
day certain risk Chang so you should be
assessing risk on a continuous basis not
necessarily on a weekly or monthly basis
maybe you should be doing it on an
hourly basis maybe every minute you
should be doing it but we don't have a
choice like that or do we well
continuous assessment this ensures that
the project determines what's best for
them every project May assess risk at
different times so we don't want to just
go in there and choose something so
specific a zero policy probably will not
be implemented but when it comes to risk
assessment you should make sure that you
consistently assess risk because when
you start a project a risk that seems ah
it's not that important or risk that
seems that it's not going to really
impact you can change over time let's
keep that in
mind
98 in a project in a project uh
designated to deploy new technologies
across several departments a project
manager notices a shift in stakeholder
satisfaction levels
despite the project ading to its
timeline and deliverables being met
feedback indicates a perception of
diminish and returns in terms of value
from the recent project increments so
this is a long question as you can see
notice they're pushing things out
they're on time but the perception is
hey not great stakeholders are just not
seeing the value much anymore what
approach should the project manager take
to address these concerns clarify to the
state call is that the timeline needs
and and completed deliverables are the
primary indicators of success assuring
them that the project is right on track
all right highlight to the stakeholders
the inherent fluctuations in value
perception due to the variant nature of
resources and expected benefits at
different project stages all
right communicate to stakehold is a
common practice to tackle the most value
adding elements first result in a
perceived decrease in value as the
project progresses okay that's actually
true by the way in in an agile project
as time moves on you get less valuable
things analyze the trend and value with
the team to identify new online issues
device strategies for consistent value
and transparently relay those plans to
stakeholders good what is the best
answer here so notice we want to address
the
concern there are two good choices here
and that's going to be either C or D
making D the best answer now why is it
not a well you meet in your timeline and
you go into them is basically you're
forcing it upon them you're not really
doing anything to address the concern in
a you're basically saying hey we're on
time and you should like that that's
just being on time being deliverables
means you guys should be happy B let
them know okay it's okay for you guys to
be unhappy now I know it's going to go
up and down basically you're not really
addressing their concern and so is C
actually because in C you're basically
telling them well you know in agile
projects the first thing you get first
is going to be and everything else is
going to be bad after that that's really
but you're not addressing the core
concern maybe there's more to this I'll
tell you guys something on this test
confront the problem solve the problem
never kick the can down the road never
push away the problem and never say it's
not a problem the question it's telling
you it's a problem come up with
something to solve that problem I know C
is correct
but it doesn't mean you shouldn't on you
shouldn't identify what the underlying
issue is notice that's what the is
saying see what's going on here and see
what if there isn't on the line
isue 99 in the initial stages of
launching a Pioneer and software tool
aimed at small businesses the project
manager is focused on ensuring the
Project's quality resonates with its
target
audience what approach should the
project manager employ to ascend this
offer tool embodies the highest quality
standards engage a reputable software
development firm to ensure the tool
aligns with industry standards okay
recruit a chief quality officer to
oversee quality control throughout the
throughout the development establish
specific benchmarks quality benchmarks
for the software tool and continuously
seek ways to enhance them all right
instruct the lead developer to
prioritize refine and the software
platform and user experience now in this
one here the best answer is going to be
C there's a couple things so you're
building a software that you want to
have good quality a couple things we
don't know what a is about engage a
reputable software firm I'm not not
because a s a firm is reputable doesn't
mean that it actually is going to
produce quality software right some big
software firms produce pretty crappy
software think of Microsoft uh to ensure
it aligns with industry standards the
best way to know industry
standards is to do benchmarks
benchmarking is a tool we use in ad as
tool we use in traditional projects to
understand what our industry standards
and how to meet them if you meet a
benchmark generally you're going to
produce good quality
products you should not be hiring a
quality officer that is your job the
lead to to prioritize this is something
that the product owner should do or
something that more the project manager
the project sponsor is going to
do last question guys question 100 in
the in the progression of an extensive
software development project a pivotal
client proposes the introduction of a
new cloud-based technology mid project
significantly deviating from the initial
technology stacked outline the
suggestion aligns with the client's
ongoing digital transformation e uh
efforts what should the project manager
do
next analyze the proposed change for
strategic alignment and potential impact
on business outcome okay notify the
projects that did about The Client shift
towards digital transformation all right
implement the change to the timeline of
budget integrating new technology
okay evaluate the team's current
capabilities against the demand
introduced by the new technology the
best thing here you're going to do if a
stakeholder comes to you with a change
any kind of change on this project now
we're not saying that this is some kind
of agile project here so we're not sure
if it is but if they come to you with
some kind of a change the best thing you
can do is to assess that change just
don't go and implement the change don't
go to the steering committee if you
don't understand the chain the changes
and that brought to two good answer
either was a or D if you got one of
those two don't feel bad if you got D
but you know what here's why you should
have gone with a
before you assess the team capabilities
against the change see if the change
really is the stakeholder comes and says
hey this is notice the suggestion aligns
with their digital well does it maybe
you want to do that assessment first see
how it's going to affect the project see
how it's going to affect the outcome of
the project and if you feel you know
what maybe maybe this is good maybe this
a line then maybe you do D so let's do a
then we do D making a the best answer
all right questions
101 Jan the initiation the initiation
phase of an Environmental Conservation
project the project manager laws that a
key funding agency requires a
preliminary environmental impact
assessment before releasing additional
funds despite the agency history of
increase in additional funds following
initial assessments a senior team member
suggest full project planning should
commence immediately to expedite the
process what should the project manager
do keyword
next direct the team's efforts
exclusively towards completing the
required
assessment consult the organization Pro
the projects organization
guidelines proceed with drafting a
comprehensive project plan to cover all
phases including post assessment
activities aligned with the senior
members suggestion and initiate detailed
planning for subsequent pro project
stages now this question I found
difficult this was a pretty difficult
question but remember what you're doing
next is not just taking an action but is
assessing looking around reviewing
something making sure that the next
action you take is a good action so
assess review see what's right to take
and then take an actual
action answer here is going to be
understanding what the organization
wants this is a complex thing because
the team member is telling you hey we
should start planning right away and
really don't wait for the assessment to
come back but is that what the company
actually wants so it's not a question
you can answer right off the bat the
best thing to do is to make sure that
you have the right guidance from the
company now couple things never shut
people down in this one here you're
telling them hey I don't care what
you're saying do that if a choice seems
negative it's probably not the answer in
this one it's like you're disregarding
what they said and you're just pointing
the direction if a team member gives you
some advice try to follow up on that
advice I'm not saying to follow it I'm
saying to follow up on it in other words
see if that's the right
advice draft a uh comprehensive plan no
wait see what the guidelines are then do
that and definitely don't just Implement
what the team member wants without
seeing if the guidelines or if that's
how the company should be doing it
102 towards the end of a large scale
infrastructure development project the
project manager detects a Slowdown in
progress with significant number of
tasks pendant in the Project's quality
assurance stage the project is managed
using a combination of traditional and
agile methodologies what should you do
next initiate an intensive quality
assurance session for the team project
Team all right bring in an external
consultant with expertise in in quality
assurance all right facilitate a problem
solving session to tackle the quality
assurance bottleneck with the team
allocate additional time specifically
for quality insurance task in the
project schedule all right best answer
here if you if you went through the
mindset you know this one is not too
difficult because the answer here is
going to be hey work with the team
anytime you face a problem on a project
go to The Experts to help you in this
particular one there is some kind of
issue going on here you detect a
Slowdown and progress you got to
understand what's causing that there's a
big number of tasks pending in the
quality assurance stage the best thing
here to do is to have the team help you
to solve this problem
notice a is not correct at all because
it's intensive quality assurance
training session um before we do that
let's come up with a let's meet with the
team to see what's actually going on so
let's do this maybe we can do c maybe if
needed we way you don't need to bring in
a consultant meet with the team see if
the team can solve it first maybe then
you do we no don't allocate additional
time meet with the team and see if they
can fix it before doing that so remember
what are you doing next anytime you get
questions of what you should do next
remember it's basically putting them in
order like we do we should do this then
do this meet with the team first and
then see what actions it's best to take
next number three Jan ongoing Urban
Development traditional project the
project manager is informed that a
stakeholder directly approached a team
member with with a request for
additional
feature which led to the team member
being distracted from their primary task
affecting the Project's progress what
should the project manager do now I want
to point out that they particularly
stated that this is a traditional
project all right so you got to
understand how to handle scope changes
or feature changes on a project
address the stakeholders requests and
its impacts on the team productivity in
the next project status meeting B report
the issue to Senior Management
highlighting the stakeholders bypass of
formal request channels and its effect
instruct C instruct the team members uh
the team member to direct the
stakeholder to submit all future
requests through the state TR the
project manager for proper evaluation
and documentation all right in encourage
a stakeholder to participate in the
project schedule review sessions to
ensure their input is captured in a
structured manner best answer here
remember it's a traditional
project is going to be tell them hey
send a stakeholder to me when you're
managing a traditional project it is
important to follow the change
management process which generally means
people bring their changes to the
project manager and the project manager
will assess the change and see if the
change is approve or not that's the best
thing you can do so you can go to the
team member and instruct them hey if a
stakeholder is doing this tell them to
come to me not to
you uh notice a which at the beginning
sounds good and then it's impact on the
team no what you need to do is you need
to uh and it shouldn't be the next
status meeting because God knows how
long ago that is how when that's going
to be from
now so the best thing here to do is to
let them know you know tell the
stakeholders come to to me that way it
doesn't affect the team productivity
never report anyone on this test you're
probably going to get choices quite a
few questions going to have choices
report this guy to Senior Management
report this guy to the sponsor report
this guy to the project management
office those are never the answer never
report anyone never try to get people in
trouble never try to get anyone
fired encourage to participate in the
project schedule this is not anything to
do with the schedule this is a scope
change notice they're added a feature
question
104 in the early planning stages of a
green building project the project
manager faces challenges with limited
data available for defining specific
activities and estimating their
durations accurately what strategy
should the project manager employ
Implement a detailed timeline with key
milestones and delivery dates okay
utilize Progressive elaboration and
flexible plan plan
techniques adapt iterative planning with
regular evaluations and adjustments use
detail estimation method derived from a
comprehensive work breakdown structure
best answer here guys now remember to
choose two best answer here is going to
be B and C correct here's why because
notice so you can do the estimation
because you have limited data
um for defining specific act limited
data for Define an activity means you
don't really have a comprehensive
WBS and you can't do a detail timeline
because you're having difficulties
estimating things the best thing here
you can do is when you're doing projects
that are complex is plan to replan
that's the whole concept of progressive
elaboration in which case as time is
progressing Things become more detailed
for example if I say let's do a 5-year
project can we really plan the specific
duration of an activity that's going to
happen in year five right now the whole
world can change in year five so what we
do is we say you know what leave that
duration plan in until we get closer to
year five maybe in year four we'll do
that that's a concept of progressive
elaboration and then iterative plan it
means we're plan to replan we're going
to say you know what we're going to plan
we're making a plan right now to replan
in four years for activities in year
five we did cover this in the course
hopefully you got this one right
question 105 as a project manager
overseeing the development of a new line
of echo-friendly packaging material you
encounter push back from certain
stakeholders who who question who
questions the Project's viability due to
environmental regulations and Market
demands
uncertainty what action should the
project manager
take request a meeting with key
stakeholders to directly address their
concerns and provide detailed
explanations okay continuously evaluate
and adjust projects f f foundational
documents to ensure they reflect current
conditions and insights craft a
comprehensive risk management strategy
to identify and mitigate potential
issues related to regulations and Market
response align project objectives and
broader environmental sustainability
goals to ensure comprehensive
organizational coherence now you're
having a problem with the stakeholders
they're questioning hey can we do this
project is there
Market is there some kind of
environmental regulations anytime you
have a problem on a project the best
thing here to do guys is to address it
with those stakeholders meet with the
stakeholders understand their main
concern directly address that concern
and solve that problem
now continuously evaluate and adjust I'm
not sure what the foundational document
here is we're not even too sure what is
it that the stakeholders are so
concerned about find that out
then maybe come up with a risk
management plan or some kind of risk
strategy um and depending on what the
strategy is maybe you do d right realign
the objectives maybe if that's needed
depending on what their concern is but
if you have a stakeholder with issues if
you have stakeholders that has a problem
with the way the project is done the
best thing here to do is address those
issues with the stakeholder thems
themselves 106 in leading a complex
software development project with te
team members spread across diverse
geographical
locations the project manager seeks
strategies to enhance cohesion and
ensure project Effectiveness oh boy
sorry about that uh forgot to put that
on there all right pause I'm I don't
want to redo this video just pause the
video right now good you did that all
right now you're now you're caught up
ensure project Effectiveness what action
should the project manager take organize
intermediate gathering for collab
problem solving and team integration
exercises have members meet in one time
zone to ensure everyone can
attend initiate a buddy system parent uh
remote team members to Foster cross
Regional collaboration and knowledge
sharing utilize a flexible work schedule
allowing team members to choose their
work hours all right what is the best
answer here so let's take a look at this
all right you got a
team across diverse geographical
locations the best answer with that in
mind best answer is going to be a now
some of these answers are just plain raw
notice have members Mee in one time zone
well that means not everyone can attend
because they don't work in the same time
zone it's cross geographical
locations a buddy appearance system
means that only those two people are
going to work
together flexible work schedule if you
allow them to choose choose their own
work schedule they might be working more
apart than together so a is not I don't
think a is a great answer but it is the
best of the for answer and this brings
me to a point remember what this exam is
this exam is not about choosing the
correct answer it's choosing the best of
the four so sometimes you got to choose
the least of the suckiest answer because
maybe they all suck but one of them is
going to be the least of those the least
worst answer and that's the one you go
with
107 as a project manager of a new
healthcare software implementation
project you're leading a team that's
decided to embrace a hybrid approach
combining elements of both agile and
waterfall methodologies the project
success hinges on your ability to unify
the team towards a common goal aim the
complexities of the healthcare sector
what steps should you take to ensure the
team
functions effectively as a cohesive
unit okay so this is a common thing in
real life all right very common thing in
real life that you have teams that are
combined and they're trying to do a
hybrid
approach uh you got to make sure you
unify them all right what are we going
to do schedule a regular one-on-one
meeting with team members to tailor
communication and task management to the
individual
preference create a conflict resolution
protocol that emphasizes empathy your
understanding to address disagreements
quickly designate clear roles and
responsibility to each team member to
streamline project execution and
accountability Foster a culture of open
communication and establish your Norms
to guide effective to guide
collaborative efforts now this question
is not that uh easy I thought this one
was pretty difficult because they all
sound great and it's not uncommon on
your
exam to have all four choices s right
you got to go with the best one the
easiest way to do this is find a choice
that includes them all find a choice
that really that can apply to the entire
thing and that brings me to this choice
of
D you see open
communication shared Norms this here is
going to form that collaborative effort
because with open Communications this
allows everyone to work together now
there's a couple things here why the
others are not wrong notice regular
one-on-one meetings with team members to
tailor
Communications and to the if you do this
with every single one it might be very
difficult especially on a hybrid project
because individual and the way
Communications are done is vastly
different between agile and
traditional protocol emphasizes I do
like this one but you know what open
Communications established Norms will
include B designate clear roles to each
member that's also is going to be be in
open Communications they caned the best
answer if you have multiple answers that
sounds great try to find the one that
includes the others if one includes all
those good answers that means probably
the right
answer 108 as a as a project manager
over seeing a large scale renewable
energy project you're confronted with a
sudden need to transition your
traditionally onsite team to work to
remote work due to environmental
regulations and affect and
affecting access to the project site
several members expressed concern about
their inexperience with with and the
potential challenges of maintaining
their usual level of productivity and
communication in a remote
environment what what step should the
project manager take to ensure the team
remains productive and cohesive while
working remotely
he arrange for economic home office
setups for all members to enhance their
work from their home working environment
all right I like that you should make
them comfortable partner with it to
provide customized Tech solutions for
each team member based on a specific
remote home okay probably should do that
too arrange for a comprehensive training
on remote uh Communications and project
manag to improve team adaptability okay
Implement a more flexible project
timeline to account for learning curve
associated with adapting to remote work
difficult
question I think each one of these has
their has their correct answer but one
of them really deals with the problem
head on and the problem that they're
really dealing with is their
productivity which one here is you see
the potential challenges of maintaining
the key thing here is productivity and
communication
it's not about their
ergonomics or their IT
issues uh or their time all right it's
how are they going to communicate so
come up with a good training system to
manage their
Communication in in these questions you
have to read carefully a few words can
change an entire question in fact one
word can change an entire question keep
that in mind so read
carefully 109
facing the challenge facing the
challenge of rolling out a critical
Disaster Response application a project
manager leads a multi-disciplinary team
under tight deadlines the application
needs to be operational in a third of
the standard timeline to effectively
respond to an ongoing crisis what action
should the project manager take to
ensure timely delivery while maintaining
essential functions essential
functionality accelerate All Phases of
the timeline
streamline Communication channel to
enhance team efficiency focus on team
deliver and MVP increase uh working
hours to cover more tasks and less time
if you understand the way agile works
the best thing here you can do is going
to
be correct we want an MVP or a minimum
viable product this is going to allow us
to push something to the market very
quickly notice needs to be operational
in a third
thir of the standard timeline by
utilizing an MVP we an MVP a minimum
viral product allows you to release
something to your users very very
quickly now it's probably not going to
have every single feature but it's going
to have the most used features or the
most requested because remember how if
you follow agile you build the most
valuable features first so this is going
to give them access to
it accelerating All Phases may not be
doable for example you can't accelerate
coding and testing because if you
haven't coded anything there's under to
test streamline communication although
this will increase efficiency the best
thing is to go with that mvp increase
never work people overtime all right if
you ever have a choice on your exam to
overwork your employees that sounds
negative don't do
it last question during the execution
phase of a large scale environmental
restoration project the project manager
encounters a debate among team members
regarding a necessary extension of
timeline due to unforeseen regulatory
changes how should the project manager
proceed stick to the stakeholder
Communications plan for systematic
engagement decision- making analyze the
impact of the timeline expand on the
project then consult with the team for
guidance organize an urgent team meeting
to vote on the timeline extension aiming
for a democratic uh uh decision directly
implement the timeline extension
prioritizing regulatory compliance all
right what is the best answer
so follow your mindset on this one I
taught this one here not too difficult
all right you have a debate am team
members regarding the extension assess
it but remember just don't assess it by
yourself make sure to consult with the
team let the team help you assess this
work with the entire
team uh just just don't tell them to
stick to this in decision making address
the problems organize an urgent meeting
to vote on it well before you vote on
the extension assess it before you do
that directly do don't do that assess it
to see how it affects the project and
have the team help you question 111
halfway through a software development
project the project manager identifies
that an important security feature was
omitted this feature is essential for
the software to me industry security
guidelines the project manager stands
that integrating this feature promptly
is critical to prevent potential
security breaches what is the most
effective course of action the project
manager should take
next schedule an urgent meeting with
stakeholders to discuss the Implement of
the implications of incorporating the
security feature conduct an impact to
understand the impact of adding this
feature at this stage of the project
prioritize the security features in a
project backlog ensuring that IT
addresses the next phase seek additional
resources to include the security
features without alterating alter the
current project Milestones remember
you're doing this here it says what
should you take next so you missed the
feature the best thing you're going to
be doing next is to see how adding this
in is going to affect the current
project because we know we got to add it
in but we got to see okay how is this
going to affect the project how much is
it going to drive the budget how much is
going to drive up the schedule before we
do anything else now there's a couple uh
reasons why the rest of these are wrong
first of all you should have eliminated
C the project manager cannot add to the
project backlog and not prioritize the
project backlog urgent to discuss the
but we already know that if we don't
incorporate it you don't need a because
you already know that there's going to
be security breaches there's no need for
a seek additional resource assess it
before seeking additional resources
making B the best
answer 112 during a healthcare facility
upgrade project a project manager is
informed by a key stakeholder that
certain Advanced technological features
expected by the stakeholders are not
visible in the preliminary designs what
should the project manager do to address
the stakeholders concerns review the
project plan and update the
stakeholders okay confirm with the
stakeholders that their expectations
will be integrated in the design
provision process organize a detailed
presentation on the current project
status and future Milestones have the
team include the design and the project
scope what are we going to be doing how
do we how are we going to address this
person's concern best answer here guys
is to review the plan and update the
stakeholders that is correct so first of
all notice a key stake certain
technological expected are not visible
so it's not visible to them is it in the
plan well that part I'm not sure about
so go and find out you're a project
manager hey stakeholder comes to you and
says hey it's not in the plan but are
you sure it's not in the plan do you
know that your next step how do how are
you going to address this your best step
here is to review the plan to see if it
is or it's
not you can't confirm with them that
it'll be integrated unless you check
that plan you shouldn't organize a
detail and future Milestone the
stakeholders check the plan first just
the team can't include things like that
in a scope it has to go to a full change
process and if it's if it's a
traditional project it'll go to a change
process if it's an adile project to
product owner can add
it 113 following a corporate
restructuring the project manager
notices that the newly assembled team is
having difficulty adapting to their
Collective
role with members often prepare
prefering to work in isolation rather
than as a unified team this behavior is
affecting the Synergy and effect and
efficiency of project work what should
the project manager do to enhance Team
Dynamics are organize a workshop to
focus on team integration and
collaborative problem solving Implement
a flexible work policy to accommodate
individual work preference establish a
regular oneon-one check-in to address
any personal concerns affecting teamwork
initiate a competitive Initiative
Program to encourage collaboration
there's really only two good answers
here you got they working in Silo
activities basically they're in
isolation the two good answers here was
either a or D first of all B was never a
good answer because of flexible work if
they're now they're not together at all
some may work sometime or not you're
separating them even more a one-on-one
checkin doesn't address them working
together now you're just addressing them
it's like you're promoting the
one-on-one initiate a comp uh
competitive Initiative Program this here
is going to make them more competitive
may not put them the best thing here to
do is to bring them together put them in
workshops and let them start working
together
let them come up with ways to solve
problems
114 in an initiative to manage a
software development team spread across
multiple continent a project manager
seeks to enhance collaboration and
ensure synchronous work Dynamics the
team diversity in culture and geography
presents a unique challenge in
maintaining effective Communications and
collaboration what initiative should the
project manager prior prti to ensure
effective team
collaboration okay so once again you're
trying to make this team work together
but now you have them spread across
continents a introduce a dynamic
platform for real-time video conference
and interactive sessions all right
Implement an asynchronous communication
tool for delayed but comprehensive
exchange all right see arrange for
physical uh annual physical meetups to
Foster personal connections D develop an
internal email newsletter for weekly
updates on Project progress so we want
the team to work together you have them
in a diverse you have them across the
continent um they're having a problem
with effective Communications so how can
we increase and make their
Communications better the best answer
here guys is going to be a if you got a
that is correct and the reason is
because a real time video conference in
like Zoom will help them to communicate
a lot better a physical Meetup is not
going to solve this because that's just
just once a year and email is more of a
push type communication it's not an
interactive
communication asynchronous is offline so
it's not interactive you want them
effective Communications and especially
collaboration when you think
collaboration always think of
interactive you can't be collaborative
if I me and you are not collaborating if
I'm just giving you information this
video is not is not a collabor ation
between me and you I'm not taking from
you you're not taking from me I'm just
giving you
information so you don't want something
that's asynchronous you want something
that's more synchronous make an a the
best
answer
115 in the critical validation stage of
a software development project a
thirdparty component fails to meet the
expected performance Benchmark this
discrepancy leads to significant
concerns about meeting the project
timeline the man identifies that the
failure is due to the component being
developed based on outdated
specifications what could have been done
to prevent this from happening now
you're going to get these questions
where you see something that says
prevent from happening that means don't
fix the problem right now it means to
fix the problem before it can happen
right it means to prevent the problem
from happening so be careful when you
read the
answers conduct a comprehensive review
of the project requirement and
management processes with stakeholders
to align expectations and specifications
all right initiate a cost benefit
analysis determine if redesign of the
components is financially viable
compared to potential project delays all
right schedule urgent me with supplier
to negotiate expertise delivery terms
all right assign a team assign a team to
develop a work around for the fail
component the best answer here is going
to be a you notice so read the question
carefully the failure is due to a
component being developed based on
outdated
specification now that means the
specifications were
incorrect B to determine if redesign and
this is going to fix the current problem
we don't want that we want to prevent
the current problem schedule an urgent
meeting with the supply to negotiate exp
this here might fix the current problem
assign a team to you don't want to work
around work around means you you a work
around means something failed and then
you're going around that trying to fix
it that all of these doesn't line up
with the keyword of prevent this problem
maybe if the question was like how do
you fix this problem you know maybe B
and maybe b and a would have probably B
and D would have been a good answer but
they're asking to prevent the problem so
read carefully 116 a project manager is
overseeing a project designed to deliver
iterative enhancement to an existing
service and has an established
prioritize product backlog from the
product owner good despite this the
product owner later voices concern to
Senior Management about the Project's
Direction not aligning with the
expectations with
expectations what initiative should a
project manager have undertaken all
right so we got a project the product
owner prioritize the product backlog but
they just don't like the direction that
they're going in what should we do
Institute a comprehensive stakeholder
engagement plan to ensure all voices are
heard and integrated into project
planning okay adapt a more flexible
approach to project management
methodologies to accommodate changing
stakeholders expectations all right
enhance team training on the Project's
Technical and business aspect to ensure
a deeper understand of project goals all
right organize regular Sprint review
meetings with the product owner and
conduct team retrospective to close the
feedback loop now you right off the bat
you can tell that this is going to be an
agile project you got the product owner
you got the product
backlog uh keep in mind here that the
product owner is not sure like they're
not something is not aligning to ensure
that an ad job project stays aligned you
should be doing your Sprint review
meetings the Sprint review meetings is
when the product owner the customer
comes in and sees what happening then
they can give feedback basically at the
end of every Sprint which is basically
every month or or every few weeks to
tell you if it's a line or it's not a
line now why is the rest not wrong well
it's not it's not really into there's
nothing in the question that states that
there's a problem with the team's
technical understanding of this so
that's wrong a more flexible approach to
the method there's nothing wrong with
the methodology maybe the methodology is
not used right Institute a comprehensive
and to ensure all voices heard you may
never hear all voices on all projects so
the best answer here is to make sure you
do the Sprint review
meetings by the way if you guys are
enjoying this video give the video a
like make sure to
subscribe 117 after project Milestone a
team member voices concerns over the
lack of detailed feedback regarding
their project contributions the
individual feels that without specific
Insight their ability to improve and
impact the project positively is limited
what should the project manager consider
first schedule on All
Hands meeting to discuss project
performance and individual contributions
openly establish an online form for the
project team to post accomplishments and
receive peer
feedback uh introduce a quarter review
system that focuses on Project Specific
achievements and growth areas enhance
documentation of individual performance
metrics and provide regular personalized
feedback session all right best answer
here guys remember it's one
stakeholder it's one team member so what
are we going to be doing is we should
personalize feedback first of all you
don't want to do individual ual
contributions and and say openly how
someone is doing great or not doing
great uh or this one because then it may
seem like some people are doing more
than others and may not necessarily be
true you don't want just an online form
you want to address this directly with
the team quarterly system maybe too long
or Too Short depending on the project
the best thing here let people know what
those individual metrics are so they
know if they're meeting them and you
want regular personalized feedback on
this making D the best
answer 118 during a project review the
client identifies a critical feature in
the new software application that was
not that was discussed but not
implemented so they knew about it but we
didn't put it in the project manager
verifies that this in this feature was
indeed documented as part of the scope
what should the project manager on take
as a preliminary
action initiate a brainstorming session
with the stakeholder to identify
alternative for the missing feature
arrange a detailed discussion with the
team to understand the oversight and
develop corrective action commission an
external audit to evaluate the project
management processes and identify gaps
recommend the suspension the project
delivery timeline to reevaluate all
project components comprehensively now
this you're going to follow the mindset
so we miss something if you miss a
feature that's critical that should have
been there they knew they should have
gotten it done but we just didn't get it
done find out why what happened meet
with the team and then come up with a
way to solve it that's the best thing we
can do brainstorming you don't want to
come up with alternative Solutions until
meeting with the team maybe the team
maybe this is something the team can
Implement right away you don't need an
external audit um to identify any gaps
in the project this should have been a
throughout answer before you do any of
that remember it's a prelim you know
it's a primary action one of the things
you want to do as a primary action is to
meet with the team have the team help
you solve this recommend the suspension
never stop your project the only time
You' ever probably stop a project is if
you're breaking the law or someone may
may die or some kind of safety
issue but never stop a project like
that 119 upon discovering a significant
quality issue with a key suppliers
deliverables the project manager needs
to address the problem to maintain
project standards what should the
project man what should be the project
manager's initial action schedule an
urgent project team meeting to
brainstorm potential solutions to the
Quality
Issue request and immediate
comprehensive quality audits on all
supplier deliverables to identify the
scope of the problem all right refer to
the Project's risk register for pre
predetermined mitigation actions D draft
and Urgent communication to the supplier
demanded and explanation of proposed
rectification plan okay so what is going
to be your initial action which is
basically going to be what's your first
action and this question was tricky
because the answer here is actually c
not sure if you got this one so what
this is doing is this is testing your
ability to understand okay so we have an
issue now but before something becomes
an issue it should have been a risk so
when you were identifying your risk in
in the plan and process you should have
had a risk that says uh deliverable or
product not meeting quality from quality
requirements from
suppliers now the actions you take
should have been stored in the risk
register which is what this is so you
should have had this thing down as a
risk and if the risk does materialize
then you should have looked at the risk
register to tell you the mitigation
strategy for it that's why this is the
best answer
here uh an urgent team meeting although
I like a I like B uh first of all d is
never never do anything like demanding
an
explanation you never want to be
negative so I would eliminated that you
A and B are good actions but you want to
do c first then maybe do a and b so if
you got a and b keep in mind that c
should have just came first it's that
initial
action last question guys 120 after an
unscheduled discussion a project team
member advises the client about
potential project delays due to frequent
changes and requirements what proactive
steps should the project manager take to
manage project Communications more
effectively emphasize to the project
team the importance of routing all
Communications to the project manager to
ensure consistency and accuracy conduct
a workshop with the team to underscore
the significance of adherent to the
Project's communication guidelin
schedule a meeting with the client to
directly address their concern and
clarifying any misunderstanding about
the the project timeline require all
significant project updates and
communication convey through formal
channels to maintain documentation and
Clarity I thought this question was very
very difficult the answer here guys is
going to be
the um this is there's nothing here that
says it's an agile project unscheduled
discussions is probably not something
you want to do especially on those
traditional projects you want to make
sure that you have formal channels all
communication should be documented
should be maintain and should go through
the project communication channels
follow your communication management
plan in other words emphasize to the
team the importance about you shouldn't
not all communication be careful of this
word all and let me see that in a choice
it means everything goes through the PM
no a workshop you never underscore
anyone schedule a meeting with the
client to address well this is just this
one time you know what solution can you
take to ensure this never happens again
make indeed the best answer practice
question 121 during the execution phase
conflicts have Arisen between two team
members negatively impacting their work
output despite the project manager's
effort to encourage open communic open
communication to resolve the
disagreements there has been no
improvement by the way this is a common
thing in real life what action should
the PM consider as the next step to
resolve the conflict implement the
strategy to delegate separate tasks to
team members reduce in direct
interaction arrange for a third- party
mediator to facilitate a solution
between the two members have the team
members keep working on the issues to
solve the problem address the conflict
by making a decision that best serves a
project objectives even if it's
unilateral now this kind of question is
common on the exam and this is a tough
question because there's really two good
answers let's see what you got the best
answer here is going to be D now let's
go through this because there's really
two good answers let's eliminate the of
the guarantee where's that mouse let's
eliminate the guarantee back ones all
right my pad isn't working in this
video so let's take a look at this which
one here is the bad one well first of
all C get rid of C because in C in that
one you're doing nothing in other words
if the question is basically take no
action in other words let them figure it
out themselves it's never an it's never
an answer on the question says what not
to do as a project manager be proactive
help things just don't do nothing the
next one here you're going to elate just
Implement don't separate them separating
the task is kind of like pushing the
conflict aside this is it's it's a way
of like smoothing out the conflicts
where you're saying hey don't worry
about it in other words you're
separating them but you're not
addressing the conflict now comes two
that actually may solve the conflict
arrange for a third- party mediator or
address the conflict now the best answer
here when when there is a big Conflict
Management happening on the project that
team members cannot resolve sometimes
it's best for the project manager to
make a step and take the options that's
best for the project objectives you guys
got to remember something it's important
to solve problems to the benefit of the
project objectives not just to the
benefit of Bob or Mary it's all about
satisfying the objectives of the project
to meet stakeholder needs now the other
one here is just to get a third party to
resolve the third party mediator in this
one you are taking a proactive step to
solve the problem
122 A team member has been reporting no
progress on a critical task for several
days during the daily standup meetings
causing a potential delay in the project
timeline this task is critical for the
next phase of the project what should
the PM do to facilitate progress
organize a brainstorming session with
the team to find alternative solution to
complete the
task initiate a risk assessment meeting
to evaluate the impact of the delay
schedule a 101 meeting with a team
member to identify any obstacles
encourage a team member to provide
detailed reports okay I do want to point
out here that this is a problem with a
particular team member and if you have a
problem with a member the best thing
here to do is to meet with that person
it's not the entire team so you don't
need to involve the entire
team uh this thing here if it's one
person you don't want to uh you don't
want to bring the whole team in meet
with that person talk to that person now
D does say encourage the team member to
provide but before you do that what you
want to do is you want to schedule a
meeting and see what's going on why is
before you say hey go do this see what's
going on so you would want to do c
first
123 For an upcoming critical initiative
a project manager must engage a vendor
notorious for not meeting deadlines yet
uniquely skilled for the project
requirements what approach should the
project manager consider during project
planning initi iate a collaborative
effort with the vendor to streamline
workflow and reduce potential delays
develop a contingency plan that involves
parallel work streams with similar
expertise set penalty clause for delays
in the vendor agreement propose a
performance-based payment schedule to
motivate timely deliveries without extra
costs all right what should we do now
this one actually has a few good answers
there's a few of them that are bad but
there's a few good answers here best
answer here guys is going to be a that
is correct if you got it now one of them
that you want to you don't want to just
penalize people like that although
penalty Clauses are set in contracts you
don't want to just do that without
seeing unless there was no other option
so let's eliminate that develop a
contingency plan that involves parallel
work before you do that work with the
vendor all right you want to work with
the vendor to see why are they notorious
late how are they going to solve this
and what can we do to reduce potential
delay just don't come up with other work
that we can do although I like D I think
there was one one bad answer was C you
should have Tor that out two good
answers Was A and D so D was this
proposed performance payment this has
given them an incentive before you do
that though work with the vendor and
then maybe D would have been an option
so let's go a then
D
124 upon discovering a critical design
issue in a software develop software
project stakeholders are un certain
about proceeding with the with the
implementation is plan what is the most
effective step for project manager for
the project manager to take to address
the concerns recommend a comprehensive
overhaul of the design update the
project quality assurance procedures to
Inc compress this new discovery initiate
a thorough risk evaluation to ascend
certain to ascend the flaws potential
impacts on the project deliverables
propose the introduction of additional
project phases to rectify the the
identified design issue now I want to
point out this is something that's
common they're not certain they're not
uh with the implementation but what are
you going to do well they said they're
not certain before you do anything else
what we what we should do is go in and
do an assessment right thorough risk
evaluation about any potential flaws
that are out there you shouldn't
recommend the overhaul you shouldn't do
this as one of the first step you
shouldn't recommend a comprehensive
overhaul of the entire design if you're
really you don't know what's going on
there you shouldn't update anything
unless you understand what's Happening
Here notice they're uncertain generally
when something is uncertain remember
something that's uncertain is a risk
something that has happened is an issue
now this one here propose additional
phases before you do that evaluate for
the potential impacts on these potential
risks when it comes to managing risk
keep in mind before you determine an
action to a risk identify
that risk and assess its impact on the
project then come up with the solutions
remember those three steps identify the
risk assess the risk identify potential
mitigation
strategies 125 at the onset of a new
phase in a complex project after a
successful kickoff meeting at the
client's site a team member request a
transfer to another project due to
discomfort with a colleague's behavior
during their first face-to-face
interaction what are the most suitable
actions for the project manager to
consider now we got five options let's
choose two organize AE organize a
conflict resolution meeting to address
and potentially resolve the
interpersonal issues between the team
members propose an immediate team
restructuring to the human resources
department separate the conflict
emphasize the Project's commitment to a
respectful and inclusive workplace by
reiterating the diversity and inclusion
guidelines seek guidance from the pmo to
determine the best course of action
suggest a temporary team reassignment
for both individual to assess the impact
on the Project Dynamics all right what
did you get this one here if you
understand the mindset if you know how
to handle people that's best for the
project I don't think this question was
very difficult although it did had a few
good options best answer here choose two
was going to be a and C why because
first of all we want to come up with a
conflict ver solution meeting this one
you guys should have all got if there's
a problem between team members bring
them together and let's solve the
problem that's confronting the problem
you shouldn't restructure the thing just
right off the bat this might affect the
entire Team Dynamics never go to the pmo
unless it's something out of your hands
when it comes to team conflicts that is
something within the control of the PM
that you should solve don't just fire
people if you ever get a question about
firing someone it's never the answer all
right if you don't don't get rid of
people try to manage people try to
understand the problem and solve the
problem so what we want to do bring them
together we want to solve that problem
and then we want to make sure that we
build a project team that's inclusive
and diverse and follows good
guidelines all right guys hopefully you
guys are learning if you guys are
enjoying this video can you give the
video a like subscribe to the channel
for more content just like
this practice question
126 and I hybrid Environ in a hybrid
project environment stakeholders are
experiencing challenging in assessing
the most recent version of the project
schedule in the Project's online
document management
system what proactive measure should the
project manager take Implement an
iterative tutorial with the document
management system to guide stakeholders
through the navigation all right B
ensure all stakeholders are train on how
to use the document management system
and not a location of critical documents
okay develop a feedback mechanism within
the document management for stakeholders
or report accessibility issues all right
create a detail create a dedicated hline
for stakeholders to call in or receive
guidance and access in the
project documents now I want to point
out here that this question uses a very
important term it's not what do you do
next it's what proactive measure be
careful with these here you see when it
says what to do next it means you're
addressing the current conflict in this
question we're not addressing the
current conf conflict we are preventing
the current conflict so you don't want
to do something right now to solve the
problem you want to do something to
prevent the problem make sure the
problem never happened
now what can we do best answer here is
going to be B part of the exam content
outline for your current PMP exam talks
about training your team members that's
what this is in sure they're all trained
to use it if they're all trained notice
they're experiencing challenges if
they're all trained they should have a
good understanding of how to access that
system you don't want to just put an
interactive tutorial although I think A
and B were the two best answers um this
one here to guide this is through the
navigation process all right notice we
want to do the whole thing not just how
to use it that's going to include that
but how to locate the documents B is
just a better answer than
a a feedback mechanism nope let them
learn how to use it not just when you
see C and D is more like you guys figure
it out and they call us for help that's
what basically D is um and C let them
figure it out and then tell us what if
there's any accessibility problems let's
train them ahead of time
127 in the midst of a software
development project the project manager
notices that the software features are
not aligned with the client's
requirements this misalignment has
caused the project schedule to slip
moving the schedule performance index or
SPI from 1.05 to 85 and the CPI from 1.2
to .95 what is the most effective course
of action for the project manager to
ensure the project meets its deadline
and quality requirements in the future
Implement a code review process to
identify an address defects before they
progress in a testing phase all right
enance communication with stakeholders
to refine project requirements and
expectations Implement an automated
testing tool to increase
efficiency re revisit it and adjust the
project schedule to better align with
project realities and client needs all
right guys what is the best answer here
now the best answer here guys is going
to be you got to read it very carefully
you see in this question I don't think
this question was difficult if you
didn't read if you if you read it
carefully it wasn't if you didn't it was
difficult because it tells you that
you're slipping so you're right now
you're 15% behind schedule and you're
about 5% over budget that's what those
numbers are telling us but
realistically it's not aligning with the
client requirements that's what's
causing all of
this right so the question is how can we
solve the alignment don't solve the
scheduling and the cost problem that's
where it throws you off things like
implementing a code
review uh all the other options A and B
A and in particular
uh really is addressing that schedule
and budget problem to like reduce that
but the problem really isn't in the
schedule is it it's in the expectations
and D is revisit you just can't go and
adjust the scope the best thing to do is
have the client come in to help you
adjust that
scope
128 a project manager is overseeing the
development of a new Urban Park during
the project a dispute arises between the
landscape designer and the environmental
consultant over the choice of plant
species with each advocating for
different selections based on ecological
impact what is the most effective course
of action for the project manager for
the projects the Project's ecological
and design goals are both met or
ecological you can pronounce it that way
too organize a collaborative session
between both parties to integrate the
ecological concerns with
design aesthetic
solicit input from local community to
determine their preference and guide
decision Implement a trial period for
both selections to evaluate their
performance in the Parks environment
rely on external research finding to
make decisions based on the best
practices all right this one here you
got a problem between two parties best
answer here bring the parties together
and let them work together to see what
is the best option for the project you
don't want to just push them aside or
Implement do your own thing cuz that's
what C is this is like you're saying
okay let's do this in a trial so you're
basically hearing what they say you're
making a decision get input well the
problem is not with the local community
so far the problem is between these two
folks right between the environmental
consultant and the
designer uh rely on external research
finding before you do that what you want
to do it's a problem between two teams
members have the two team members work
it out basically part of that
mindset
129 in the process of deploying a new
customer relation management system the
project manager realizes that the
updates provided to the sales department
head are perceived as lacking specifics
on user adaptation rates and feedback
what should the project manager do to
ensure the sales department head
receives the necessary information to
gauge project
success tailor the project updates to
include detail metrics on user
adaptation rates and specific feedback
for users all right Implement an
interactive dashboard that allows a
sales department head to access
real-time data organize a bi-weekly
review sessions to verbally communicate
user adaptation metrics get a feedback
distribute a monthly comprehensive
report covering all aspects of the CRM
deployment including user adaptation
this this question really goes to the
Core
of project management it goes to the
core of studying project management and
knowing what you should be doing as a
project manager because if you study
well you're going to come to understand
that tailor the communication one of the
things is in that you're going to learn
in the course you've learned already is
there's this process called identify
stakeholders in that you're not just
knowing who your stakeholders are but
you're understanding what their
communication preference are is from the
output stakeholder register that you
create communication management plan and
your stakeholder engagement plan which
means meet with the stakeholder and
tailor the communication to the
stakeholder on a project not all
stakeholder receives the same
information in fact stakeholders
receives vastly different information
the report you give to your CEO isn't a
report you're going to be given to team
members right so let's tailor that
communication to your
stakeholders every option here you are
choosing what's best for them let them
choose what's best for
them last question a project manager is
leading the development of a new public
park in a densely populated urban area
Community leaders have written concerns
about the Project's approach to
maintaining the natural habitat and
promoting biodiversity what should you
do next organize your community leaders
to detail their concerns about the
projects and its impact okay
Distributing information brochure
detailing the environmental benefit host
a virtual presentation with experts
discussing the Project's impact on local
wildlife launch a community feedback
initiative to get a suggestion of
further Improvement okay what should you
do next well if you have stakeholders
that
have uh some kind of concern get more
detail about that concern so we can
address it we want to do this first
right before you first of all we're not
sure if the project they're saying it
doesn't meet it so you telling them more
about it this is not going to help them
host of virtual experts discussing the
impact on local
Wildlife although this was the other
good answer uh discussing the projects
on notice with experts well we want to
meet with these Community leaders all
right launch community feedback I like
this option on farther but you know what
before we do that let's get to the core
of the problem what don't they like all
right let's get into it
131 by way I'm going to be reading it
and answering it right away please pause
the video you read it you answer it and
then see how you do to counteract the
issue of certain team members
disproportionately influencing the
outcome of project scope discussions the
project band decided to implement a
nominal group technique session what is
the significant benefit of utilizing
this approach enables the sequential
voting process to prioritize task
encourages equal contributions from all
team member prevents any single
viewpoints from
dominating stimulates Creative Solutions
through group server groups group
Synergy this is a tough question because
there's two answers now if you know this
group technique here this nominal group
techniques definition there's two good
answers uh that you could have gone with
and those two good answers was either B
or C now first of all it's not just
about sequential voting and uh groups
Synergy or Creative
Solutions this type
of uh group technique or management
technique here what this is going to do
is just ensure that everyone gets their
Viewpoint across and not just a few
people dominated but it's really not
about just about equal it's not equal
contributions but it's everybody's
contributions some may have more than
others but it prevents one or two people
from dominating your meat and make C the
best answer question 132 Jing an
environmental impact review of an energy
project the project manager discovers
that the environmental plan does not
adequately address potential impacts on
local Wildlife what should the PM do
encourage the environmental specialist
to assess the environmental impact on
Wildlife protection suggest the team
create a new environmental plan continue
with the project that's plan adjust
based on regulatory feedback pause the
project to reassess all environment
environmental impact aspects what should
you do first well before you stop the
project before and that's going to be
the before you stop the project to
create a new
plan if you feel like there's something
going on meet with the right specialist
meet with the right people on the team
to see okay I I think I got a hunch
maybe this is not going to work or this
can potential impact don't stop
something that's potential don't stop
the project that's potential ensure that
your this potential is 100% correct or
you have good information before making
that decision so the first thing you
should do is make that assessment and
never do nothing just don't continue to
plan and wait for some kind of
regulatory feedback never do nothing
always assess the
situation 133 as new software
development project kicks off
when is it most appropriate for the
project manager to conduct the first
status first project status meeting
shortly after the project kickoff
meeting to align on early objectives
after the two after two development
Sprint is completed once the first
version of the project is ready as soon
as the team demonstrates progress and
collaboration all right this was a tough
question it really had two good answers
and that was either a or D now you don't
want to wait for Sprints to be done or
or a product an entire first version
this can take a long
time it really comes down should you do
one shortly after the kickoff meeting
well the kickoff meeting is about
alignment to the project objectives you
don't need it right after that but the
moment the team starts to demonstrate
progress the moment the team starts to
work on the product now you have
something to report on notice this is a
status
meeting if you haven't really done
anything on the project you really
cannot report status on it right so n it
just demonstrate progress on there the
best
answer 134 team members lack enthusiasm
for participating in essential project
planning sessions with many arriving
late or not contributing uhoh this is
not good what strategy should the
project manager employ first introduce a
structured agenda with allocated times
for each speaker to ensure Focus
discussion all right develop a rotating
Leadership Model for the planning
session allowing different members to
lead okay encourage team member to
contribute their insights and
suggestions on Improvement the uh the
plan and process all right transition to
a digital collaboration platform for
planning sessions to provide flexibility
and participation this one had quite a
few good answers by the way tough
question best answer here guys is going
to be did you get it C is correct now
why is C correct notice in this one
here you're telling them what to do
you're telling them what to do you're
telling them what to do or you're
designing the whole thing this one here
let's meet with the team and let's
encourage them to do something encourage
them to share encourage them to bring
their suggestions encourage them to be
part of the team just don't come out and
says okay we're going to do this we're
going to do this we're going to do this
that's not being a good servant leader
that's more of a dictator type
leadership 135 when the project manager
of a software development project finds
the specification provided by the client
are ambiguous was what is the most
appropriate initial
action initiate development based on the
existing specifications while waiting
forther clarification all right and from
the Project's key stakeholders about the
potential for delays and scope
clarification reach out to the client
for clarification and Confirmation
adjust the timeline to accommodate
potential changes in the project scope
best answer here guys is going to be did
you get it C is correct why is that well
you should never really execute a
project or you should not do a project
if you don't understand the scope if you
don't know the scope of the project
you're setting yourself up for almost
guaranteed failure so you don't want
that so the best answer here guys is
going to be reach out for confirmation
because this can lead to delays
obviously pushing the project over for
scope delays potential time and cost
delays
so initi the other good answer is
initiate development based on
nonexistent if you do this you're
guaranteed to fail because you don't
have the right scope
clarification are you telling them about
potential for delays this was the second
best
answer before you do that let's see if
we can get it first then we we may want
to do that uh you can't just adjust
timeline especially on these types of
remember on an agile project technically
you have a fixed timeline on a
traditional project you need approval
for
that before I get to this question if
you're in enjoying this video give the
video a like subscribe to the Channel
136 upon noticing the primary technology
provider for a digital transformation
project will not meet the deadline for
delivering Essential Software component
a RIS previously noted to the provider
previously noted due to the providers
historical performance issue what should
you do next negotiate with alternative
technology vendors to ensure timely
delivery and update the financial plan
to reflect any changes report the
situation and potential impact of the
project steering committee for immediate
guidance consult the risk register with
the team organize a strategy session
with the project team to identify
variable Immediate Solutions all right
best answer here now there's two good
answers all right those two good answers
was C and D now you know this was this
was a risk that was previously noted so
where would the risk be it'll be in the
risk register with the actual mitigation
Str
strategy you don't want to just
negotiate with the vendor the moment the
vendor did something
bad right you notice will not meet so
this is guaranteed to happen so this is
going to become an issue where do you
find a solution to risk that has
previously been documented in the risk
register making that the best one um
report the situation not to the stering
committee you don't take things to the
stering committee especially project
problems that is under the control of
the PM the stering committee is more for
like choosing or approving a change they
may choose the direction of a project
but project issues that's your thing to
fix organize a session with the team you
don't need to do this yet the reason is
because you've already done it with the
team it should have been in your risk
register
137 discovering that one team member
feels their efforts are undervalued
compared to others leading to a decline
in the participation and the overall
team spirit what should the PM do to
mend the situation uplift the team
schedule individual performance reviews
to provide personal feedback and growth
plans all right conduct a project
Milestone cabor celebration to
acknowledge all team members
contribution equally highlight the
import the Highlight the Project's
Collective achievements emphasizing the
success is attributed to the team as a
whole not individual implement the peer
recognition program where team members
can acknowledge each other's
contribution best answer here this one
has a bunch of good answers by the way I
thought this one was pretty difficult
the best answer here guys is going to be
C now I know I know it says
inid it's one person right one team
member but notice the real question is
not just fixing that team member right
the real question
is uplift the team what that's the main
point of this question it's like okay
what do you want to do how can we uplift
the team well bring the team together
show them what they have done tell them
the success is due to all of them you
notice this guy feels under value
compared to others let them know right
he's why does he feel like that he feels
like some have done more maybe it was
she and she felt like some has done more
something like that let them know the
success isn't just to one person it's to
the entire team individual performance
review this was the other good answer
you could have gone
with this is feedback and growth plan
but it's the entire team right it notes
the overall team period so address the
team not just one
person conduct a milestone celebration
we're not sure if Milestones here is
what's going to help them uh a milestone
celebration to acknowledge all team
members we not not every project not
everyone contributes equally all right
some may contribute more some may do
more work than others it's I'm not
saying others are not important but some
people just do more work because that's
required of them Implement a peer
recognition this is given over let the
team members technology each other and
leaving you out don't do that never let
people solve problems by themselves work
with them to do
it
138 faced with a constrainted budget and
a tight deadline for launching a new
product development project the project
manager discovers that the current
Financial Resources will not suffice to
cover all the project all the uh project
activities all the projected activities
what should the project manager do next
propose a phased project approach to
stay holders focusing on critical
development phase first document the
financial shortfall in the project
status report highligh and potential
impacts on the timeline have the pmo
identify priority areas and allocate
budget to critical stages engage with
the team to explore options for re
reallocating budget items to cover key
tasks all right what are we going to be
doing best answer here guys is D now
here's what you notice you're faced with
a constrained budget and a deadline you
got to get this product out the door you
realize you got enough money to cover
each
activity what are we going to do here
well propose a phased approach to
stakeholders okay focus on critical
development I like that but you notice
this is something you're doing on your
own you're not engaging the team here
you're you're proposing this this option
you should engage your team D is just a
better answer than a if the team says to
do a maybe it's a good option but you
shouldn't choose that by yourself
document and Stat highlighting the
importance the the impact on it be you
don't know those potential impact yet
work with the team on this so you want
to do d d can lead to a or b or both
have the pmo don't bring the pmo work
with the team first before go into your
pmo pmo can provide guidance and
approvals and whatnot but with something
like this let your team work with you
always work with your team to solve
issues as part of the mindset
139 during a significant landscape
redesigned project the project manager
finds a cut ined irrigation system that
could that could drastically reduce
water usage and maintain costs
introducing the system would necessitate
a modest increase in both project budget
and timeline what should the project
manager take what should the project
maner take first assess the Project's
existing budget and
timeline initiate a pilot pilot project
with the current scope drafted detailed
analysis comparing the long-term savings
and environmental benefit of the new
system against the initial increase in
Project cost and timeline for
stakeholder review showcase the
compatibility of the new integration
system with the project sustainability
goals and Report finding to stakeholders
best answer here guys what are we going
to do now it's going to
be notice what should you do basically
basically what should you do first I
like this one there's two good answers Z
or
all right just don't you just don't want
to showcase it you have to assess its
impact on the project you shouldn't push
it out either unless you know how it's
going to impact the project assess the
the Project's existing
budget uh and timeline but it's not just
those two right you want to do a
detailed analysis long-term savings and
benefits of the new system against the
initial increase in cost so basically
assess how this thing is going to affect
the scope how it's going to affect the
increase in cost and time this one here
is a and C is basically saying almost
the same thing but C is giving you a
more detailed explanation making c a
better answer than a I know writing
these hard questions sometimes is
difficult a is not a bad answer I'm
telling you guys a is not a bad answer
just C is a better answer because in
this one you're looking at long-term
saving you're looking at environmental
benefits you're looking at how it's
going to increase cost how it's going to
increase time and then you're giving it
to the stakehold of a review versus just
ay it's just the budget and the timeline
you're really not looking at the
Environmental benefit is just more than
that right See's
better 140 during a critical phase of a
healthcare software implementation
project the project manager realizes
that the project team is struggling to
maintain Pace with rapid iterations and
frequent changes in Project requirements
indicating a need for better cohesion
and flexibility what two practices
should the project man Implement to
improve team performance and project
fluidity fluidity now a Foster a culture
of continuous dialogue and collaboration
amongst team memb Embrace a mindset of
flexibility and willingness to adapt the
project shift Implement regular
retrospectives to identify an act on
Improvement opportunities organize a
training session on agile methodologies
to enhance team understand schedule
brief daily check-ins to keep the team
aligned and informed love this question
to me this was the hardest of the 10
questions in this set by the way they
all sound great all right so we want but
let's focus on the thing you want better
cohesion and flexibility so we need the
keyword is flexibility and bringing them
together what two option does that
that's the answer that's the main point
of the question I'm not saying you
shouldn't do you should do c you should
do D probably want to do uh e also but
if you're looking for flexibility then
choose the answer that includes that let
them build that mindset of flexibility
and in order to bring people together
it's all about collaboration
so if you read the question carefully
the answers to the to the question was
literally in the
question um these here while they were
good they didn't get to the core of the
question retrospectives are not bad but
retrospectives are more of how to
improve the next Sprint not necessarily
to embrace
flexibility the training session that
may Embrace flexibility but it might not
do cohesion that that well daily uh
check-ins we do that on a day today
basis in agile that's really to look for
more issues best answers is a and b
let's get into our questions here all
right where's Mike pen here we go as a
project manager in charge of a new
sustainability initiative you have
introduced a groundbreaking
environmental monitoring system however
you notice that your project team is
hesitant to adapt this technology
leading to delays in the implementation
phase what is the most effective measure
to ensure team adaptation and project
progress we Implement a reward system
for early adapters of the technology
arrange for a series of brief
informative sessions on how the
technology contributes to project
goal conduct an extensive workshop with
the team that examines the technology
enlist the help of environmental expert
to explain the importance of the
technology to the team's work okay so
what are we going to be doing here you
have a team that is hesitant as you can
see here to adapt to the technology but
why are they hant maybe because they
just don't understand the technology so
one of the things you you don't want to
do on this exam is force something on
someone don't push things on the team
let show people why something is
important so first of all you don't
need uh a doesn't really work on this
question because it's the team that is
hesitant and you just don't want to just
push it on them which is kind of what a
is doing it's like okay it's a reward if
you guys do it but they're probably
going to be still hesitant you want to
you want to take the choice to remove
this word like how to remove them being
hesitant on it arrange for a series of
brief informed on how the technology
contributes to the project goal was the
other good
answer enlist the help of the
environment no you don't want to just go
outside work with the team first so it
was two good answers it was either B or
C here I was going on it now you notice
this one is how it contributes to the
project goal the best thing here we can
can do is have the team work with the
technology have them dis Discover it
themselves versus we telling them hey
this is going to align with the goal so
those were the two options should we let
them Discover it let them examine it and
let them find out for themselves or
should we just tell it to them if you're
saying hey it's best let them find out
they're going to better understand the
technology that's why C is going to be
better than
b 142 launching a project uh launching a
project to introduce a new Health Care
System across multiple clinics the
project manager realizes that there are
discrepancies between the project scope
and the latest project data protection
regulation while the Project's
leadership team advises proceeding as
planned anticipating that these
discrepancies will be dissolved in due
time the project manager is concerned
about potential compliance issues this
is something that's probably very
realistic in real life by the way what
is the most appropriate initial step for
the project manager conduct an in-depth
analysis of the health care of the
Health Data protection regulations and
outline a detailed compliance plan okay
initiate a risk assessment session to
evaluate the impact of potential
non-compliance on the project arrange a
consultation with a legal expert in the
health health data protection uh to
advise on compliance strategies
redesigned the project scope to include
only those elements currently in
compliance with existing regulations so
there was one answer you could have just
throw right out and it really came down
to three good answers I thought this was
a very difficult question here's what I
got let's see what you guys got now
first of all Which choice could you have
thrown out well you just can't just go
and just redesign a scope like that on a
project first of all if it's a
traditional project keep in mind on
traditional projects you need that
change management system you need to do
a change request you need to have a
change control board or sponsor review
it and on an adob project if you want to
change a scope you got to have the
product owner added to the product
backlog so at no point is a project
manager should be ever redesign it or
changing a scope without either the
sponsor or the product owner now this
one says arrange a consultation with
legal experts so you don't want to go
outside yet it's saying the initial step
right so this is the key word it's like
what should you be doing first so you
don't want to go outside yet you never
want to just go outside unless there's
really no other option try to do the
internally on the project now it came
down to two all right I really thought
is it going to be risk assessment
session to evaluate the impact or an
in-depth analysis of the data and come
up with a compliance plan well before we
do before you come up and you start
doing all your risk assessment you have
to conduct an in-depth plan what exactly
is this risk compliance so what you
should be doing is an in-depth analysis
of this particular regulation
that makes a better than b by the way I
want to point out something that by
doing a you're going to be doing B also
because when you do an in-depth analysis
and coming up with your compliance plan
you should be doing the risk assessment
in it making a a better
answer 143 at the beginning of a green
buildin project the project manager is
tasked by the lead architect to engage a
key supplier known for their sustainable
materials however the supplier is
reluctant to collaborate believing the
Project's environmental goals do not
align with their business model what
action should the project manager take
to encourage supplier participation
propose a trial period for the supplier
to assess the Project's commitment to
sustainability refer the matter to the
lead architect suggesting the need for
higher higher level negotiations
initiated a campaign to highlight the
project sustainability achievement and
future plans conduct a detailed
presentation for the supply outline and
the environment at impact and mutual
benefits okay this one here pretty
difficult really came down to two good
answers what answer did you get because
I got D to me is the best answer here
here's why now you notice this person
like the first question is
reluctant the other one in the first
question we had in this 141 they were
hesitant in this one this one they
they're reluctant they're like we don't
know why we should do this and you
notice it does not align with with their
business bus model so you have to help
prove that so the question is saying hey
this guy doesn't want to do it because
he doesn't feel that it aligns with
their business model so now you have to
go and prove that to them a trial period
is not going to prove that it aligns to
their business model this is them doing
it this is them doing it but they're not
really sure if they're align or not you
don't want to never give away your work
if this if there's a choice on your exam
that says give the work to someone it's
probably not the answer
a campaign to highlight the project
sustainability achievement well you know
what this is going to be their
achievement and future plans it doesn't
C does not really have anything to do
with the vendor by the way but D does
and D you're going to go to them you're
going to show them what's why this
particular thing is useful for the
project and the benefits that they're
going to get out of it makeing D the
best
answer 144 following a directive to
enhance operation efficiency within a
within a multinational corporation the
executive team has requested an update
on the progress and remain in TAS for
all ongoing ad job projects what
methodology should uh what methodology
should the project manager employ to
accurately convey this information time
tracking analysis resource allocation
report progress Milestone review or
Sprint burnup chart all right this one
here was actually pretty easy you notice
they want to see uh how much work is
left on remaining task and this uh the
burn
up chart does that now I do want to
point out that it the burn up chart is
use an agile because it represents the
work completed versus the work remaining
done so I want you guys to before you
walk into your exam room you're probably
going to get a questions on burn up and
burn down chart make sure you know the
difference we do cover those in the
class and you notice the moment we
saw that they were looking on agile
projects you should have known right
away burn up and burn down charts are
exclusive there time tracking analysis
is not something we use uh these are the
things are not something we use on adob
projects they're more likely used on
traditional
projects 145 during a complex software
development project the project manager
notes that several Technical and
operational challenges are arising due
to conflicting requirements from various
stakeholders what is the most efficient
strategy for the manager to facilitate
project advancement initiate a
stakeholder analysis to better
understand conflict interests and
address them systematically all
right assign a team assign team leaders
to negotiate solutions for each
conflicting re requirement directly with
the stakeholders all right update the
project communication plan to include
more frequent uh stakeholder engagement
sessions okay directly negotiate and
reconcile the conflicting requirements
to Streamlight project execution this is
a trick question don't go with the
answer you think you're going to go with
I'm telling you guys this is a trick
question
now these types of questions you have to
read them very carefully because if a
lot of you guys said a it's not right
here's why you see the question
specifically asked to fix this it's an
effective strategy to facilitate project
advancement so what strategy here is
going to allow the project to proceed
you see a is not a good answer because
in this one you're just trying to
understand their conflicts so in this
one you're understanding their conflicts
and you're trying to address them the
best way to address them is to negotiate
with them negotiate and reconcile the
actual differences between the project
making a a better answer than making d a
better answer than a never give away
anything never say okay hey you guys go
out and you guys do this update the
communication plan to include more
frequent stakeholder engagement it's not
something you can do without a change
request now I want to point out
something to you guys if this question
it says what should you do first what
should you do next then a would have
been a better answer than D but the
question isn't asking for what to do
first the question is literally asking
to fix the problem so I want you guys to
point out something if you're looking if
a question is like how do you fix this
you can't fix things things by examining
things if the question is what should
you do first well never fix things first
all right so you got to read it
carefully all right so let's let's let
let me say that again if a question says
what what's the next step what should
you do first then don't fix it right
away examine the situation analyze
what's happening around you read some
documents review your plans meet with
team members ask them what's going on
but if they're asking hey what which
which one of these choices will fix this
problem eliminate this problem well you
asking around you checking plans you
doing this is not going to fix or
eliminate the problem then you got to
come up with an actual concrete solution
to address the actual
problem all right 146 during the
integration phase of an international IT
project the project manager noticed
frequent miscommunications between the
on-site and offshore teams primly due to
cultural misunderstanding and language
nuisances the project manager has
individually spoken with members from
both teams and confirmed that these
differences are hindering project
progress all right this may be real life
for if you work on many uh International
projects what should the project manager
do to enhance understanding cooperation
between the teams Implement a technology
I'm sorry Implement a mandatory language
proficiency course for all team members
okay facilitate a workshop that allow
both teams to share the cultural norms
and communication preferences assign a
bilingual team liaison to translate
immediate communication require all
project communication to be
conducted in written form to reduce
misunderstanding best answer here guys
is of course B yeah this one wasn't too
difficult so if you have team members
that can't get along the best thing to
do we are we learn in the in our exam is
we have to make sure we train them
correctly uh we don't want anything
that's just mandatory we can't I don't
think people are going to learn an
entire language that
quickly require all Comm to be done in a
written sometimes best it's hard to do
written Communications if they're
actually communicating very
frequently uh you don't want to just
pass it on and if the liaison is not
there to translate might be a problem
the best thing here is to have them work
together as a project manager facilitate
facilitate facilitate bring people
together let them work together let them
discuss what's going on so the problem
is actually solved making B the best
answer 147 as part of a companywide
project to enhance it security the
project manager schedule a series of
educational webinars for employees a
leader from a department not yet covered
in the initial roll out expresses
interest in attending one of these early
sessions what should the project manager
do to best support the initiative's
goals and engage interested stakeholders
all right limited webinar attendance
only those Department schedule for early
phase roll up okay so suggest the
webinar leader wait for the tailored
sessions uh tailored session specific to
the department encourage Department to
join the upcoming we to get to get an
early insight and prepare their team
provide recorded versions of the webinar
exclusively to those in the initial roll
out phase all right now this question
plays on the concept of engaging your
stakeholders engage your stakeholders
how if you remember I say this in the
course often and early always remember
that often and early or I should say
early and often making see the best
answer here's why
so notice that this is a companywide
project and if you're scheduling a
series of educational webinars for
employees then who should you invite
right if you have a project that is
going to be affecting the entire company
means everybody's a stakeholder in this
project and you want to do a series of
educational thing about this then who
technically should you invite if you
said everyone because they're all your
stakeholders because you want to engage
all your Stak code is correct that's why
C is the answer you don't want to limit
it right off the bat you don't want to
tell them to wait uh previously recorded
versions while this is good maybe you
want to encourage them to come and if
they could great if not maybe then you
can do the making see the best answer
148 a project manager's tasked with
integrating Advanced artificial
intelligent features into an existent
software product however the current
project team lacks the AI expertise
required for successful implementation
what should the project manager do to
ensure the project success despite the
team's current skills
limitation initiated Target AI training
programs to the team okay partner with a
partner with an AI technology firm to
provide expert consultation facilitate
Workshop that in that innovates problem
solving
techniques deploy automated tools to
assist the team with AI related tasks
okay best answer here is going to be a
is correct now there were two good
answers here all right first of all you
don't want to just give away to work yet
let the team work and if they cannot
figure it out or we cannot get the right
training maybe then you can do B the
other one here you could have uh done
was d uh got rid of was D because you
don't want to just deploy to they don't
understand the technology you put in
more automation toolate just complex the
process more now you came down should
you facilitate workshops that encourages
problem solving techniques or should you
get in the right training now it it
tells you in the question they lack the
expertise so if they lack the expertise
them doing promise all is not going to
help them because they don't know how to
solve it in the first place the best
thing you can do when your team lacks a
particular knowledge that they don't
have the best thing to do the best thing
the project manager should do is get
them that
training by the way guys if you guys are
enjoying this can you give the video a
like click subscribe to the channel we
do spend a lot lot of time putting these
questions together and recording these
videos would be greatly
appreciated let's get back to it 149 a
project manager has coordinated a new
environmental research project involving
experts from various uh continents the
geographic geographical spread of the
team makes regular face-to-face uh
interactions impossible what should the
project manager do to ensure seamless
communication and collaboration across
the team now if you guys know me in the
class I always tell you guys face Toof
face is the best form of communication
adapt an Advan uh project management and
communication software okay set up
rotational schedule for team to adjust
their avability for occasional
synchronous meetings uh by the way
synchronous and asynchronous synchronous
communication is basically me talking to
you like on a zoom call or on a phone
call it's live it's real time
asynchronous is like what I'm doing here
this is asynchronous uh it's not real
time it's not
live create a cultural Exchange program
within team to facilitate better
understanding establish a system of
regular email updates and reports to
keep all team members informed best
answer here guys notice that we want the
question particularly points out this
thing of face-to-face communication and
if you can't do it if you can't do
face-to-face communication because of a
massive spread continent spread in
particular the best thing here to do is
to get the right technology to do it as
we have many options like Zoom or go to
meeting uh this here will solve the
problem because now they can have
seamless communication and consistent
not occasional communication we don't
need an exchange program as this may
take
time and you know what's better than
email this is asynchronous communication
synchronous communication is much better
all right so if you have good
communication software like Zoom that's
considered synchronous versus email is
asynchronous
communication
150 as the project manager for an
Innovative smart home device project you
receive a requests from the stakeholder
to incorporate Advanced AI capabilities
into capabilities to improve design
usability the addition is expected to
significantly enhance the product but
comes late in the cycle with a
challenging deadline all right so this
might delay the project here guys what
should the project manager do
next conduct an impact analysis to
determine how the integration of the
advanced AI capabilities affects the
timeline of budget okay suggest focusing
on launching the current version without
Ai and adding it as a feature in the
next product release okay uh increase
the team's working hours to meet the
demand of inte of integrating the new
feature within the timeline negotiate
for additional resource specifically
focus on developing and integrating the
function now I want to point out that
you notice this particular question says
what should we do next and if you
remember what I said earlier what should
you do next is going to be to analyze
something don't fix the prod problem yet
analyze something how is this going to
affect the project not just the timeline
but I want to point out that when you
affect time you're probably going to
affect cost making a the best answer you
shouldn't just add it
in uh or just reject it so B is like hey
just rejected we'll do that later never
do that to a customer never overwork
your team negotiate for additional
resources before you do that I would say
you would do a then B
um if the question was like Hey how do
you fix this what are we going to do to
fix this maybe then you might need more
resources to get it done but in this one
here they're asking what should you do
next in other words assess the situation
all right question
151 a project manager is leading the
development of a new Public Library
during the planning phase it come it
comes to light that the library's
proposed location is a popular site for
an annual book fair which was not
considered in the initial consultations
the oversight Rises concern about the
fear's future on libraries uh community
relations what should the project
manager do to ensure the project aligns
with Community interest and maintains
positive relations a redesign the
library layout to include a dedicated
space for the annual book fear without
additional speaker input organize a
discussion for with book organizers and
community members to explore how the
library project can accommodate the fear
prepare a risk management plan
specifically for mitigating the backlash
from the book fear enthusiasts suggest
relocating the book fear to a less
Central but still accessible location
without consulting the event organizers
this question plays the game of engaging
stakeholders a project manager should
not be modifying or editing the scope
without consulting your stakeholders and
that makes it one good answer which is B
here's why you see in a you're you as
the project manager you're just
redesigning the space just like that
without their input so is D you're just
moving things you're doing things
without cons Consulting the event
organizers no what you want to do is you
want to bring your stakeholders together
so they can work together and come up
with a scope or a solution that best
matches their requirements prepare risk
management plan in this one you're doing
nothing in this one you're basically
proceeding and you're saying well if
there's a backlash will deal with it at
some point so in this one here you're
taking no actions not the best answer
our best answer here is going to be
B 152 as the project manager for a
software development project you're
informed that due to budget relocations
reallocations several developers will be
reassigned to other projects create an
unease amount to your team about project
timelines and their roles what should
the project manager do
first Implement a Revis project schedule
that accelerates timelines to
demonstrate the project can proceed
without additional
resources facilitate a
discussion facilitate a session to
discuss the reassignments emphasizing
the Strategic vision and how team
contributions are critical to both the
project and broader company
objectives introduce a mentorship
program parent remaining team members
with experience mentors to bolster
confidence and set skills set and skill
sets in h in light of reduced staff and
levels sorry guys a lot of big words
here launch a cross training initiatives
to diversify the skill sets of remaining
team members ensuring the Project's
critical functions are covered now this
is pretty common especially on today's
world where all of a sudden they may cut
cut budgets or reduce your budgets and
other team members or particularly good
team members may have to be reassigned
to other projects what do you do well
you notice this question is what do you
do first and one of the first things you
do is to assess the
situation understand what's happening in
in light of what's budget cuts or people
leave and things like that notice b c
and d takes an action in this one you
shouldn't just revise a schedule like
that that will requires generally some
kind of change
request this is a mentorship program
this is a cross trining program in these
here
you're probably going to do these later
I would do B let's understand let's do a
discussion to understand what these
reassignment means how it affects the
projects how it affects the company's
objective let's do that first maybe then
we can do a mentorship program and and
or a cross trainining program so
remember on this exam watch that keyword
what should you do first what should you
do
next 153 during the implementation phase
of a Citywide public transportation
Improvement project a city council
member requests A specialized update
that goes beyond the scope of regular
briefing provided to the public and City
officials okay the team utilizes
Advanced so uh simulation software and
traffic flow analysis to plan and
monitor progress what should the project
manager
do provide a tutorial on how to
interpret the simulation software
results
invite the council member to workshop on
traffic flow analysis techniques using
the project engage directly with the
council member to clarify what specific
Data Insights are
needed compile a comprehensive report
using data from both simulation software
and traffic
analysis okay best answer here guys is
going to be by before I give it to you
remember what do you do next what do you
do first is going to help determine the
the answer of
C you see before taking this action
before giving them something meet with
them ask them when do you want it how
how would you like it in like what
format who should be giving it to
you um what time of day in what setting
would you like to get this basically
you're building that communication
management plan you notice a b
and D is giving them the data in a what
are you doing you're giving them a
tutorial you're telling them to come to
the workshop you're telling you're
giving them a report in this one here
let's clarify exactly what they want no
pinpoint the specific of what they want
and then you can better then you can
better give them what they want so first
clarify what they need 154 following a
critical review session of healthcare
software project a project manager notes
that the output of one software engineer
is not up to the project standards while
what is the most appropriate form of
communication for the project manager to
utilize in addressing the software
engineer performance
concerns send a group email highlighting
the importance of meeting project
standards without naming
individuals schedule a one-on-one
meeting to discuss the performance
issues and development plan all right
issue a formal performance Improvement
plan through the company's HR System
okay initiate a team-wide meeting to
discuss project
standards and individual contributions
collectively all right best answer here
guys is did you guys get that 101 here's
why anytime you have a problem on a
project where it deals with one person a
stakeholder a senior manager a sponsor a
team member it's just one person this
person is causing chaos this person
needs more information this person has
particular concerns the best thing to do
is don't do it in front of people deal
with that person right
on so what are we going to do we're
going to schedule a one-onone meeting
we're going to discuss the performance
issues and come up with a plan of how to
fix it we don't want to do this in a in
a group setting it's one person one
person that's having some of the
problems so the best way to deal with
this one person is going to be to ensure
that you meet with this person see what
the problem is and solve it instead of
bringing the team all in it so remember
that tip for your
test 155 leader in a software
development ad out project for a
multinational corporation a project
manager faces the challenge of managing
a team spread across multiple time zones
common nowadays right guys the project
manager has previously encountered
issues with such teams regarding
inconsistent work
quality and miss deadline what action
should the project manager take to
ensure high quality
deliverables and adherence to the
timeline initiative frequent virtual
stand-ups to clarify project goals
synchronize team efforts and address any
issues okay develop a comprehensive
trainer program on time management and
productivity tools distribute a detailed
weekly template for members to fill out
summarizing their progress organize a
quarterly in-person Meetup for team
building and detailed project reviews
best answer here guys is going to be a
this is correct first of all you should
be doing a virtual standup meetings on a
daily basis this is an adob project um I
wouldn't do weekly or quarterly because
quarterly may be too long maybe too far
apart
weekly may or may not be too long or Too
Short apart from from from their updates
but as a as an adob project the best
answer here is to do a standup meeting
you should be doing that anyhow notice a
training on time management this is a
decent answer I thought a and Bs were a
good answer and productivity tools for
all members but the best thing here is
just to fix the problem right what you
want to do is you want to make sure that
everybody understands their goals here
and the best answer is to do a frequent
daily standup meeting best answer was a
156 a project manager is tasked with
launching a new drug product which
requires adherence to strent health and
safety regulations it's crtical it's
critical for the launch to comply with
these regulations to avoid penalties and
ensure Public Safety what should the
project manager do next to guarantee
compliance with these regulations
arrange for regular training sessions on
Regulatory Compliance with the team all
right assess and document the potential
compliance risk related to health and
safety okay Implement a quality control
system to continuously monitor the
product against safety standard organize
a consultation with legal experts
specialized in regulations to review
project alignment this was a tough
question almost all of these answers
were pretty much correct best answer
here is going to be to assess it that's
correct notice what should you do
next assess and document potential
compliance risk that's the next thing
you want to do here
uh
notice you want to make sure that you
stay to it it's critical to comply well
what happens if you don't comply because
you want to avoid these penalties right
and ensure Public Safety what should you
be
doing well the best thing here is to
document potential compliance risk
related to safety put that in the plan
because it's from looking at the risks
then you can understand okay this is how
it can affect the schedule this is how
it can affect Public Safety this is how
it can affect the budget this is how it
can affect the scope uh arrange for
regular training let's do B then a so
we'll do remember it's what should you
do
next organize a consultation with legal
experts so let's understand how it
affects the project first Implement a
quality control this is something you're
going to implement later on not right
now best answer was
B
157 during the critical testing phase of
an Enterprise software upgrade the
project manager ident ifies that testing
is significantly behind schedule posing
a risk to the planned go live date what
should the project manager do first now
you notice the project this year
identified testing is significantly
behind what should you do escalate to
the company's executive management all
right conduct a detailed session with
the team to pinpoint causes for the
delay all right seek additional funding
to contract external testing services to
catch up Implement overtime hours for
the testing team this one here if you
follow along what I was saying uh at the
beginning of this video what you do
first don't take an action right away
let's go ahead and do a detail session
with the team let's go in there and uh
pinpoint what's causing this delay and
then we can go ahead and fix it you
never want to escalate project problems
especially to Senior Management the
company's executive management is there
to make decisions not to help you manage
your
project seek additional funding not yet
understand how it affects the project
don't Implement overtime one of the
things we want to resist on this exam is
implementation of overtime or
implementing overtime can overwork your
team members causing a significant drop
in productivity and overall quality of
deliverables
158 during the construction phase of a
new city park conflicts have emerged
between the landscape designers and
environmental consultant over the choice
of plant species and their environmental
impact what are the two most effective
actions for the project manager to take
to take first to resolve these conflicts
select
two delay any decisions on plant species
until further research can be conducted
okay organize individual meetings with
landscape designers and environmental
Consultants to understand each group's
concern initiate a workshop at all
stakeholders to democratically vote on
the species election escalate the
solution the issue to the city council
for final decision to avoid further
delay conduct private Target discussions
with key representative from both sides
to find a middle ground all right what
answers did you get the best answer here
I have is going to be B you want to
bring them together right you want to
understand what's going on so the first
thing I want to
do is let's do individual meetings with
the designers let's understand what's
going on understand their concerns
then what we want to do is we want to
conduct private targeted discussions
with the representative from both sides
to find that middle ground so in the
first one you meet them you meet you
meet the designers you meet the
Consultants then the next thing you
bring them together and see if there's a
middle ground hopefully we can solve the
problem you don't want to escalate it
not yet all right you don't want to
escalate this you have to try to solve
the problem now before you do a workshop
to vote on the pl species understand is
there a middle ground and never delay
anything delay any decision until
further research can be done no let's
work together and fix it just don't push
it off don't kick the can down the road
is what I generally say when answering
if you ever see a choice that looks like
it's going to kick the can down the road
it's probably not the
answer
159 during a critical software
implementation project the project
manager identifies a significant
slowdown in the integration phase
attributed to the team's unfamiliar
unfamiliarity with the new software's
API this issue threatens to delay
project Milestones what should the
project manager do first to address the
team's skill Gap without Rising the
budget initiate a collaborative problem
solving medum to identify Alternatives
integration strategies or Solutions okay
delegate the integration task to more
experienced team within the organization
reducing the learning curve all right
invest in FastTrack external training
program specifically focus on the new
software's API hire an external
consultant with expertise in s in the
software to lead the integration phase
and TR trainer team read the question
carefully you notice I highlight
this without Rising the budget so that
means you could have eliminated two
choices right you this here will
definitely rise the budget this here
will rise the budget and this here gives
away the work right so B gives away the
work the best thing here the best answer
all it's not the greatest answer ever
the best answer here is there any
alternative integration strategies or
Solutions we can go with we don't have
much choice because we cannot rise the
budget as for the question making a the
best
answer did you guys enjoy this video if
you did give this video a like subscribe
to the channel 160 during the planning
of a new development project a recently
enacted zoner Law changes the permis
building
the the permissible building Heights
within the Project's area the project
team has been informed of this change
what is the most effective course of
action for the project manager to take
proceed with planning until the legal
department informs you to update the
Plan update the project documentation to
reflect change in zonal laws impact on
the scope okay schedule a meeting with
local government officials to seek
exceptions uh for the current project
consult with legal councel and on
understand the implementation of Z Z and
law change on the project best answer
here this is a trick question by the way
best answer here guys is going to be B
why is
that well let's put it to you guys this
way they're still in
Planet I want to point that out they're
still in Planet and once you're in
planning you don't need a change request
to update the scope or anything like
that and if something is a law you have
to do it notice this isn't an active law
by not doing it you're breaking the law
making this a better answer proceed with
planning until the no you already know
the plan has to
change uh you don't need an ex exception
because it's a law now the other good
answer was D consult with legal counsel
understand uh this thing on on the zone
and law change to the project well you
already know that the height cannot be
done so you already know the impact of
it so now you just need to reassess your
plan um notice document the changes and
it document the impact on the entire
thing one of the things you have to
remember about law is if something is a
law you have to get it done it can be
the best answer and first question up in
the late stages of marketing launching a
marketing campaign project it's
identified that a critical piece of
content is not ready because a team
member fell behind schedule this issue
came to light during a presentation to
the marketing department causing concern
about launching about meeting the launch
date what should should what action
should the project manager do first have
a confidential discussion with the team
member to understand the reasons for the
delay and explore Solutions together all
right delegate the unfinished task to
another team member who has the capacity
to expedite completion all right
organize a session for the team to
collaboratively brainstorm ways to
expedite the remaining work seek advice
from a senior manager on how to handle
the team member's delay in task
completion now I want to point out to
you that anytime you get a question
where there's one person that may be
causing an issue one person delaying the
project one person wants something one
person uh callus on a commotion on the
project the best thing to do is to meet
with that
person and find out what the problem is
and how we can fix
it when somebody when somebody's causing
a problem and I'm talking one person or
maybe even a small group deal deal with
that person privately individually is
the way to do that don't push it out in
the group and embarrass people or cause
a bigger problem now one choice you guys
should have eliminated right off the bat
was senior manager senior manager is not
there to solve problems on your project
that's what they hire you for so let's
eliminate that one before you organize a
session to fix this issue right now or
assign someone to fix it the best thing
to do is to meet with this person and
see if you guys can work together to fix
it best answer was
a 162
the project manager for a renewable
energy initiative receives a suggestion
from an environmental consultant to
incorporate a new technology that can
improve project outcomes but also extend
the timelines and increase costs what
should you do first forward the
suggestions forward the suggestion to
the Project's CCB by the way this means
change control board for approval before
I go on I want to point out that on the
exam generally when they give you an
acronym they probably spell it out for
you you don't have to memorize acronyms
on your test generally speaking except
those formal acronyms those evm acronyms
you should know
those arrange a project team me in to
discuss the feasibility and implications
of integrating the new technology
consult with industry experts to gauge
the potential benefits and drawback con
uh conduct a preliminary risk analysis
to understand how the new technology
might affect the project risk best
answer here guys now before I give you
the answer I want to point out that
remember it's a suggestion from an
environmental consultant it may be good
it may be bad the best thing we can
do is to have the team come in and tell
us if this is a good or a bad idea
always utilize the expertise of the team
that's what they're there for so what we
want to do is you want to meet with the
team and we want to say hey what do you
guys think is this good how is this
going to affect the project they're the
expert not us you can't send it to the
Change Control Board for approval if you
haven't see how it's going to how it's
going to affect the project how much is
it going to extend that deadline how
much is it going to extend that
budget before going to Industry experts
remember what to do first we want to
meet with the team first and to do this
risk assessment your team should help
you uh your the team should help you
before you do a risk assessment and the
team should help you do a risk
assessment don't forget all changes must
be assessed before it can be approved by
CCB
163 in the midst of a renewable energy
project a team member notices a
significant risk related to equipment
procurement that could potentially D
derail the project timeline the concern
is promptly communicated to the project
sponsor who then request the project
manager for a detail assessment and
action plan all right which a document
should a project manager consult with
the team to outline predefined
approaches to assist to address this
procurement risk appropriately risk
register issue log risk respon strategy
and risk management plan so the question
is
asking basically what
document has predefined approaches to
risks did you get it best answer here
was risk register is correct the risk
register has the risk and the potential
responses to the risk this is a risk
this is not an issue so it does not
belong to issue log there really is no
such thing as a risk response strategy
that's actually in the that's there's no
such document like that the strategy is
in the risk
register the risk management plan
doesn't actually have risk or risk
responses making a the best
answer 164 in finalizing an
infrastructure upgrade project the
project manager needs to ensure that all
critical operation knowledge has been
transferred to the clients to the
client's maintenance
team efficiently or effectively what
approach should the project maner your
employee to confirm the thoroughness of
the knowledge transfer schedule
face-to-face sessions with the
maintenance team members and the project
team to validate understand and
application of operational knowledge
okay develop and administer a formal
assessment to the maintenance team on a
key operational procedure create an
interactive online module for the
maintenance team to complete uh covering
all necessary operational information
facilitate a Roundtable discussion with
key project and maintenance team members
to evaluate the depth of knowledge
transfer all right you want to uh let's
take a look at the question here uh what
approach to employ to confirm the
thoroughness of the knowledge transfer
this is the key here you want to confirm
that it was thoroughly done best answer
here guys is going to be a if you got a
you are correct one thing I do mention
in the course is anytime you see that
word face Toof face communication it's
probably good answer to choose
face-to-face communication is one of the
best ways and the richest way to
communicate
and I think face to-face communication
here just trumps or or is better than an
interactive online module or some kind
of formal
assessment uh the best thing here is to
have face tof face discussion let them
talk and let them validate your
understanding so they can both talk to
each other and see hey do you understand
this do you understand it's better than
that the other one here was more of a
round table but I think this face Toof
face is is better uh than actually just
going going through a round table
question 165 in a software development
project the project manager notices that
the various project teams have different
priorities and methodologies leading to
inconsistencies and delays in Project
Milestones the project manager realizes
the need for a unified approach to
streamline processes and improve
collaboration amongst the
team what is the most effective course
of action for the project manager to
ensure consistent progress across all
teams Implement a centralized project
management tool to enhance communication
and task tracking all right conduct a
workshop to align all teams on the
project objectives and establish a
shared methodology okay assign a liazon
from each team to facilitate better
understanding and integration of work
practices real uh reallocate project
resources to prioritize task according
to urgency and importance of the project
milestone
okay what did you guys get we have a
problem here what's the problem teams
having different priorities and
different methodologies this is what's
causing the problem you got to select
the answer that deals directly with this
and the best answer here is going to be
to bring them all
together make sure that the the choices
is going to deal with solving this
problem right this whole problem of
different priorities
and especially
methodologies one of the things we have
to do when we do this exam is you have
to read that question
carefully and say to yourself does that
answer actually solves the question
because you're going to have multiple
answers that sounds great but only one
of them may actually solve the problem
and this one does because if you notice
it establishes a shared methodology and
that's what we want a shared methodology
would lead to consistency right right
now to have inconsistency
ancies a centralized project management
tool is you choosing for them let the
team choose not you choosing for them in
all the other choices you're choosing so
is C you're saying hey let's do a
liaison between them now the entire
teams are not there reallocate project
resources to prioritize tasks now you're
doing it for them don't do that let the
team
choose next
question
166 while implementing an ER r p
enterprise resource planning the agile
project manager received several
requests for additional features from
department heads potentially affecting
the project scope and timeline what
should the project manager do to address
these feature requests efficiently or
effectively uh direct the department
heads to submit their request after the
Erp goes live all right have the product
owner integrate the feature request into
the product backlog for
prioritization Asa advise the Department
of Health that all project changes are
Frozen to avoid deviations from the plan
schedule request detailed business case
for each feature to assess the impact
before adding them to the product
project
plan so I want you guys to know that the
agile it's clearly states this this is
an agile project and somebody wants to
add something to Agile not difficult if
you understand AG practices because
there's one thing we know the only
person that can add something to the
scope put a project on an ad job project
is who is the correct the product owner
only the product owner can add features
to the product backlog and then
prioritize it not the department heads
needs to work with the product owner you
don't stop changes on an adob project
they never stop and you don't need a
detailed business case for each one
that's something between the product
owners and the uh people asking for
people asking for the
changes 167 in the implementation stage
of a critical network security project
it is revealed that a specialist
responsible for key parts of the
configuration will be taken emergency
leave what should the project manager do
to address this specialist absence
imminent absence and keep the project on
schedule facilitate a discussion with
the project team to redistribute the
specialist
responsibilities efficient effectively
uh efficiently among existing members
suggest pausing the project until the
specialist can return and resume their
duties contract an external consultant
firm to Temporary fill the specialist
role request an immediate extension of
the project deadline to accommodate the
delay all right somebody's leaving the
best thing here to do guys is meet with
the team and see how put up a discussion
and see hey can we spread this
responsibilities amst each other this is
what this is how you can do this really
quickly and just try to keep the project
on
schedule because it's saying that he
plays you know this person leaving plays
a key part in the configuration but
we'll be taking emergency leave work
with the team if the team tells you that
they need an additional person maybe
then you can go out and get a consultant
firm to give you someone I wouldn't
pause the project like that if the team
said it's okay
then I wouldn't ask for an extension if
the team says so then but let's see if
the the team can deal with this if you
notice you know we've been doing a lot
of questions 167 of them if you notice
the team has the power on the project
the team knows better they're the
experts next question 168 nearing the
completion of an extensive software
development project it is noticed that
one developers innovative solutions have
greatly enhanced the project outcome uh
distinguishing their contribution from
the rest of the team what is the most
appropriate way for the project manager
to acknowledge this outstanding
contribution create a feature in the
company newsletter highlighting the
developers Innovative work all right
organize a casual team lunch where
developers efforts can be uh informally
recognized by peers all right submit a
recommendation for the developer to be
considered for the prestigious industry
award I like that one that's a good one
identify a form of recognition that
aligns with the developers value most
whether it be professional development
opportunity specific for a or something
personal the best thing here guys if you
find that someone is doing a great job
and you want to award them the best
thing to do is to talk to them ask them
what do you think is the best way to
award you we like you and we want to
give you something what would be best so
work with them you notice in this one in
c b and a you're choosing the way to
acknowledge their
contribution right you you're choosing
the acknowledgement you're choosing the
method of acknowledgement the best way
is to work with the team member to let
them
choose as a project manager for 169 as a
project manager for a novel online
educational platform you're face with
different views Divergent views among
stakeholders regarding the balance
between interactive content and
accessibility features the development
team is split on uh which aspects to
prioritize potentially affecting the
project timeline what action should the
project manager take to navigate this
impath effic
effectively deploy conf deploy conflict
resolution method technique specifically
designed to address and navigate the
diverse viewpoints into a unified
strategy okay conduct a poll with the
team and among stakeholders to
democratically decide the Project's
Focus area facilitate discussion
facilitate a focus group discussion
leverages is design in principles to
Foster Innovative solution choose the
best solution all right suggest the team
separately debates and reaches a
consensus without managerial
intervention this one here has two good
answers let me see what you guys
got best answer was a here's why first
of all before we answer this it's
basically have different view amounts
the stakeholders you want to balance
this interactive method and the
accessibility
feature team is split what are we going
to do here guys well you don't want to
just do a poll amounts the stakeholders
because uh you might have to sometimes
software development these features
might be needed by law so you might have
to include them um don't just tell the
team to go and figure it out themselves
never tell the team to go figure it out
themselves it's part of your job to work
with the team now this one here you
notice that the team is split all right
on this how are you going to do it well
there's lots of different conflict
resolution techniques you can use and
because there are different views
amongst the people you're going to have
to work you're going to have to use
these techniques to manage the different
views into one strategy so the project
can progress this one here is more of a
design principle to come up with
innovative solutions although that
sounds great the best answer here is
going to be the company unified strategy
remember the project can't move on if if
we don't come up with a unified strategy
make it a better than
C last question
170 halfway through a critical website
development project it is revealed
during a Sprint review that an
unforeseen technical hurdle could
potentially delay the Project's
completion this Revelation came as a
surprise especially considering the
project manager prior weekly updates
indicated that the project was
proceeding according to
plan what could have been been done
differently to avoid being caught offu
by such a critical issue establish a
robust risk man risk management process
to identify monitor potential technical
challenges to our project all right
schedule mids Sprint reviews to assess
Pro uh progress and uncover hidden risk
before the escalate conduct regular
one-on-one meetings with the team to
identify potential risk that might not
surface in the group set all right use
project management tool to track
progress and flag potential risk based
on the time deviation
okay so I want you just to review this
question it says here it is revealed
that during a Sprint review on
foreseeing technical could potenti so we
know that this is a
risk right because this is something
that can stop it the best answer now
again this is a risk when you're
managing risk what should you be doing
all right in order to manage risk well
remember you want to do something to
avoid this from ever happening you know
what's going to avoid this from
happening manage risk throughout the
project correct risk is not something
that you may want to
do uh mid-print it's not something that
you're going to want to do maybe weekly
it's something that you're going to do
throughout the project every day every
minute every second of a project you're
doing risk assessment identify and
assess and risk because remember risk
happens all the time making this a lot
better answer one-on-one meetings I like
one-on-one meetings but risk management
risk assessment risk identification
should be done as a team not just just
as 101 we don't need a tool for this we
need everybody to work with it making a
the best answer question
171 as a project manager overseeing the
roll out of a new online banking
platform ensuring that customers can
seemlessly transition and utilize a
platform is
critical the project sponsor emphasizes
the importance of excellent customer
support following the launch what action
should the project manager take to
fulfill this requirement coordinate with
the customer service department to
extend their hours in the weeks
following the launch okay initiate a
temporary dedicated hotline for new
platform inquiries and issues all right
set up a series of self-paced webinars
for customers focusing on platform
features and common troubleshooting step
okay create a comprehensive online help
center that includes tutorial videos
searchable knowledge base and options
for Live support our this question is is
a tricky question right because it says
here that you want to ensure that
customers can seamlessly
transition uh and the importance of
excellent customer support the point of
this question was when you're dealing
with a lots of lots of different
stakeholders and you might not be able
to uh assess all their needs the best
thing here to do is to give them as much
options as possible you notice D talks
about tutorial videos knowledge based
and Live support versus this is more of
just a self-pace webinar this one here
is just a dedicated
hotline and this one is just keeping the
branches open longer the best thing here
to do would be to give as much options
to satisfy as many of those stakeholders
as you
could
172 at the at the outset of an
initiative to introduce Smart City
Technologies it is discovered that the
input from a CR from a crucial
environmental expert was not included
during the preliminary discussions on
the Project's environmental impact
assessment what document is most likely
in need of revision due to this
submission stakehold register engagement
plan project schedule or the
communication plan all right best answer
here guys is going to be the stakeholder
register here's why I want to point out
something you notice that the input from
this crucial environmental expert was
never gotten that means that this person
was probably not even identified keep in
mind that the stakeholder register has a
listing of all your
stakeholders and how they're going to
impact the project and what how they're
going to impact the project how the
project is going to impact them that's
in the stakeholder register so you would
need to know this before you even got
out before you went out and got their
opinion or got their statement the
engagement PL comes after the register
this is how you plan to engage with them
we never even know the existed the
project schedule is has nothing to do
with stakeholders the communication is
how we plan to communicate with them but
we didn't even know they exist because
we never even got their
input best answer stakeholder
register
173 just assigned to lead a new
technology integration project the
project manager Lawrence that no
foundational documentation exist leaving
the team uncertain about scope
deliverables and timeline what action
should the project manager take to
establish a solid solid
foundation initiate the project uh by
focusing on highle tasks and develop
documentation as these tasks progress
right instruct Department helps to
comply to respective sections of the
project documentation to streamline lock
in Industry standard project management
templates to quickly draft the necessary
documents engage the entire team in a
com comprehensive planning session to
collaboratively develop all critical
project management documents best answer
here now I want to point out I did
Circle this here I shouldn't have done
that because that makes it easier right
because in order to have the best
success on a project you must make sure
you have all the documents and you want
to engage your team while building these
documents
notice you can't just really go and do a
project if you do something that's like
high level you want to engage the team
the best answer here why this is one of
the best ansers because it engages the
team let the team help you let those
experts help you instruct departmental
heads know the project manager deals
with this templates are great I like
templates but you want to engage the
team here to help you build the plan
itself it can the best
answer 174 to enhance project
communication and address emerging
issues a project manager organizes by
weekly meetings with the development
team of a software project what should
the project manager prioritize at the
beginning of these meetings detail the
current status of the project schedule
and any deviations meet an agenda times
and topics to cover
reevaluate the scope in light of recent
developments gather feedback for
continuous Improvement now the first
thing you're going to do when you do a
meeting is what you guys should got this
what should prioritize at the beginning
of these meetings right beginning of
every meeting you guys should do what
talk about what you're going to be
covering how long uh and the topics to
go over that's the best
answer then later on in the meeting
you'll talk about schedule reevaluating
the scope if needed gather feedback
continuous Improvement these are all
things are going to cover in the meeting
but at the beginning of the meeting tell
people what this meeting is and the
times on the meeting that way the
meeting doesn't waste too too much
time
175 in the midst of executing a high
stake software development project
several unexpected software bugs and
team miscommunications have led to
delays causing tension within the team
and concern from the sponsor about
meeting key deliverable on time what
should the project manager do to
alleviate these issues and steer the
project back on
track conduct team building events focus
on enhancing team collaboration and open
communication okay host a problem
solving Workshop where team members can
collaborative identify solutions to
technical issues all right I like that
increase the frequency of progress
review meetings to closely monitor team
performance and progress H arrange for a
professional mediator to address and
resolve interpersonal conflict with in
the team I can eliminate one choice
right off the
bat but the others are pretty good let's
see what you got here's what I got the
one I could have eliminated right off
the bat was this one you are this person
you shouldn't hire a professional person
that's you let's get rid of that choice
I really lik to B and um see not so much
so let's let's get R to see the
frequency of the progress can increase
the frequency of progress meetings
they're not getting along here they
might this might lead to them not
getting along even
more now host problem solving where
teams can collaboratively identify
solutions to but this is to technical
issues that's not all of it notice
several unexpected software bugs and
team
miscommunication have led to delays and
concern so it's not just the software
bugs because this is technical it's also
miscommunication the best thing here is
to focus on their collaboration and open
communication this here can lead to less
miscommunication and hopefully leads to
fixing technical things always on this
exam it's not a technical exam try to be
a project manager that works with the
team in a way that is all about open
Communications and everybody can talk
anybody can get along just don't try to
fix one thing like technical issues I'm
pretty sure if you have open
Communications you're going to fix the
miscommunications and the technical
issues
176 during a key phase of an
infrastructure project the project
manager notices the notices a
significant slowdown and decision making
due to their need to approve numerous
minor project adjustments this has
started to impact the Project's momentum
as the project manager schedule is
dominated by stakeholder
meetings What in itive should the
project manager introduce to improve
decision-making
process organize weekly Roundup sessions
to address all accumulated decisions in
one go Implement a critical path
analysis to ENT to pinpoint decision
making as the the primary project delay
assign decision- making responsibility
for specific areas to trusted project
leads make all decisions to ensure it's
done in a timely
manner okay one choice here you can
eliminate the rest of this is a toss up
in the air in my opinion let's see what
you guys got here's what I got all
right let's go through these answers
this one here you got to eliminate
because this is the problem right here D
is not doing anything D is just saying
okay let's continue doing it you notice
the project might noce significant
slowdown due to the need to approve
numerous D is the same thing D is
basically say you just keep doing it so
we don't want that organize a weekly
we're not sure if weekly is
enough all right to address all the and
if you have to make these decisions it
might become a problem because in this
one you're going to be making them at
once a week and then teams might be
waiting what if they need a decision
Monday and you only do it on
Fridays a critical path well this one
here is not going to solve the problem
all right this is not this is going to
tell us where the delay is we don't need
to do this we already know where the
delay is it's in those decision making
the best here we can do is pass off some
of the
smaller right notice it says significant
slowdown due to numerous
minor right approve of these Minor
Adjustments give that over to the team
and Trust the team is going to do a good
job with them they can see the best
answer
177 in the midst of a complex IT project
feedback from an executive sponsor
indicates dissatisfaction with the
detailing nature of the project updates
which they find cumbersome and
distracting from Key insights what
measure should the project manager
Implement to refine the communication
process with the executive
sponsor transition to a streamline
weekly email summary highlighting
critical points and decisions needed all
right utilize a project management tool
that allows a sponsor to view realtime
updates that they're convenient okay uh
conduct a detailed discussion with a
sponsor identify their preference for
information and Report format
okay scheduled brief Focus update calls
with sponsor to review major milestones
and address any concern this one not too
difficult here's what if you notice in
this question the sponsor basically this
satisfaction with the project updates
the best thing here you can do is meet
with them and ask them what is it that
you want when do you want it how do you
want it who should send it to you in
what format do you want it in notice in
this one you're choosing for them you're
choosing for them and you're choosing
for them you know one of the tips I'm
going to give you guys to this test
is if you find choices are all the same
if you find like two choices that pretty
much doing the same thing it's probably
not the answer because you can only
choose one unless the question says
choose two of those in this one here
we're working with sponsorer we're
tailoring the communication to the
sponsorer preference Mak can C the best
answer
178 during an iterative development
project for a new software tool a
developer who was recently added to the
team suggests implementing a cut and
cutand Edge testing technique that diff
significantly from the project standard
practices the rest the rest of the team
has expressed reluctance to to deviate
from n methods what should the project
manager do to address the teams
reluctance and explore the potential of
the new method instruct the new
developer to maintain the status quo to
preserve team Harmony and project uh
Pace maybe assign the developer to less
critical task to avoid any potential
disruptions to the established
testing okay I'm not sure that I'm not
sure about that one facilitate a
discussion where the new developer can
present the proposed tesed method
detailing its advantages and imple and
implementation process all right
recommend the developer prepare a detail
report on the proposed method for review
at the Project's conclusion best answer
here guys is going to be that's right
don't shut the person down okay first of
all if you do
a you're telling developer hey I don't
want to hear you we're going to continue
doing this you have to do it our way
don't do that you see anytime people
want to change the world somebody comes
up with some crazy new idea the rest of
the world or majority of the world says
hey that's crazy we don't want to do
that but until that person proves it
they're probably going to get a lot of
push back even though it was an amazing
thing so in this one you don't want to
just tell the person
no and B I said hey I don't know about
that one because you're basically firing
the person from the task don't fire
anyone now notice although I D may not
look so bad but at the project
conclusion that means that this thing is
really beneficial no one gets to use it
have the developer meet to the team and
show them why this tool is amazing and
maybe the team will agree May con seeed
the best
answer
179 ahead of a uh crucial update
meeting uh a project manager learns
about a potential unforeseen delay in a
project segment that involves an
external
contractor the full extent of how this
will affect the project timeline is not
yet known what two action should the
project man take before addressing this
in meum
eight lays out with the external
contractor to understand the reasons
behind the delay perform a detailed
assessment to gauge the overall impact
of the delay on the project delay the
discussion until stakeholders notice to
delay themselves compare the situation
with a documented outcome from similar
incidents in all their projects record a
delay in the project risk register and
discuss it openly in the stakeholder
meeting all right let's see what answer
you you guys have notice it
says project law about an un potential
unforeseen delay all right with an
external contractor what are we going to
do
well the first thing here you want to do
is you want to perform a detail how is
this going to impact the delay on the
project and you want to record this in
the risk register why in the risk
register see this word potential this is
not an issue right you don't want to put
this this is nowhere near an issue this
is a the moment you see potential you
you know this is a
risk uh you don't want to lay on with
the external to understand the reason
well perform an assessment
first delay the discussion until the
stakeholders notice the delay no this
means you're just letting it be delayed
you're not taking proactive actions
compare this situation with documented
outcomes some similar incident although
I like that answer see how this is going
to affect this project first and of
course put in the risk register once you
do these two maybe then we can go back
and talk with the contractor and so on
making B and E the best best answer
180 at a conclusion of an Enterprise
software implementation project a
department head suggests the addition of
a new analytics feature to improve data
visualization capabilities the feature
was not covered in the Project's initial
scope but is considered by the
department head to be straight forward
enhancement that can be managed by the
current IT
staff what action should should the
project manager take in response to the
Department's head
suggestion a assess the feasibility of
incorporating new analytics feature
within the existing projects without
formalizing it consult with the finance
team to assess the potential financial
implications and budget adjustments
required for additional feature
coordinator meeting with the key
stakeholders to evaluate the added value
versus the effort and risk of
incorporating draft supplemental Charter
for an analytics feature addition
pending executive approval all right
guys best answer here is going to be did
you say that is
correct this is a straightforward
question lot of big words a lot of words
in this question it's a feature that
wasn't in the initial scope you want to
add it to the scope well then how
feasible is it how is it going to affect
the um how is it going to affect the
project but you don't want to formalize
it notice without formalizing it you
can't formalize a change to a scope if
it's a traditional project it needs to
change control needs to go through the
Change Control both project sponsors to
get approved if it's an agile project
you're going need to get it through the
product owner so assess it but don't
formalize it making that the best answer
consult with the team to assess I like
this one here but this one here looks at
the entire thing of the feature not just
a part of it this one here is looking
more for just budgets um this one here
is added value evaluate the added value
versus the efforts and risk you have to
look at not just that but the entire
thing uh draft a supplemental Charter
this doesn't need a chter project is
already started making a the best answer
181 as part of an initiative to upgrade
an educational institution digital
infrastructure a department head
proposes the integration of an AI based
learning assistant which was not
included the initial project scope the
department had also so is also unsure if
the Project's investors would agree to
the necessary budget increase what
initial all right initial action should
the project manager to take regarding
the proposed integration assess a
feasibility study to explore the
technical and financial aspect of addin
the I based lawning system estimate the
potential impact on the project budgets
timelines for
incorporating the AI laar assistant
consult with the team to assess how the
integration could affect the overall
project conduct an assessment of the
proposed addition impact on a project
all these answers are pretty good I
think they're all good but one of them
is better because if you notice one of
them includes the team in this one it
said what initial uh action should the
PM take in this one it seems like you're
doing it you're doing it and you're
doing it you know who's the best person
to tell you how something is going to
affect the project the experts and the
experts are the people people that's
working on the task the team
themselves so I would say definitely go
with the team here and notice this is
the overall project this one here is
looking at more Technical and financial
this is just budget and time but what
happens with quality what happens with
risk what happens with vendor and
procurement so there's a lot of other
areas that you need to look
at we can see the best
answer 182 in the roll out of a critical
update to an e-commerce platform the
project manager is presented with
several pressing issues there's an
immediate need for expertise in cyber
security due to new threats significant
Personnel shortages are on Horizon
including the exit of the product owner
okay this is a bad project right here
guys and a new data security law has
been passed o what should the project
manager's direct
Focus to ensure the project remains on
course uh initiate a search for a cyber
security expert to fortify the platform
against I like that begin the transition
process for a new product owner to
ensure strategic project oversight
continues good start the process to
secure a new it support contractor or
renew the existing one for
uninterruptible services resolve uh
identify Regulatory Compliance issu to
prevent any legal or operational
setbacks this question is difficult
because it's not there isn't a choice
here that really fixes them all right
you got a couple of choice here you have
cyber you you need a cyber security
expert there is a significant Personnel
change on the horizon right especially
your product owner and there's a new
cyber security law that's passed what
should you focus on right and the
choices are basically going to go into
and tell you there's like three or four
things here and they're going to tell
you all three or four things the one you
should focus on is the law no project
should be progressing if that project is
breaking the law This falls into the
domain
of business environment if a project is
out of compliance that project should be
stopped no project should be breaking
the law so if you're progressing on
something that's breaking the law that
project needs to get stopped in this
this is dealing with the cyber security
expert this is finding a new product
owner this here is something to do with
a contractor the best thing here you can
do is to check you know if you had to
choose one of these things would it be
insure the cyber security law would it
be getting the product owner or getting
the expert in cyber security best answer
was ensuring you're in
compliance
183 as a project unfolds for a global
Health Initiative the project manager
identifies the that the current online
collaboration tools are hindering
effective Communications across time
zones affecting the Project's progress
the team suggests that it CH that it
change in digital tools could
significantly improve Project Dynamics
and cross team interactions what should
the project manager do to ensure the
selection of the most effective tools
for the
team uh trial several top rated uh
collaboration tools on a small scale to
gauge Effectiveness before a full team
roll
out delegate the decision to the
organization technology Advisory board
for expert organize a series of Workshop
aimed that maximizing the current tools
capabilities before considering you one
organize a meeting with the entire team
to assess needs evaluate alternative
decide on the best collaboration tool
follow the mindset on this one this one
is not too difficult what's the best
tool work with the team let the team
tell you what's the best tool in this
one here this is more like you're you're
doing it yourself before you do a full
team roll out in this one here delegate
the decision to that you're giving away
the decision you're not incorporating
the team the best tool is dependent on
the person not everybody likes every
tool let the team tell you what they
like organize a series of Workshop
before considering noce maximizing
occurrent how about if we see what's out
there first bring the team in make
indeed the best
answer 184 for the Implement for the
implementation of a sophisticated
security software across multiple
departments the selected external
provider asserts that their solution is
plug andplay negating the need for any
in-depth involvement or validation
activities from the company the project
manager aiming to ensure the solutions
capability and Effectiveness decides to
confirm these assertions with the
organization stakeholders what initial
step should the project manager take to
guarantee alignment and meet the
organizational standards convey a
comprehensive briefing with key
stakeholders consolidate on standard and
set unified expectation for the project
draft a contingency plan to address
potential gaps that that might emerge
post implementation choose a preliminary
phase of collaboration between the
vendor's technical team and the
organization's it Department send out a
survey to department heads to collect
initial Impressions and concerns
regarding the vendor's claim all right
what are we going to do here guys the
best answer is going to be a that is
correct
notice I want a comprehensive briefing
right we want to consolidate your
understanding and set the expectations
on this project the is saying hey you
don't need to do anything we want to
make sure the stakeholders understand
that this one here draft a contingency
plan to address potential
gaps uh we're not sure what those gaps
are yet draft a preliminary propose a
preliminary phase of collaboration and
the organization's it well you got to
get not just it but the actual
stakeholders on top too sponsors and so
on we don't want just a survey a you
know what's better than a survey a good
comprehensive briefing with them versus
just a survey you can need a b
answer
185 a technology firm is transitioning
its software development practice to
Agile methodologies to improve its
productive its product development life
cycle the move aims to make the progress
more Dynamic and responsive to customer
needs and Market truns what is the
principal advantage of adapting agile in
this agile methodologies in this context
enhance the efficiency of the
development cycle to reduce time to
market for new features all right
Implement a structured risk management
approach to significantly uh decrease
project
uncertainties prioritize and deliver
product features in alignment with their
value on customer
demand reduce operation by by optimizing
team workflows on resources okay there's
two good answers and there's two bad
answers let's see what you guys got
let's Point them out first of all two
bad answers
adile really doesn't have a massive
structure approach so let's get rid of
this it may or may not increase or
decrease expenses is not something that
you can gauge right off the bat but
agile does do two
things it does lead to things get into
the market quicker and it also
prioritizes features leading to the most
valuable product coming out first so
that brings me to a or C if you choose a
or C you're probably if you got a you
probably say hey what is what did what
happened here well you have to ask
yourself what's better in agile is it
the whole concept of get things to
Market first or is it get the most
valuable things to Market first if you
said well let's get the most valuable
thing to Market first that's the value
of agile agile is about developing the
most valuable thing first not
necessarily to get it to the market
first it's to develop the most valuable
thing first making a a better c a better
answer than
a
186 during the critical phase of a green
energy plan construction project it
becomes evident that the project that
the project may not adhere to the
initially planned schedule this
situation arises even as the project
team has been performing efficiently
making their completion of several
important fa marking the completion of
several important
phases what is the first course of
action a project
manager what is the first course for the
project manager to address the Lumen
schedule delay inform Senior Management
and key stakeholders about the potential
delay suggesting a reassessment of the
project timeline summarize the project
achievements to date and expected imp
impact on the delay of the delay in
detailing in detailed breef briefing for
the project board revise the project
timeline with lead Engineers to pinpoint
specific tasks that are causing the
delay and their potential remedies
review the project the current project
timelines um with I should say with the
entire team what answer do you guys have
here guys the best answer guys is going
to be
D all right I did miss a word here it
should be with the entire team here okay
sorry about that one word we missed
there okay so notice the first course of
action all right you really got to put
this thing in order anytime you guys see
this thing that
says uh what do you do first Sometimes
they going to be choices and you got to
say okay which one am I going to do
first of those four choices because you
may say well I have to assess something
first yeah but um I have to revise
something you're absolutely correct and
that's what we're doing here you notice
in this one before you inform senior
manager you have to assess the problem
summarize the achievement and the
expected impact before you do that you
would have you should meet with the team
first right you should meet with the
team before you do
this revise the timeline no you just
can't revise the timeline you just can't
change the time this requires a whole
change request so D is the best option
here not you just can't go and change an
entire timeline like that and always
meet with the team revise reassess
assess the situation before taking an
action 187
aim the roll out of a new software
platform designed to enhance customer
engagement for a retail chain the lead
role transitions due to a
promotion the lead role transition due
to
promotion the incoming project manager
tasks with guid in the project to its
completion under a hybrid management
framework what document should the new
manage manager review first to
understand the Strategic benefits and
objective of a project the road map the
business case strategic alignment
documents technical design documents
now this question you see you're going
to get questions on your exam where like
a whole portion of the question is not
even needed the real question is here
all of this is just saying that there's
a new project manager that's what this
is saying so I'm going to throw that
paragraph out the real thing is what
should the project what what should a
new project manager review first you
want to understand the benefits and
objectives of this project and that is
stored in a document we call all correct
the business case the business case will
store that the program road map is not
even a project road map the program
roadmap are all the different projects
on the program to accomplish its
strategic
goal strategic alignment document really
no such thing or technical design
document this is how it will be
technically developed use the business
case in this
one
188 embarking on an enterprise-wide
software upgrade project this distinct
distinct
distinctively different from the
organization's usual it initiatives the
project manager's task with selecting
project management methodologies and
tools that best align with this specific
venture's needs who should be the
primary responsibility for choosing the
project management methodologies and
tools tailored to this distinctive
project it's a good
question the LA really it's in the last
part right like who's really responsible
for choosing a project management
methodology you should be key
stakeholders excuse me on that uh from
each department should collaboratively
determine the methodology and tools for
the project the project manager and the
team are to strictly utilize the
industry standard set of methodologies
and
tools the chief technology officer is
the highest Authority on the technology
project should set the methodologies and
tools the project manager and the
project team should identify and select
the methodologies and tools that best
suit the project so this really is who
should choose the right methodology well
I'll tell you guys right off the bat it
is not key stakeholders from departments
it you shouldn't just use industry
standards or the CTO you and your team
should work together to select the best
methodology for your
project only the team really understands
the work and the project manager is
going to work with the team so work
together on that every project is unique
every project is
different in spearheading a ground
ground breaking environmental let me
stop right here for a second guys if you
hear me mispronouncing words I've been
doing this all day yes these videos are
recorded in one session and these words
are massively
large it's easy to read it in your mind
when you're reading it nonstop like this
it's tough it it's tough it's tough
uh it's tough let's get back to this
video man don't don't take this out you
know what let me give you guys a quick
lesson we got time in this um when
you're reading this exam I have been
added right now for about a 100 of these
that it's recorded all in one day and
I'm going to tell you guys something uh
it is very very difficult uh to do this
I imagine on a real test and me reading
out me read see I can't even pronounce
it anymore I need to take a break now me
reading the words out loud is even more
difficult on the real exam take breaks
you're going to get breaks take it I'm
telling you guys I can't sit here and do
this and I wrote these questions you
guys are going to see these questions
for the first time you're going to be
critical thinking I'm not critical
thinking I'm just memorizing the answer
because I I wrote them for you guys take
your breaks I'm telling you guys you
need them like I need it right now I'm
going to have a real hard time at 189
190 I'm gon to have to take a break come
back to to the last set
here editor don't cut this section out
this is me uh being real with them let's
get back to this finish this up inspir
headen a groundbreaking environmental
initiative within a large organization a
lot of words there the project manager
faces the challenge of ensuring clear
and effective communication amongst team
members from various disciplines
including engineering environmental
science and project management what
should the project manager do develop
individualized communication management
plans that cater to the specific
informational needs preference to each
project team
discipline inst Institute a centralized
project information dashboard for
realtime updates and transparen and
across the team
disciplines conduct interdisciplinary
workshops to Foster Mutual understanding
and collaborative problem solving
problem solving skills amongst team
members all right assigning
communication Le Aon within each
discipline to streamline the workflow of
project information and facilitate
interdepartmental understanding okay
guys best answer here all right notice
you got teams from various discipline
the best answer answer here guys is you
want to have a communication management
plan that is very catered to everyone on
a project keep in mind the communication
is tailored to the stakeholders it's not
just a centralized thing or it's not
just one method to everything like this
here this is one
method this here is interdisciplinary
Workshop this one here is bringing
people more like together but it should
be customized we don't want just a
liaison we want to have everyone get in
the right form of communication make hey
the best
answer oh thank God it's a short
question 190 following the approval of
the project Charter the project manager
begins working with the team to organize
the project Scopes into smaller detailed
components what is a project manager
primally working on creating a project
racy chart so this stands for
responsible accountable consultant
inform form a project schedule Network
diagram work breakdown structure
WBS uh already
scheduling the uh execution phases for
the project task best answer guys is of
course the WBS if you are
decomposing uh the scope when you
decompose the scope you're basically
creating the work packages that builds
up on the WPS this is to assign people
to work they're not doing that here this
is to build a schedule you got to finish
the plan before you build a schedule you
can see the best answer all right 191
here we go on a high stakes software
development at out project the project
manager notices a pattern where numerous
team members are either late or entirely
missed the virtual entirely missed the
daily virtual scrum designed to
facilitate project cohesion what action
should the project manager take to
enhance the efficiency and attendance of
these
sessions work with the team to identify
a project communication protocol that
will work with them to ensure timely
participation in the daily scrum all
right identify time that could
potentially incre increase attendance
and punctuality transition to an
asynchronous communication model to
allow team members to update their
status at their convenient solicit input
from stakeholders on efficient methods
to improve team engagement and meeting
with attendants now it really comes down
to two P two good questions first of all
which one should you there's two answers
you could eliminate first of all which
one can you eliminate did you get it
first one you should have eliminated was
B because you just can't Identify some a
time for the team it's an agile project
these are the daily standup meetings the
daily scrum is a daily standup meetings
work with the team on this an
asynchronous method doesn't work for a
daily scrum a daily scrum technically
should be a standup where everybody
talks it should be if it's virtual
everybody should be there now it really
came down to a or b and in this one
you're getting input from stakeholders
but it doesn't particularly say the team
maybe you're getting inputs from the
project uh the product owner or maybe
even the customers the best answer here
is to work with the team all right work
with the team come up with a good
protocol or a set of rules that they are
willing to follow that ensures that they
come and show up to the Sprint either on
time or just sh up so the best thing is
to work with the team don't just get an
input from everybody else get input from
the team in particular making a a better
answer than
D 192 a project manager discovers that
recent legislative updates necessitate
additional security enhancement to the
project although the development team is
incorpor prop these enhance enhancements
without exceeding their budget the
project manager realizes that the
allocated budget for quality insurance
and testing is quickly being depleted
due to these unplan requirements what
action should the project manager take
what actions should the project manager
take to manage the escalating cost
associated with the increased scope of
testing a propose a temporary
reallocation of resources from less
critical activities to support the
expanded testing requirements have the
sponsor analyze potential cost-saving
measures within the project to
reallocate funds towards the testing
budget submit a formal change request to
revive the cost based on accommodating
the extra expense incurred in the
testing adjust the Project's Financial
strategy to ensure the newly identified
testing needs are adequately funded
without compromising quality guys the
best answer here is going to be did you
get it yes so if there is something that
needs the project to in increase its
schedule increase its budget it's
important to get that approved you just
can't do it that's what a d is doing you
just can't adjust the financial Str you
just can't add money to the project and
this is not a job of the sponsor sponsor
is there to approve or disapprove not to
help you with
assessment and noticed a temporary
reallocation of resources this may
require change request the best thing
here to do submit a formal change
request to update that cost Baseline so
you can get those testing done C is the
best
answer 193 in the development stage of
an Innovative mobile application the
agile the agile project team discovers
the need for an advanced software
library that wasn't initially
anticipated which is critical for
enhancing the apps functionality what
should the project manager do to
effectively uh manage this unforeseen
requirement organize a strategic meeting
with the product owner to reassess the
project priorities and integrate the new
software Library update the project
timeline to reflect the expected delay
to the uh due to the integration of the
new software Library identify this new
need this new need as this new need
asset project risk seek immediate advice
from steering committee delegate the
task of integrating the new software
library to a specialist within within
the project Team without delay best
answer here guys if there is any kind of
things that needs to get added to an
adob project how do we know it's an adob
project it literally says the adob
project team if there's something that
needs to get added to the adob project
and particularly something added to the
scope it must go through the project the
product owner they have to agree with it
they have to add it in and then it has
to be reprioritized and the product
backlog you just can't update the
timeline you would need approval from
product owner identify this as a
identify this need as a project risk
well you notice they need need they need
this in order to keep going far is
critical for their to function the best
thing the best way to get this
Incorporated would be to added to the
product backlog delegate the task well
you never give away your task never just
give away your work make an a the best
answer
194 while working on a project the
client's request for additional changes
threaten to extend the Project's
timeline significantly the project
manager is exploring options to
accelerate the project time timeline to
accommodate these changes but there's
concerned about the potential for
increase overtime for the team what what
action should the project manager take
to keep the team motivated despite these
challenges offer a monetary incentive to
team members who agree to work extended
hours to meet the
deadline attempt to meet the timeline
regularly recognize team efforts
celebrate Milestones to maintain moral
challenges uh during during challenges
during challenging period reassigned
task to focus on high priority
deliverable and reduce the team workload
introduce monetary team building
activities to encourage collaboration
and increase motivation the best answer
here guys is going to be did you get it
yes this is the best answer here's
why
now read the question carefully the
question is what will keep them
motivated that's the question right the
question is what keeps your team
motivated they may have to work overtime
notice introduce mandatory team building
anything that's mandatory is probably
not going to be motivating it might lead
to more
demoralization Reign task to focus on
high PRI and reduce the team workload
although I like this it may not be
feasible in times like
this offer now it really I was thinking
A or B keep in mind that everyone is
incentivized by money and what if it's
the entire team and not just a few
people then a is not going to work but
what you could do is celebrate Milestone
recognize their effort just try to keep
them motivated which is what B is
doing 195 in a major software
development project the project manager
finds that several team members are
reluctant to to use new project
management software believing it to be
overly comp complicated and not
beneficial for their task what should
the project manager have done initially
to facilitate the adaptation of the new
software by the team encourage team
leaders to use the software in their
meetings to set an example for the rest
of the team Implement a reward system
for early adapters who effectively
integrate the soft integrate the
software into their
workflow conduct one-on-one sessions to
understand individual resistance and
tailor support
accordingly organize a comprehensive
training session to demonstrate the
functional benefits of the new software
best answer guys is going to be D that
is correct here's why
you got to read the question carefully
it says have initially done what you're
trying to do is prevent the problem not
fix the problem see fixes the problem we
don't want to fix the problem right now
we want to prevent it from
happening the others now encourage team
leaders this is not going to not because
of team leaders doing doesn't mean that
the other members see the benefits of it
versus the
inde everybody is seeing the benefits of
this thing maybe they're resistant
because they just don't know the
benefits of it Implement a reward system
not because you offer someone a reward
doesn't mean they see the benefit of it
they'll just use it just to get their
reward the best thing to do is to show
them the benefit let them see how it's
going to help them and they're more
likely to take in the software make and
deem the best
answer
196 on an infrastructure project to
upgrade City Water Systems the project
manager struggling to finalize the
project schedule due to unpredictable
regulatory review times and potential
delays in securing necessary
equipment what schedule and technique
should the project man adapt to to
manage the planet effectively under
these terms Rolland wave planning
backwards pass analysis uh dependency
structuring lag lead and lag
optimization now notice let's go over
this here for a
second unpredictable regulatory review
times and potential if something is
unpredictable review times if something
is
unpredictable you may not be able to
break down the work you may not be able
to schedule it right away you may not be
able to build a plan right away so you
have the plan to replan that's called
rolling wave plan and you plan as time
is progressing as time is progressing
things becomes more
clear that's basically the definition of
rolling wave planner
everyone uh backwards pass is to
calculate the critical path we not
that's not going to help us here
dependency structure is showing you what
task depends on what is
it uh finish to start start to start
type thing uh lags and Lead shows you
there any delays or overlap between tals
that's not going to help us here what we
need to do is we need to understand that
we can't plan for everything right away
let time progress and then we can plan
for
them 197 during the roll out of a new it
system within a large corporation the
project manager observes that
discussions and stakeholder meetings are
frequently derailed by a participant
who the the the can't pronounce that
word right now stop right here guys I'm
way too tired on this into technical
details uh irrelevant to the to the
meetings objectives the behavior is
causing meetings to overrun and is
reducing the time available to cover all
agenda items leading to dissatisfaction
about stakeholders so let's see what's
going on here we got one team member
that is going into too much technical
detail is probably not needed what
action should the project manager take
to ensure meetings are more focused and
productive emphasize the meeting agenda
at the start and kindly remind
participants to keep discussions on
topic allocate specific time for open
discussions at the end of the meeting to
cater to additional
topics introduce a me and co-
facilitator to help steer conversation
back to the agenda when they go off
course Implement a suggestion by for
topics that require further discussions
outside of the scheduled meeting this is
a good question actually because it has
quite a good set of tasks uh what should
you do to ensure meetings are more
focused and productive the best answer
here guys is going to be correct
emphasize the agenda say this is what
we're covering we don't want to cover uh
and do this at the beginning you may
have to do this throughout the meeting
too and tell people hey you know what
let's try to stay on topic this here
would solve the
problem although the other answers are
not bad I don't think the other answers
are terrible like a suggestion
box um I'm not sure about this co-
facilitator you should be the
facilitator you need another one and
even allocating extra time with the end
Delo this can speed up meetings or
sometimes this can make the meeting go
over so I think a here is the best
answer 198 on an agricultural
development project a key team member
expresses dissatisfaction with the
current risk management strategy
feel feeling it doesn't adequately
address the potential for unpredictable
weather conditions affecting crop
trials what action should the project
manager take first Implement a
contingency fund specifically for
weather related delays consult with the
external agriculture expert to gain
insights on managing weather related rks
reevaluate the risk management plan and
risk register with the entire team to
incorporate feedback on the weather
related risks adjust the timeline and
Milestone to allow for greater
flexibility and response to weather
changes best here guys is going to
be C is correct why is that well if
somebody brings up something to you
they're saying hey we're not adequately
managing risk we may not have the right
responses we're not be identifying them
fast enough for all of them what can we
do well bring it to the team work with
the entire team let them re help us
rebuild maybe the RIS management plan
let them add it to the risk register and
let's get their feedback in there let's
do this first before we go to the
agricultural expert or get some kind of
contingency fund or don't just change a
timeline like that that might need a
change request so do c before you do a b
or d making that the best
answer
199 a project team in a digital
marketing project discovers that their
key design software license has expired
Halton the team work on a critical
critical campaign visuals what is the
most effective initial action for the
project manager to
take request that the team manually
sketch the campaign Concepts while
awaiting uh this the license
renewal have the team work with the IT
department to renew the license
prioritize other aspects of campaign
that doesn't require software doesn't
require uh design software according
with it Department prompt to renew the
software license best answer here guys
is going to be D now part of being a
servant leader is
removing imp
removing obstacles from the team this is
clearly not something that's project
related this is more computer it related
computer errors and when you have
something like that it's your job or it
should be your job to help remove this
obstacle from the team remember the
concept of servant
leadership so in this one here you're
telling the team this is not optimizing
the work you're not giving them the
right tools you're see to manually do it
in this one here you're telling the team
to fix it prioritize other aspects
you're not addressing the problem in
this one here making D the best answer
question 200 during a during a critical
uh phase of a software development
project the key developer notifies the
project manager that they will need to
take an unexpected leave impa in the
completion of a crucial backlog item
schedule for demonstration in the
upcoming Sprint review what should the
project manager do and since the
developer work remotely during their
leave to ensure the backlog item is
completed on time escalate the issue to
Senior Management and demand the assign
an additional resource immediately
reevaluate the Sprint goals and backlog
priorities consult with the team about
adjustments
and communicate the revised plan to
stakeholders cancel the upcoming Sprint
review stting the lack of progress on
the crit on the crucial backlog item the
best answer here guys is going to be C
that is correct here's
why so one thing we want to talk about
here is you notice somebody left right
so they need to take expensively don't
make them work if they're leaving for an
emergency or family issues they got to
go you can't just tell up to work
remotely that might not be possible just
don't go to Senior Management and demand
things from Senior Management this just
sounds wrong first of all you might be
fired for that that leavs two things you
can't just cancel the Sprint the best
thing here is to work with the team now
you're re-evaluating the goals you're
not some people say hey Andrew you're re
no we're not re prioritizing the backlog
you're reevaluating it the only person
that
can uh rep prioritize a product owner
but you're Consulting with the team
right maybe we need to change the Sprint
goal that's within the team so you can
adjust the Sprint goals because you know
what you might not be able to get that
done with this team member
gone and that guys ends the 200 practice
questions hopefully you guys enjoyed
this journey hopefully you guys uh
really like these 200 practice questions
it would mean a lot to me it took me a a
lot of time to write this took me a lot
of time to present it as you can see the
length in this video If you
guys uh really enjoyed this type of
content give the video a like subscribe
to the channel would be absolutely
amazing it really helps us out it really
helps us to make our content I guess
gain a bigger audience which would
really help us out and if you want more
questions like this check the link below
we have the ti exam Simulator the
closest to the real exam tons of people
have used it over 30,000 people have
used that to pass their PMP exam and
also my 35-hour course my study guide my
books are all below you guys can all
check that out and with that in mind
guys hopefully you guys learned a lot in
this in this video and in the
compilation of when it's a bigger video
hopefully you guys learned a lot and
I'll see you in the next video